?? (Lucien): "Once upon a time, there was a queen who ruled the whole kingdom."
?? (Lucien): "The Queen had many, many toys. She lived in a castle and lived with her toys."
?? (Lucien): "At the Halloween party, the Queen was so bored! So… she decided to play a new game."
?? (Lucien): "She gathered all the toys and told them to find what they desired most in their hearts within the castle."
?? (Lucien): "'The first toy to find it can gain freedom.' The Queen sat on her throne and announced to all the toys."
?? (Lucien): "But how could the Queen possibly know what each toy desired the most?"
?? (Lucien): "Of course... because the Queen knows everything!"
Lucien: "Now then... let the game begin. But be warned, don't get caught by the Queen during your search…"
Lucien: "...or you'll never be able to leave this castle for the rest of your life——"
MC: Lucien, wait... just hold on a second! Let's talk about it after we run to a safe place!
Eerie and urgent footsteps circle endlessly behind as if crazed hands are about to reach out from the darkness, savagely seizing everything.
I don't have time to immerse myself in the joy that lit up my eyes upon finding Lucien as I instinctively obey my fear and start to run.
But the person beside me remains calm and unhurried, smiling as if he's just taking a stroll in an ancient castle.
Lucien: I hope my task requirements haven’t made you feel troubled.
Lucien: My identity card says I need to finish telling this story within 5 minutes of meeting another player.
As his words fall, along with the hurried footsteps behind me, a short but slightly piercing alarm sounds from somewhere unknown.
Lucien: Otherwise, my game will be declared a failure.
The alarm sounds again.
MC: What does this alarm mean...? Did what you just said violate the rules on the identity card?
He smiles without a word, seeming to agree with my judgment.
MC: This is a bit too immersive! Why doesn’t my identity card have any tasks on it?
Despite my complaints, my running footsteps don't stop, and the silent doors repeatedly block my escape routes.
We twist and turn through the old castle until a "click" rings out, nearly making me cry in surprise.
The eerie footsteps grow louder beside my ear. The soles of the shoes rub against the slightly worn carpet, making a rough scraping sound, like sharp nails scratching against my eardrum.
In the darkness, I hold my breath, and that nerve-wracking sound seems to slowly fade away into the night.
I let out a breath of relief, and as I look up, I bump straight into a pair of deep, enigmatic eyes.
The room is cloaked in darkness, illuminated only by the moonlight, yet his eyes, glimmering with a hidden smile, shine even brighter.
The smoky black makeup extends into delicate marks of mischief, like dried tear stains or the playful strokes of a child’s crayon.
His usually soft hair is now slicked back, the ends styled into slightly unruly arcs that accentuate his sharp jawline.
The black and white suit amplifies the elegant yet bizarre aura, yet it feels perfectly natural on Lucien.
MC: This place did an incredible job with the styling. Once we’re done, I’m definitely filling my entire album with photos of Mr. Jester.
This Halloween, Lucien and I booked a super popular immersive escape room game. Although it’s only for two players, the activity spans an entire large castle.
The script for the game is assigned based on a playing card drawn a week before the game starts. It focuses on a highly immersive experience, and I’ve heard there are dozens of different endings depending on players' choices.
MC: No, I should say I never expected the 'Queen's toys' to be so plentiful and appealing—and there's also Mr. Jester!
Lucien: I think it's this beautiful doll lady before me that truly makes it impossible to look away.
Our bodies, already pressed together from hiding, are pulled even closer by him. His warm fingertips stroke my cheek, then trail slowly down my neck in a delicate caress.
Lucien: The Queen has instructed the toys to seek what they desire most in their hearts. If it were me...
Lucien: ...then surely what I desire most must be right here before my eyes.
Of course, those are just Lucien’s jesting words to tease me. The game is still going on after all.
After my makeup is finished, the staff simply tells me that my identity is ‘Miss Puppet’ and then leads me into the old castle.
If we are all so-called ‘Queen's Toys’, then according to the fairy tale Lucien just recounted…
MC: "Find what the toys desire most in their hearts within this castle…"
MC: That means we need to find the props in this castle that correspond to our identities, and then we should be able to win the game.
But then I have second thoughts, and look at Lucien who is being a bit too mysterious on the side.
MC: "The first toy to find it can gain freedom."
MC: Does that mean that in this game with just the two of us, there can only be one winner?
Meeting my gaze, he leans lightly against the door and smiles lightly.
Lucien: Does this doll lady want to gain freedom?
Lucien's words aren't laced with much emotion; instead, they hold a kind of faint scrutiny and enjoyment that stands outside of winning and losing.
It seems that more than victory or defeat, he takes pleasure in the interesting developments he's "created" throughout this whole process.
Enveloped by his permeating silent arrogance, I, on the contrary, subtly curl the corners of my lips into a smile and lean closer to him.
MC: Compared to freedom, I'd rather not let a certain Mr. Jester get too bored.
MC: Furthermore, I enjoy a challenge and am prepared to put in all my effort to win.
I gently graze his cheek with my fingertips, letting myself sink into the depths of his profound and mysterious eyes.
MC: You better be a bit more serious, okay?
MC: Otherwise... be careful not to get left behind in this castle~
Lucien: …
His eyes seem to freeze for a fleeting moment, but they fill with even more smiles in the next instant.
Lucien: Then this Miss Puppet will have to put in a lot of effort.
Lucien: After all, leaving you all alone in the castle would make me feel terribly lonely.
After issuing a ‘declaration of challenge’, naturally, it's necessary to seek more information.
But this castle is much larger than I imagined. Even though many rooms can't be opened, it'll still take considerable time to investigate the rest.
At the same time, the occasional sounds of clockwork and footsteps add a touch of horror to this dilapidated old castle.
The sounds of footsteps varied, sometimes intense and frightening, and at other times merely a soft, creeping rustle across the floor, creating noises that grate on the nerves.
Lucien: Looks like the party is going well.
MC: This means... the other 'toys' are also searching for things that are important to them, right?
Facing my interpretation, Lucien curls his lips without a word. At this moment, I finally vaguely confirm a certain boundary to Lucien's words.
In our earlier exchanges, there were two instances where he clearly mentioned the task settings for ’this game,' which triggered warning alarms both times.
Moreover, throughout all his interactions and expressions, he has been entirely restricted to addressing me as a 'puppet'.
This indicates that although I still can't further confirm what prop Lucien desires as the ‘Jester’, his words are still an important way for me to obtain information.
MC: Mr. Jester, shall we cooperate for the time being?
MC: There are a lot of rooms here. Given that we don't have much information, I think working together would be more efficient.
MC: There should be other rooms we can open on this floor. How about we each take half and then combine the information?
Lucien: You trust me that much?
Just as his voice falls, a sharp warning sound rings again.
Lucien freezes momentarily, ponders for a while, then nonchalantly lifts his lips into a smile as he looks at me, seemingly waiting for my answer.
MC: Indeed, if you hide any information, I wouldn't notice it.
MC: But luck also plays a part in the outcome. Whoever finds the key clue naturally has the conditions for victory.
MC: Besides, who’s to say it won’t be me hiding the information instead?
Lucien: …
Under the moonlight, Lucien smiles as he leans down and gently lifts my fingertips.
Lucien: Please allow me to apologize for my recent discourtesy.
The moment his thin lips lightly touch the back of my hand, I feel as if I can hear the sound of my heartbeat.
Lucien: Good luck to you, beautiful Miss.
Accompanied by chilling footsteps, Lucien and I begin searching the castle.
Most of the rooms I can access are incredibly shabby, but fortunately, I'm still managing to gather a number of clues.
Using clues from the diaries of some other toys, I quickly identify several key-seeming props mentioned in them and hide those props.
MC: I found a page from a fairy tale, and the content matches what you said earlier.
MC: But it's been ripped out of a book, which means there's a complete version of the story.
Lucien: According to the map, this villa has three floors. The first floor consists of the lobby, reception room, and toy display room, while the Queen’s bedroom is on the third floor.
Lucien: The second floor is fairly special. It has dozens of rooms, and the room numbers aren't in order.
MC: I have a feeling those rooms belong to the toys.
As I speak, I unfurl half of the kraft paper scroll towards him, revealing the words "Toy List".
The paper is filled in symbols of various shapes that look like a child's freehand doodles, each with numbers like "201", "205", "219" written beside them.
MC: There are 13 of these symbol and number combinations, so I'm guessing...the Queen has 13 toys in total.
MC: Corresponding to the 13 rooms on the second floor.
Lucien: It seems our objectives have become quite clear.
MC: That's right. Once we figure out which symbols correspond to which toy, we can use the map to find the rooms.
MC: Do you think... that 'Toy Display Room' might have the answers?
Faced with this probing question, Lucien doesn't respond but simply looks at me deeply as I shake the kraft paper.
In the next second, he lightly flicks his fingers––
A silver key sways and gleams faintly beneath the moonlight.
Lucien: I’m curious too.
I never thought that Lucien would just happen to have the key to the toy display room in his hand.
However, in this kind of adversarial game, having one more condition to compete with him is never bad.
And now, I’m indeed lucky to have made the right bet.
The night seems to grow even darker, and the eerie footsteps cast long, strange shadows, flowing like water past our feet, then slowly fading away.
With a 'click' sound, I follow behind Lucien and walk into the toy display room.
Only the moonlight remains inside the room, falling onto the staggered display stands, where toys of various shapes are placed.
The toys sit quietly in this somewhat rundown room as if they are waiting for someone.
I gently pick up the toys and notice that each has a familiar symbol emblazoned on its body and a heart-shaped hollow on its chest.
I quietly ponder for a moment, and instead of saying anything, I continue searching.
Soon I spot a puppet on the display table at the edge of the room, dressed in the same clothes as mine, except this puppet has a wooden puppet control bar and strings attached to it.
MC: …Wooden control bar?
An inexplicable 'click' sound occurs when I pick up the puppet.
I look at the symbol on the doll in my hand with confusion, my mind spinning.
Is it a similar doll? Or is there another reason? Thinking this, I open the scroll and begin searching for clues.
Suddenly, I freeze.
No matter how many times I check, I can't find the same symbol as the one on the puppet.
But after cross-checking the symbols with the other toys in front of me, I subconsciously hold my breath——
Dachshund spring toy, toy soldier, plush bird, roly-poly toy, carousel, feather pen…
The 13 symbols on the toy list correspond precisely to the 13 toys.
My gaze slowly moves to the figure under the moonlight; the master's smooth fingertips carefully caress the marionette that looks like me.
Then, as if sensing something, he indifferently looks back.
There is no jester toy in this room.
The missing jester, the extra marionette.
At this moment, Lucien and I seem like some kind of aberrant existence.
Neither of us is the Queen’s toy—I immediately come to this judgment.
Then who am I? And who is Lucien?
Could it be that he secretly hid some more important information?
Meanwhile, Lucien also seems to have realized my judgment.
But he still unhurriedly fiddles with the marionette in his hand while gracefully walking up the steps.
Lucien: The Queen hosts a fun-filled party with all her toys.
Lucien: The toys search for what they desire most—ah, it’s their beloved Queen.
He gives a small bow, and as his words fall, a red balloon floats out of nowhere.
I unconsciously grab it, only to see more and more red balloons appearing, until eventually, all that remains are that pair of captivating eyes.
Lucien: So... ultimately, is it the Queen who captures the toys, or the toys who get the Queen?
His voice lingers near my ear, only to dissolve into the moonlit night instantly, along with his disappearing figure.
Following that, the sound of footsteps coming nearer and nearer, yet also more and more numerous.
I don't have time to consider when Lucien learned magic tricks; I immediately run out of the display room through the opened door.
Those intrigued eyes are firmly imprinted in my mind. This person is playing this game with me very seriously; I can't let him down.
His identity as a jester is definitely not simple, and I... could I be the puppet representing the 'Queen'?
Lucien's words from just now seem to linger in my ears as if hinting. After thinking for a moment, I immediately run carefully toward the third floor.
I've been here before, but the door is firmly locked, and I never found the corresponding key.
Remembering the mechanical sound when I picked up the puppet, I can't help but decide to take a gamble.
Facing the silent door, I take a deep breath and press the door handle down with force—
'Click.'
MC: …As expected!
The pleasure of solving the puzzle makes me feel confident, and I go in cautiously.
The shabby room can't hide its luxury. The large bed is covered with an exquisite embroidered sheet, and the red velvet bed curtains reveal faint patterns.
The fireplace no longer burns, and the vase no longer shines, like servants who, though dejected after being left by their master, still maintain a dignified demeanor.
The walls, covered in cobwebs, are adorned with many picture frames.
But these frames don't contain any scenery or photos—
Instead, they contain all kinds of hearts, big and small.
I quietly observe them for a long time before continuing to rummage through the room.
Soon, I find an old, yellowed book on the bedside table, with one page torn out.
With the help of light from the moon, I flip through it.
MC: "The Jester laughed loudly, proclaiming that the Queen was bored. She lifted the hem of her bright red dress and decided to play a game..."
MC: "A game of escape."
I realize in hindsight that something's not quite right.
Why is there a marionette with a wooden control bar and strings in the toy display room?
Marionette isn't on the toy list, so what does the symbol on it represent?
Suddenly, I freeze.
——it is Lucien's hint.
Just now, he guided me into thinking I was the Queen, leading me here. But if I really were the Queen, I would be very different from the one in the display room.
MC: As a toy… I'm a marionette.
MC: But the strings on me have already gone.
The toy’s escape is also the Queen’s escape.
At that moment, even though the room is clearly silent, I inexplicably feel as if someone is watching me.
From the very beginning, that gaze has been fixed on me, and all my actions are under his "control."
At this moment, I already understand who the owner of those footsteps outside the door is. After avoiding those searching "toys" and reaching the second floor—
there is a door that has always been tightly shut. Now, it opens its arms wide as if it has been waiting for a long time.
Scratches appear on the door, revealing a symbol identical to the one on the puppet's body.
I hold my breath tightly, expecting to see a familiar figure inside, but instead, I find the room completely empty.
To be safe, I close the door first and then step inside.
As expected, the entire room has already been searched.
A metal box lies on the ground, completely empty inside, with the opened lock quietly lying beside it.
MC: ….
Am I really going to lose?
As if in response to my heart, the footsteps outside the door stop at the entrance with the sound of a clockwork.
At this moment, I understand why this door is open.
This is an invitation for ‘me’ to take the initiative to step into this cage controlled by him.
There's nowhere to go but through that door.
In the end, I have no choice but to take the initiative to open the door myself, offering myself as a sacrifice and presenting him with a delicious victory.
But I don't want to lose yet.
I stop in front of the door, even holding onto a sliver of luck as I lean toward the peephole, trying to find any possibility of escape—
Lucien: Good evening, dear miss.
Red balloons float mid-air in a green corridor, and a candle burns suspended in the air as if they’re part of a grand illusory melody.
Layer upon layer of cobwebs hang down, and twisted pumpkins are painted black and white.
In the absurd and mysterious world, Lucien raises the corners of his lips, his eyes with painted black tear streaks curving slightly.
He lifts his hand, inclining slightly in a gentlemanly bow as though taking a final curtain call.
Lucien: "A long, long time ago, there was a Queen who ruled an entire kingdom."
Lucien: "The Queen had many toys, and she lived with her toys in a castle."
The graceful yet dangerous jester tells the story again, but he carries it further this time.
Lucien: "But the toys could never get the Queen."
Lucien: "The party ended, and no one gained their freedom."
He smiles gently, and the flickering, dancing candle flames seem to sway excitedly without stopping, yet at the same time, the melting wax flows down like tears.
Lucien: "And so…The party went on, and the Queen, feeling extremely bored, intended to play a new game."
MC: …Is that the full story?
Lucien: No.
Lucien: This story will go on forever.
MC: Why?
Hearing my voice, Lucien puts away his smile.
That pair of profound and mysterious eyes unusually ooze with a hint of long-forgotten coldness, resembling a dark and gloomy sea.
The blood-red balloons are tethered in place and can only swing their body from side to side.
Yet I can clearly see the black tear mark slowly lengthening.
Lucien: Because... 'I' said so.
The Jester smiles as he opens his arms, revealing his beautiful and dangerous fangs, waiting to make a curtain call to his sole audience.
Looking at Lucien before me, I take half a step back.
A jester who doesn't exist in the story, a marionette who has lost her strings, a story that will go on forever.
A somewhat bold idea spreads in my mind, causing my heart to inevitably start beating rapidly.
After all, this is a game—and it’s only a game.
Lucien has obtained the prop, but the game isn’t over yet, so the prop alone is useless.
The grand door slowly opens, revealing that pair of captivating eyes in even greater clarity.
MC: So, dear Mr. Jester, what is it that you desire?
Lucien: Perhaps it’s simply… to sway with you in a dance that never ends.
With that, he places one hand behind his back, bows slightly, and extends his right hand to me.
The moment I touch his warm palm, it feels like a huge clockwork begins turning again, bringing the entire castle to life.
??: [cheers] Party! Party! We want to keep the party going!
??: Party! Party! We want the Queen’s party!
An unknown dance tune begins to play, and Lucien lifts my hand, guiding me in graceful dance steps and making me sway like the red floating balloons.
The colorful and ambiguous shadows subconsciously draw my attention, but then I’m pulled one step closer to him, leaving no room for retreat.
His hand is clearly only lightly resting on my back, yet I can’t push away even half a step.
Lucien: Dear lady, don't leave my sight.
His voice is soft, but it seems to carry an undeniable power.
For a moment, all I can do is look into his eyes, move my feet in sync with his guidance, and spin under his palm.
He is both my dance partner and the conductor of our duet.
The moonlight sprinkles over the desolate castle, and the sweeping hem of my gown traces luminous arcs amidst the black and white.
My retreat and approach, intimacy and evasion, are all in the palm of his hand—
as if there are some invisible threads that make me dance only for him.
MC: Mr. Jester, do you want to get me?
Lucien: Perhaps I’ve been striving for that purpose all along.
At some point, red strings have been wrapped loosely around my wrists.
The faint touch pressing against the small of my back also seems to remind me that he has already decided to close the curtain on this game.
With a ‘click’, the gemstone on my chest lights up.
In the Jester’s clockwork castle, the escaping Queen has returned to her throne, back under the Jester’s control.
The music ends. In that instant, I seem to catch a flicker of boredom in Lucien’s eyes.
He steps back slowly, his hand about to release me, but I suddenly pull it tightly.
MC: Mr. Jester, the story isn’t over yet.
I take one step forward, not missing the brief flash of surprise in his expression.
The halted music hasn't faded, and the game is still ongoing, just like this story.
I place Lucien's hand back on my waist, leading him to dance with me once more.
MC: "Once upon a time, there was a Queen who ruled over the entire kingdom. The Queen has many, many toys, and she lives in this castle with them."
MC: "Who is her toy, and whose toy is she?"
These are lines written on the last page of the book in the Queen's chamber.
The Jester forgot, even though he exists outside the story, when he entered the story as an escapee character—
he naturally became a part of it.
As I guide Lucien in the swaying dance, the melody begins to play once again.
I am the Queen of this castle.
MC: Dear Mr. Jester, I welcome you to my castle.
As if summoned, the toys dashed out of the darkness, surrounding us on all sides.
The silver disco ball spins, scattering vibrant specks of light across the entire room.
I pull Lucien's hand, leading his steps as we spin in the middle of the room, as though this is precisely the center of the whole world.
??: [cheers] Queen! Queen! Our beloved queen!
But Lucien also seems unwilling to be outdone; those deep, profound eyes now brim with even more undisguised mirth.
When I want to take a step forward, he moves even closer, drawing me into his embrace. When he lightly pushes me forward, I sidestep and twirl to his side.
Beneath the flowing melody, a more suggestive and provocative tension pervades the air.
The contending steps and calculating gazes, exchange of critical winning moves—each and every second is savored before victory arrives.
MC: Give me your heart.
I place my fingertips on the black heart on his chest as I lean forward–––
He encircles me even more firmly in his arms, letting me sink deeper into the depths of his eyes.
At the same time, the black hue underneath my palm gradually fades away, replaced by a red glow identical to the gemstone on my chest. The light reflects in our shared gaze.
“Thump”, “thump."
The sensation of heartbeat felt beneath my fingertips seems to make that shade of red even more vivid.
Lucien: What if I refuse?
He speaks as his fingertips caress my chin gently yet resistlessly, his warmth delicately spread through the fabric of his glove.
In places hidden from view, the red strings entwined around my wrists and fingertips gently tighten as though he is orchestrating my entire heartbeat along with the blood vessels.
MC: It's already too late.
My hand gently caresses the seemingly throbbing light, and I lightly tighten my grasp.
MC: Each toy's chest is hollow, and in the Queen's chamber you haven't had the chance to visit... I found all the hearts.​​
When someone's heart is taken, they become the Queen's loyal and devoted toy.
However, only a Queen bound by shackles can take someone else's heart.
MC: You should have left quickly after putting the "wooden control bar" on me
Lucien: I was too greedy.
Lucien: Or rather... from the very beginning, I was mesmerized by something far too beautiful.
Lucien: But I don't feel like I've lost anything.
He makes his heart fit even more completely in my palm, yet at the same time, he also tightens the red strings in his hand, his eyes flickering with dazzling light.
Lucien: If you want this heart of mine, you might have to pay a heavy price.
To get his heart, you must willingly surrender to his control. To not be controlled, you must get his heart.
This game seems like a never-ending story.
Lucien: Now… answer me again.
Lucien: Do you still want my heart?