// ⚠️ cw v*re-ish theme, (not heavy) bl**d, d*b-con. Please proceed with caution if you are sensitive to these topics
Some translation notes! In here, both MC and Lucien are Snake Demons (蛇妖). Demons (妖 yāo) – (which is sometimes left untranslated as “Yao” or alternatively translated as Monsters)
Yao / demons are born when an animal, plant, or even an inanimate object absorbs spiritual energy over a long period and then gains spiritual awareness.
They're not necessarily evil and are different from 魔 (Mó)/Evil Spirits. Still, their identity as such beings in this AU is important to remember because it means that both MC and Lucien are indifferent to human standards of morality.
Also in this date, there's a concept of cultivation or "修炼" (xiūliàn), which is a central concept in many Chinese fantasy genres, particularly in xianxia (仙侠) literature.
It involves the practice of refining one's body, mind, and spirit to achieve higher levels of power, enlightenment, or immortality. As for other terms… I'll add T/N if there are more specific terms ahah-
And, let me explain a bit about the v*re theme... So, in some Chinese fantasy literature and cultivation stories, consuming others can be a method of cultivation.
This practice might involve eating parts of these beings to gain their powers or absorb their essence, which is believed to advance their cultivation level.
Although I’m also kind of convinced with what Chuverall said that ‘hunger’ here is a metaphor for another kind of desire or Lucien just genuinely confuses l*st with hunger LOL
I'm starving.
I swallow a pile of random 'food' expressionlessly, yet the intense emptiness and hunger are not satisfied in the slightest.
Immense power courses through my body, but it seems as if it is confined within an earthen jar, desperately trying to find an outlet, yet unable to find a way out.
I am well aware that, after four hundred years, I have once again encountered the opportunity to break through the Primordial Spirit stage.
[T/N: 元神 (yuán shén) or "primordial spirit" refers to a refined spiritual esssence that, when cultivated, can gain awareness and project outward.]
Back then, I devoured the crocodile demon that had occupied the deep pool for hundreds of years, and only after digesting its entire Primordial Spirit did I successfully achieve a breakthrough.
[T/N: A breakthrough in cultivation refers to a significant leap in spiritual or martial progress, often leading to enhanced abilities or a higher level of power. It can happen several times.]
I feel the surge of power within me, and now I only crave for more.
Half a country's worth of humans is probably not enough. I still need to find a way to concentrate on cultivation, or perhaps consume another powerful being.
The harsh, blazing sunlight pierces through the cave entrance, casting a bright circle inside the cave.
I squint my eyes, lazily stretching my snake tail towards the patch of light.
The cautious tip of my snake tail ventures only an inch into the light but is instantly pierced by the scorching heat, causing it to shudder and quickly recoil back into the shadows.
MC: …So hot.
MC: I'll think about it later.
The chilly and damp stone cave dispels the scorching heat of the sun. I close my eyes and adjust my position for greater comfort, half my body submerged in the pool water.
There's no need to rush. After all, this scorching summer heat that could kill a demon is a mysterious demon-slaying technique in itself.
??: …
Suddenly, I sense something entering my cave.
It's just that the little creature's demonic power is too weak to stir even a sliver of my interest.
Perhaps because of my indifference, "it" seems to be growing bolder, venturing closer and even approaching my pool.
Slightly displeased, I open my eyes, only to meet with a pair of unfamiliar eyes—deep and brimming with smiles.
??: So hot. May I borrow a corner of your abode, My Lord?
The man's clothes hang loosely on his frame, barely concealing his broad, sculpted chest in a manner that seems almost deliberate as he leans casually against a nearby rock.
Who?
Countless lesser monsters inhabit this mountain, and I never pay attention to those I can crush with half a finger.
But perhaps it's because I'm so bored, or perhaps because he carries the scent of my own kind, that I can't help but stare at him for a long while.
Lucien: My Lord, my name is Lucien.
Perhaps sensing the reason for my silence, he smiles gracefully and bows his head respectfully.
Lucien: I have been living in this mountain for many years, always relying on your protection, My Lord.
Lucien: I have expressed my gratitude to you many times before, My Lord, but it seems...
He pauses, his deep and bright eyes settling on me.
Lucien: ...those sentiments have not reached you.
Hearing him say this, I try to recall the countless memories I've accumulated over the years on this mountain, but I can't possibly remember the face of every insignificant lesser demon.
Seeing that I still show no reaction, the lesser demon's face seems to stiffen for a brief moment.
But a seductive curve quickly forms on his lips as he steps into the pool.
His body bends gracefully in the pool as water laps over his waist and abdomen, leaving him glistening wet.
He extends his arms into the pool, seemingly sensing and finding my tail as if guided by instinct.
His cold fingertips gently caress my scales, then encircle my tail and draw it towards his chest.
Water droplets run down his hair, trace the contours of his jaw and cascade onto his chest, mingling with the water dripping from the tip of my tail. Together, they seep through his semi-transparent garment, disappearing into the curve of his waist.
The uncomfortable warmth faintly spread over me, yet his audacious behavior piqued my curiosity. I wonder what intriguing actions this little demon can do.
But my somewhat arrogant and silent scrutiny doesn't seem to instill any fear in him.
He nuzzles my snake tail with his face, his lips gently pressing against my scales. After a moment of delicate caressing, he—
Suddenly bites down hard.
MC: …!
A tingling numbness quickly spreads from the tip of my tail. The venom is manageable, and it will take me less than a moment to neutralize it.
Yet, in that fleeting moment, a particularly hazy, green-colored figure forms in my mind.
MC: Are you that little green snake who bit my tail decades ago and then fainted?
One autumn many years ago, the sunlight was still pleasant, and I was coiled idly in the mountain, feeling bored to death.
The autumn light stretches endlessly, the entire forest suffused with a lingering pleasant fragrance that makes me coil my body even more lazily.
My demonic aura permeates the entire mountain, utterly unrestrained. The lesser demons cower in corners, none foolish enough to dare disturb my tranquility.
Suddenly, a burst of very weak stings prickled the tip of my tail.
Puzzled, I lifted my tail, only to find a small green snake clinging to it.
It must have tried to feed on my energy but was overwhelmed by the backlash of my demonic power. The little snake has already fainted, but its tiny fangs are still tightly embedded in me.
It's natural for creatures to have a predatory instinct, but such a bold and greedy little thing might eventually develop even greater desires.
I observed it for a few more moments with interest before casually tossing it away.
That blurry green shape in the daylight unexpectedly coalesces into the face of the person standing before me.
Turns out it really transformed into a demonic form.
My tail instantly coils around his entire body, tightening around his neck, and pulls him towards me.
MC: What did you say your name was?
Lucien: My Lord, my name is Lucien.
The venomous fangs in his mouth remain unretracted as if deliberately left exposed to provoke.
I grip his upper jaw, my fingertips sliding into his parted lips, caressing the delicate tips of his fangs.
As I gradually apply pressure, a pale yellow liquid slowly trickles down my fingertips.
A fascination stirs within my heart, and I drive the venom to flow uncontrollably until it overflows my palm.
The labored breath escaping his lips doesn't bring even a hint of fear to the face before me. Those eyes, like mysterious deep pools, draw me in completely.
MC: I remember you.
I lick the venom on my fingertips and then lightly lean toward his lips.
MC: Perhaps devouring you wouldn't be such a bad idea.
Lucien: It would be my honor to become a part of you, My Lord.
Venom from his fangs spills to the corner of his lips, adding an inexplicable allure to his serene expression.
Lucien: However... to you, my lord, my demonic power is very weak. Even after appearing before you many times, I never caught your attention.
Lucien: I'm afraid I can't help you achieve your breakthrough, my lord.
[T/N: Throughout this date, he used a "您" (nín) to address MC instead of the usual “你” (nǐ), which is the formal and polite way to say "you" in Chinese. It is used to show respect, deference, and admiration to the person being addressed.]
His face even bears a hint of hidden bitterness, as if silently reproaching me.
MC: How did you know I wanted to breakthrough?
Lucien: Because in my eyes... all I see is your figure.
Lucien: In the corners you never noticed, I've always been watching you.
Through those deep and unfathomable eyes, I see a reflection of a slender white figure, and her face is filled with disdain and inexplicable emotion.
Lucien: You've protected this place for many years, providing us with a safe haven. So, I also wish to contribute my humble efforts to your cause.
Lucien: I have found a group of remarkable humans who might be able to help you break through your cultivation, My Lord.
Half a country wouldn't even suffice.
I form this sentence in my mind but don't say it out loud.
Facing my silence, he gently smiles, as if he had expected it.
Lucien: What do you think, My Lord... about the 361 demon-slaying cultivators of the Qingping Sect, including the Sect Leader—what should be done with them?
His hushed whispers are carried on a breathy exhale and reach my lips. Sinking into the depths of his dark eyes, I curl my lips into a smile.
MC: Is there more to this than meets the eye?
Lucien: In the past two years, many demon hunters from this sect have repeatedly disturbed the peace in the mountain, and many lesser demons have fallen at their hands.
Lucien: My Lord, you have cast spells in this mountain, clearly not wishing to be disturbed. I merely volunteered to ease your worries.
MC: But those bugs always manage to get in, do you know why?
Lucien: A sophisticated formation like yours, My Lord, is naturally beyond the comprehension of a lowly demon like myself.
Lucien: The Qingping Sect is also a great sect with a hundred years of history; [chuckles] Perhaps there are some mysterious and powerful humans there.
Lucien smiles modestly and looks at me obediently.
I close my eyes, pondering his words over and over.
The Qingping Sect people have been coming to the mountain to hunt demons in summer and winter for the past few years. They must have observed my movements.
When I'm dormant, I'm usually too lazy to bother with such trivial matters. But if it's delivered to my doorstep, there's certainly no reason to refuse.
But with Lucien's cultivation level, it should be very difficult for him to handle such a large sect.
I think for a moment, then fling him away.
MC: So, in a place where the talented and powerful people hide, how are you going to offer them to me?
Lucien: I'm just using a few little tricks. You can inspect it now, My Lord.
His words barely leave his lips when the scene before me abruptly blurs. In a flash, I conceal my demonic form.
An unfamiliar Taoist temple comes into view. We are already standing in the shadows of a corner.
I glance around, slightly raise my fingertips, and grip Lucien's neck.
MC: Lucien, I don't like being controlled by anything else.
Lucien: Perhaps… I was just too eager, hoping I could be of some help to you.
Lucien: I really long to see you happy.
His eyes curve into a gentle arc, showing a certain beauty that is both pleasing to the eye and delightful to the heart.
I let out a cold snort, dismissing him, and step out of the shadows, releasing my hold on his neck.
The scorching sun beats down mercilessly, making me irritable. Just as I'm about to turn around and warn that little creature to make it quick, I sense an unusually strange and mysterious Qi in the air.
In the shadows, Lucien stands still, his deep, dark eyes hiding a gleam.
Interesting.
A spark of interest ignites within me, and I swagger down the road.
Several demon hunters who look quite delicious pass by me. They appear numb, like puppets, and show no sign of panic in my presence.
??: Ah, it's Mr. Lucien!
Suddenly, a young Daoist Priest seems to regain his senses and runs towards me.
Lucien, who is already standing beside me, responds gently.
Lucien: Greetings, Daoist Priest.
Lucien's eyes shimmer with an emerald green light. As his voice trails off, several nearby demon hunters eagerly gather around, engaging him in conversation.
MC: "Do they know you?"
I glance at Lucien and use a spell to transmit the words directly into his mind.
But he merely smiles faintly, and under the gaze of those empty eyes, he leans down and whispers in my ear.
Lucien: Some things are easier to erode from within.
Lucien: After all... I'm just a little green snake.
Abundant power surges within me. After absorbing and dissolving the last remnants of the primordial spirit, I open my eyes, feeling refreshed and invigorated.
While there's still a long way to go before my primordial spirit breaks through, I won't force it.
The blazing sun overhead reminds me of the day I parted ways with Lucien, leaving me to wonder how many days and nights have slipped by since.
The vastness of time has long since lost its meaning for me.
MC: Some of these are for you.
Lucien: …?
Upon hearing my words, he seemed to freeze for a moment, his eyes darkening slightly.
Lucien: If I wanted to keep it all for myself, I wouldn't have invited you, My Lord. All of this is my offering…
MC: You're so long-winded.
MC: Rewards are given for merit; take it if it's given to you. Those are my rules.
I was too lazy to listen to his long-winded speech, so I stood on the steps and looked down at him.
MC: Lucien, I have only one question for you right now.
MC: Aren't you hungry?
Lucien: ….
He stood in my shadow, deeply gazing up at me.
After a long pause, he curled his lips into a bewitching smile, his gaze locked intently on me. He extended his tongue, lightly licking his lips.
Lucien: Very hungry, my lord.
I stand up and stretch, ready to take a stroll in the mountain and see how Lucien's cultivation is progressing.
He's very clever. In just a few decades, he's not only cultivated into a demon form but also amassed considerable power and even dealt with the entire Qingping Sect.
Perhaps in a few more decades, he could be the final piece I need for my breakthrough.
Just as I am about to leave the cave, I sense an extremely familiar pheromone nearby.
Its owner is cleverly masking their scent within my demonic aura, but it seems they're struggling to maintain the disguise, and faint traces are still leaking through.
I raise my head to gaze at the colossal Buddha statue before me, and then with a swift movement, I stand atop the entwining vines that encircle it. A quick glance reveals a familiar figure—
Lucien: ...!
His dark green outer robe has slipped down to his arms, revealing a large expanse of his back. The slanting rays of the sun illuminate the faint snake scales on his skin.
Gold dust spills from the cracks in the Buddha statue, scattering around him. One of his hands, unable to contain the surging power, has fully transformed into its demonic form.
His broad and supple snake tail is fully exposed, writhing restlessly against the stone statue, creating a subtle rustling sound as it rubs against the surface.
Fine beads of sweat emerge on his forehead, gradually dampening his hair, which clings stickily to his flushed skin and trails downwards.
Lucien seems surprised by my arrival, turning around with a guarded look, his fingers reaching for his shoulder as if wanting to cover up more.
Lucien: My Lord, how could you...?
MC: Lucien, you're really good at finding places, aren't you?
I examine the area around the Buddha’s Hand. Lush bushes cover most of the cave entrance, providing him with ample shelter along with my demonic aura.
A small white snake then slithered into the opening of his clothing, making its way up to his face. [T/N: As mentioned, powerful cultivators can project their souls outward—so this white snake is the MC.]
Lucien: I'm fortunate to have your protection.
He pants lightly, his eyes never leaving even for a moment, fixed firmly on my figure.
Lucien: I understand that you needed to focus on your cultivation and didn't want to be disturbed.
Lucien: But I haven't experienced many breakthroughs before. I need to focus all my energy on refining my spirit. Last time, I almost got eaten by other lesser demons…
Lucien: Being by your side, My Lord, I feel more at ease and can also help guard against potential dangers for you.
His husky voice sends tingling sensations through me, making me inexplicably feel a bit hungry.
Lucien: I just didn't expect you to be so powerful, absorbing so many spirits in such a short time…
He furrows his brow in what seems like frustration, which looks a bit cute.
MC: Those are still far from enough, but your breakthrough speed is also faster than I thought.
Lucien: It's all… thanks to you, My Lord.
He forces a weak smile, seemingly still struggling to suppress the surging power within him.
I know that feeling, the unbearable heat from the inside out, the frantic surge of Qi sweeping through the body again and again, as the soul drifts between fullness and emptiness.
I've always been on my own, so it's quite interesting to witness someone else going through this for the first time.
Lucien's fingertips continue to tighten, revealing an attractive white color.
He seems to be waiting there, waiting for me to disappear. But I don't.
I wiggle my fingers, and the little white snake glides along his burning skin. Every inch closer elicits a heavier, instinctive gasp from the depths of his throat.
The increasingly prominent snake scales seem to be burning, and his long tail coils around the Buddha's hand over and over while continuously trembling.
MC: Is it hard to bear?
He knows she's laughing.
Through his hazy gaze, he sees the girl perched on a nearby branch, like a wisp of delicate white gauze, overlooking him completely.
He can feel the cold little snake mischievously exploring all over his body as if her fingertips were stroking him.
This makes him feel even more messed up.
The power surges within him, more violently than he anticipated, and it's taking longer than expected.
He overestimated her greed, and at the same time, underestimated his own.
A tremendous sense of emptiness drowns him in an instant, magnified infinitely under her wicked gaze.
At that moment, it's as if he forgets everything.
He instinctively follows that surge of intense force, returning to a darker place, where he finds some form of primitiveness and liberation.
A surge of heat courses through him from his chest to his lower body, carrying him from the heights of the clouds to the mist below.
He is obviously filled with a momentary sense of satisfaction, yet a greater emptiness is born. Amidst the lingering white mist, her eyes always remain clear.
Bright, vile, and charming.
As if shining into his greedy soul, allowing him to see the reflection of his face so clearly.
Lucien: [breathing heavily after some kind of ‘release’...but obviously haven't ‘satisfied’ yet-] ….
Suddenly, I see Lucien smile.
He leans against the Buddha's palm, his entire body sprawled out and clothes in a mess. It's as if he's completely submerged in water.
The tense snake's tail trembles as it lifts, gently and intimately coiling around my wrist.
People say snake demons are masters of seduction, but perhaps they are not even one ten-thousandth as good as the person before me.
Lucien: Teach me... My Lord.
MC: Aren't you afraid that I'll really eat you?
I laugh and tease him. The moment my toes touch the Buddha's hand, a scorching hot snake's tail wraps tightly around my waist, coiling down to one of my ankles.
With a gentle tug, he pulls me into an even hotter embrace.
Lucien: Then just eat me.
Lucien: From the very beginning, I didn't mind becoming one with you, My Lord.
His breath is hot, and so is his gaze. This kind of temperature, which usually makes me uncomfortable, fills me with some kind of pleasure now.
I gently caress his chest, feeling the surge of Qi within him, and can't help but smile even wider.
MC: If you want to be eaten by me... you're still too weak.
Infusing my power into my palm, I gather his power into one place.
At this moment, I realize that I might have left Lucien with too much force. It's no wonder he hasn't fully absorbed such a massive force. It's also fortunate that he has exceptional abilities.
If he were an ordinary demon, his meridians would have ruptured long ago. [T/N: Meridians (经脉) are the channels through which Qi/vital energy flows in the body, if it ruptures it can lead to death]
MC: Luckily, you've been able to hold on until now.
MC: But... you still need to work harder.
I push my palm forward, dismantling that power and sending it into his primordial spirit.
I feel myself being hugged tightly, his whole body trembling uncontrollably. His snake fangs bite hard into my shoulder and release his venom with a force that feels like a torrent.
The venom he secreted is like sweet honey, devoid of any threat.
When he raises his head again, I see that his deep eyes have become even brighter, as if they have swallowed a thousand surging tides.
MC: How do you feel?
Lucien: My lord... your body is so cold and feels so good.
His tail coils tighter around me, and his scorching breath falls on my neck.
He seems to have coiled his entire body around me, enveloping me in his center.
Lucien: You... are very beautiful.
His wet tongue slides again and again across my throat and neck. I feel like his whole body is exuding a delicious scent.
I'm so hungry.
I can't resist the urge to bite his lips. His strong essence is absorbed into my body through our intertwined lips and tongues.
Lucien doesn't resist at all and just hugs me tightly as if devoutly offering his entire being to me.
In an instant, I push him away, meeting his gaze, which seems to hold an air of expectation.
Lucien: Are you not going to eat me anymore?
He looks a bit tired, but his lips still rest against mine, like the instinctive nuzzling of an animal.
I don't respond to him, only glancing at him for a moment before covering his captivating eyes with my hand.
MC: Go to sleep.
Just a little longer. If I wait a bit more, he'll be even more delicious, and it'll help me break through even further.
[T/N: Fun fact: In real life, snakes intertwine their tails and bite each other when they mate]
Over a month later, on the seventh day of the seventh lunar month, the evening breeze brings a chill. I stretch and head down the mountain, holding up my skirt as I walk.
I quite enjoy human festivals. Every year, during these times, the lively and interesting rituals make this frail race seem a bit more endearing.
Bathed in the soft glow, a familiar figure dressed in green appears in my sight.
Lucien: My Lord, it seems quite lively down there. Is that the human "temple fair" they speak of?
MC: You've been in human form for decades, and you know quite a few demon hunters from the Qingping Sect. Haven't you ever been to a temple fair?
Lucien: I'm just a lowly demon, so I wouldn't dare.
Lucien: But if I go with you, I'm sure I'll be able to experience some of the fun.
MC: Are you a fool?
With a grand sweep of my hand, I lead him into the warm and dazzling sea of lights.
I turn to face him, a smile playing on my lips as I tilt my chin up in a challenge.
MC: Since you're already a demon, you can afford to be even more bolder sometimes.
His pupils dilate sharply. The gently swaying lanterns cast a soft, flickering light as Lucien gazes deeply into my eyes. Then, in a surprising turn, he reaches out and takes my hand in his.
Lucien: I will certainly heed your teachings, My Lord.
We make our way through the bustling crowd. Though Lucien seems a little curious about everything around him, he still walks steadily by my side.
Suddenly, he stops in his tracks.
I turn back to see him carefully wiping a jade bracelet on one of the stalls.
The bracelet is a vibrant green throughout, its color rich and translucent, with a subtle, warm glow. At a glance, it's clearly a piece of exquisite jade.
I don't know why, but that captivating shade of green reminds me of his original appearance.
He quickly pays for it, and amidst the vibrant spectacle of festive lights, gently places the bracelet on my wrist.
MC: What are you doing?
Lucien: I saw that other humans seem to do this. Do you like it?
In that fleeting moment, he seems to be imbued with the essence of the human world. His eyes curve into gentle crescents as he smiles tenderly.
In the vast and endless expanse of time, I can no longer remember if the last person who smiled at me like this was also so soul-stirring.
Perhaps, there has never been such a person before.
MC: Though I can't say whether I like it or not...
MC: But you seem to have become even more delicious.
Lucien seems to smile even more happily. For some reason, I think I see the same emotion of mine reflected in his eyes.
But that's probably just my imagination. Despite his greed, he's ultimately just a weak little demon.
As we stroll along, the distant voice of a storyteller drifts towards us.
Storyteller: “Continuing from where we left off, the battle between the thousand-year-old white snake demon of Baihua Mountain and the crocodile demon has been at a standstill for a full hundred days…”
Groups of young boys and girls walk together, their faces flushed with shy smiles. An elderly woman calls out, advertising her steaming hot meat buns. Red firecrackers explode, welcoming a bride from some unknown family.
The festive atmosphere surrounds us. Perhaps influenced by the surroundings, I hear Lucien's curious voice.
Lucien: My Lord, are you also interested in human love?
MC: That's the most impermanent thing in this world.
I take a bite of the candied hawthorn he's holding and gaze at the ordinary faces around us.
MC: It might be interesting, but as demons, we live for far too long. So long that...
MC: Such fragile things can't nourish our parched and greedy souls.
MC: But if you're interested, you could always find a human and experience it a little.
I smile and playfully bop his nose.
MC: But be careful, don't let any bad woman trick you, Lucien.
Lucien: You worry too much. I have no interest in those.
Lucien: Because I've already encountered and tasted something far more delectable.
His dark inky eyes hold my reflection captive, as if drawing me into their hidden depths.
Lucien: Lord MC has taught me everything I wanted to know…
Lucien: As one of the same kind.
Later, Lucien takes the initiative to show me around several places. After we've explored the town extensively, fireworks illuminate the deep night sky.
Lucien: Do you know where we can enjoy the most beautiful fireworks?
MC: You've asked the right demon.
With a flick of my finger, I whisk him away to an ancient pagoda that's been sealed for many years.
The airtight walls keep the interior pitch black. The air is filled with the scent of sandalwood, and the faint sound of fireworks echoes like distant bells.
Lucien: It seems... we can't see any fireworks here.
MC: Just wait.
I turn my palm, and in the blink of an eye, the surrounding stone walls suddenly become transparent, as if they were never there.
I pull Lucien to sit at the center of the circular platform. Suddenly, a profusion of vibrant fireworks bursts forth all around us, their carefree beauty so close as if within reach.
The vibrant colors of the fireworks paint Lucien's figure, layer upon layer. For the first time, someone is here with me to enjoy the fireworks, and my heart can't help but fill with a touch of joy.
MC: Humans are so rigid. They think a tranquil place can't also be lively. What a waste of a good spot.
MC: Might as well let these Buddhas enjoy the show too.
Lucien: Indeed… incredibly beautiful.
As he speaks, it's hard to tell if his eyes are fixed on me or the fireworks behind me.
But beautiful scenery is always fleeting. Soon, the fireworks display comes to an end.
And as I try to stand up, I suddenly realize that I can't move.
Just as I'm about to summon my power, a piercing pain shoots through my entire body. It feels as though some invisible ropes in the air are binding me in place.
While I'm still puzzled, I hear Lucien's surprised voice—
Lucien: ...I didn't expect it to succeed on the first try.
I lift my head, and our gazes collide. His eyes are full of smiles.
His index and middle fingers pressed together, their tips shimmering with a faint light as he swiftly forms an intricate seal in the air.
The instant I see the strikingly familiar gesture, my eyes widen in shock.
MC: ...Why do you know a sealing spell used only by demon hunters?!
Lucien: Humans are rigid, thinking a tranquil place can't be lively. And you demons are just as rigid. Who says...
Lucien: ...a demon can't learn the arts of eliminating demons?
His lips form a triumphant and seductive curve as his cold fingertips caress my cheek.
Lucien: Don't worry, I know my own capabilities.
Lucien: The formation I've set up across the entire town, combined with the second layer of formation at the heart of it, will only restrain you for a short while.
Lucien: However, this short time will be enough.
His voice softly weaves into my ears as he holds me tightly in his embrace.
MC: Those places you took me to earlier... were they all part of setting up this formation?
Lucien: That was merely just a test.
Lucien: It was you who said, I could be a bit bolder.
His delicate breath steadily brushes against my neck, making me feel lightheaded that maintaining my human form takes almost all of my strength.
MC: This… this is a Qingping Sect ancient text... You couldn't possibly have had the chance to…
A shockingly unbelievable thought suddenly pops into my mind. I clutch his lapel tightly, my whole body trembling.
MC: So it was you... You found the weakness in the mountain formation and led the Qingping Sect to hunt the demons.
Lucien: Yes, it was me.
All pretense vanishes from his eyes, revealing utterly raw and unbridled greed and desire.
Lucien: Those humans are so easily deceived. As long as I help them kill a few demons, they think I'm a talent worth cultivating.
Lucien: So I had the chance to plant the poison. In just over a decade, they would be completely under my control.
Lucien: And My Lord, you are my best reward.
Lucien: I finally found the opportunity to gain your trust. And with your help, I also obtained the ancient text.
[T/N: I think, her ‘help’ refers to her ‘eating’ the most Sect member which was his offering-]
[-now that the whole sect was gone, he was able to gain access to the Sect's sacred ancient text, which allowed him to learn how to create this formation to trap her-]
His words are incredibly gentle, yet devoid of any warmth. He meticulously plans every step, taking small risks for greater gains. In the end, he uses the entire town as a formation, waiting for me to walk into the trap myself.
MC: Have you been wanting to eat me all along?
Lucien: I've never lied to you.
He smiles as he presses his cold lips against my brow and eyes, tenderly caressing my lips.
Lucien: I told you, from the moment you appeared in my life, in my eyes... all I see is your figure.
Lucien: A snake wanting to eat another snake… that's normal, isn't it…?
Lucien: I've always, always... wanted to eat you.
Along with his voice, a slippery tail coils around the tip of my own.
As if fearing I might escape, it coils around me tightly from the start. Our scales rustle as they rub against each other, and I feel inexplicable suffocation.
Lucien lowers his gaze to look at me, his eyes filled with undisguised desire. He bares his fangs, teasingly grazing my skin before swiftly sinking them in with a sharp bite.
After a slight sting, a cold liquid is injected into the bite mark. My skin grows hotter and hotter, making the coldness even more alarming.
He probably knows that this bit of venom can't harm me, so he indulges in "tasting" me to his heart's content.
His sharp fangs expertly latch onto the easy-to-bite spots, biting down hard as if he really intends to devour me.
He leans toward me, pressing closer and closer. Our tails are already entwined inseparably; the tips of our hair and the sashes of our clothes are in complete disarray.
I can't summon any power to resist the venom's encroachment. I can only feel the burning heat spreading through my limbs and bones, my whole body trembling uncontrollably.
Lucien: I know I can't completely devour you yet, but it doesn't matter…
Lucien: I will leave my mark inside your body, on every inch of your skin.
Lucien: Let our breaths entwine... until yours carries the essence of mine.
He bites my lip, his mouth devouring every bit of my moan and wet sounds. His tongue, laced with venom, forcefully swirls over mine, compelling me to swallow every drop.
Lucien: Until... the day I eat you.
My head is swimming, all I can feel is his snake tail coiling tighter around me, a tingling heat flowing through my body as something is being poured inside me again and again.
The feeling is too arousing, making me instinctively tighten my body, but also wrapping him even tighter.
The air is heavy with erotic scents, and the sound of our entwined scales rubbing against each other creates an ambiguous symphony of slick and moist noises, intensifying my hunger step by step.
MC: [laughs] The one who should be eaten... is you, isn't it?
MC: Given time, I will cleanse your weak poison completely.
MC: Great, you already look delicious.
Unfamiliar yet pleasurable waves surge rapidly within me, hitting me again and again, causing me to instinctively bite him back.
The cloyingly sweet blood, mixed with venom and clear bodily fluids, fills our mouths, necks, and entire bodies.
Lucien: …Then let’s see how this plays out.
Scalding sweat trickles down his jaw, blending into my clothes that are already soaked with sweat.
Lucien pushes deeper into me as if even the deepest part of my soul is being imbued with his essence.
Lucien: No matter the outcome… we will… become one.
His final line! I think… it's the biggest proof that he never really lied to her. His final line on this date reveals that his ultimate goal is to become one with her, whether through her eating him or vice versa, the method or outcome doesn't matter to him.
Since he is much weaker than her, it's easier for him to be consumed (which is why he keeps asking her to eat him). However, in case she doesn’t want to eat him, he also has this backup plan.
Whether he is to be consumed or to consume her, both scenarios require decades of deceiving humans to first gain her attention. While his methods may not be entirely honest, it is undeniable that he has worked very hard for her and it's a bit endearing-
or maybe it's time for me to admit that atp i'll forgive any stunts he pulled *kicked*
Although the ending is fairly predictable given his character, this date introduces a fresh element with its unique dynamic where the power balance shifts in favor of MC
It conveys a similar dynamic of the ‘God x mortal’ trope, where the mortals yearn for the love of their God. And despite all the things he did, I really can't help but think that he really is just a hardworking yet stubborn/obsessive little snake HAHA.
Not much analysis here, this date is pretty much just ‘fast food’ LOL. So, while his obsession towards MC definitely gets amped up in this AU, I do like how it still retains his core like his greediness, curiosity, and obsessiveness/stubbornness though
and the details of them mirroring each other's desire are always so!!!
I guess... that’s all haha. Thank you for reading~