video credit: 一包洛氏薯片 in bilibili, thank you for letting me use the video to be subtitled!
[T/N: This date references some dates in the past; like his Prison Date, Monochrome Scenery Exclusive Past and its Event Story, “Lab Koi” call, his last year birthday story, and The Sea No Longer Distant MQ.
I’ll put links on the comment, Since this date has a lot of callback, it’d be better if you read those first if you haven’t :>; or at least the MQ and birthday story because this date is a kind of extension to those]
I wake up to the faint whirring of the fan and the subtle scent of a fruity fragrance lingering in the air. I turn over in bed, slowly blinking my eyes open.
The brilliant sunlight filters through the lace curtains, casting iridescent patches of light that dance playfully across Lucien's body.
He sits in a rattan chair by the window, flipping through a book in his hand. An exquisite purple clay tea set rests on a side table nearby.
For a fleeting, dreamlike moment, I feel like I've traveled back to the 1970s.
As if sensing my gaze, Lucien turns his head, and a hint of a smile appears in his eyes as he looks at me.
Lucien: It seems a certain lady hasn't adjusted to the time difference yet.
Lucien: It is now noon in U.S. time.
My foggy brain finally starts to sluggishly turn. I leave the bed, drag a chair over to sit beside him and yawn again.
MC: It can't be helped. It's already the wee hours in Loveland City.
Lucien: Oh? But as I recall, a certain night owl sometimes doesn't go to bed obediently even at those hours.
MC: ...Hmph, you're one to talk, Mr. I-Don't-Need-Sleep!
Lucien: I've been quite well-behaved lately, haven't I? And when it comes to sleep duration, well, let's just say you're the ‘expert’.
Lucien blinks at me innocently, and I quickly take a sip of the tea he offers, hoping he won’t delve deeper into this topic.
A sweet and sour sensation blooms in my mouth. Perhaps there are other unknown herbs added, as I also detect a hint of honeyed sweetness.
Ten hours ago, in the dim and quiet cabin, the only sound was the occasional soft tapping of a keyboard from the seat next to me.
I lifted a corner of my eye mask and leaned closer.
MC: It's time for sleep, Professor Lucien. Didn't you say the seminar doesn't start until next week? We arrived three days early.
Lucien: That's true, but I don't plan to use this time for conference preparations.
Lucien: After all, a certain classmate expressed a desire to take this opportunity to visit my lab from my master's and Ph.D. days. I want to dedicate my time fully to you without any interruptions from other matters.
Beyond his words, I sensed other emotions in his earnest tone.
MC: Is our Professor Lucien nervous because I'm going to visit the places where you once studied and lived?
Lucien: Yes.
He admitted it frankly, his eyes lit up as he looked at me.
Lucien: That place is very important to me.
Lucien: This feeling is like... inviting you to step into a chapter of my past.
Lucien: It should be a proper occasion, something worth your anticipation.
As I step out the door, a wave of heat washes over me. Thankfully, the house is nestled among the trees, providing some relief from the sweltering heat.
Lucien leads me down the stone steps, deeper into the verdant greenery. The lively apple trees grow abundantly, and even the breeze seems to carry a sweet fragrance.
The bed-and-breakfast he booked is located within Carver Estate Farm, not far from the lab. Since it's still early, we decided to take a stroll in the farm's orchard first.
MC: Now I finally feel like I'm truly on an American farm—
Lucien: The furniture and decor in that room can indeed be a bit misleading.
Lucien: That said, the radio and clock in the living room are just decorative pieces, and the stainless steel kettle in the kitchen is also fixed to the table.
Lucien: As for the fan and the TV, including the sewing machine, they actually work and can somewhat be considered "antiques".
MC: When did you…
Lucien: The wait while you're asleep feels endless*, so I have to keep myself busy.
[T/N: Lucien actually uses the word "难熬" (literally meaning hard to bear) to express his longing and impatience while waiting for MC to wake up, emphasizing how much he misses her rather than annoyance]
Seeing him speak so seriously, I can't help but give his palm a gentle pinch.
Lucien: To be honest, I was a bit curious. I didn't expect the owner to maintain this style, or rather, deliberately preserve it.
MC: Have you been here before?
Lucien: Mm, Dr. Lawson brought the entire lab here before.
[T/N: Dr. Lawson was Lucien's mentor during his Master's and PhD years, in those years Lucien also had some seniors like Colt, Caroline, and Elliot. You can read more in Monochrome Scenery Exclusive Past-
-It can be said that the time during his Master’s and PhD years was the 'happiest' for him, after he abandoned his name and before he met MC-
-This genius discovers that he’s not the only one. Surprisingly, this isn’t a bad thing; because being considered a genius had previously isolated him from his peers-
-but being surrounded by other geniuses provides him with a taste of mundane life... although he can’t fully taste it due to Black Swan’s pressure at that time]
Lucien: I remember it was autumn. We had just finished a phase of our experiment.
Lucien: The process of this experiment was very prolonged, and almost everyone expended a lot of effort. Fortunately, the results exceeded expectations.
Lucien: As a celebration, or perhaps simply out of a need for a break, Dr. Lawson suggested an outing after the experiment concluded.
MC: Sounds like a team-building activity?
Lucien: You could say that.
Lucien smiles lightly.
Lucien: At first, we all thought it would just be a matter of finding a nice restaurant, having a meal and chatting, or going to the theater to watch a performance.
Lucien: It wasn't until everyone received an email from Dr. Lawson that we realized we had been granted a mandatory five-day vacation. And the destination was this very farm estate.
MC: Pfft, Dr. Lawson is quite ceremonious about giving everyone a day off~ So, did everyone just obediently accept the arrangement?
I notice Lucien pausing, lost in thought, which is unusual for him. Then, a smile spreads on his lips.
Lucien: Not exactly.
Lucien: Eventually, everyone practically treated this place as a lab annex, almost bringing in equipment. Fortunately, the farm owner was an old friend of Dr. Lawson's, so we weren't kicked out.
MC: Hahaha, I knew it!
As we walk deeper into the apple orchard, the intertwined branches and leaves block out the sunlight, creating a vast expanse of shade. Vibrant red apples dot the lush greenery, looking especially tempting.
Lucien: The farm owner is an elderly Chinese gentleman. It's said that he and his wife came here to live when they were young, and this apple orchard was also planted by them with their own hands.
MC: No wonder. I think I suddenly understand why the house's decor feels so nostalgic.
Lucien: Perhaps it's precisely because they've been away for so long that they need tangible things to solidify those memories.
The swaying shadows of the trees dance in his deep eyes, and even though he's talking about someone else, I feel like I'm hearing unspoken words meant for himself.
So I rise on my tiptoes and cup his face, turning it towards me.
MC: So today, little Lucien is revisiting his old stomping grounds~ And as such an accomplished young professor, no less!
MC: This memory is very precious, and it's important to solidify it well.
Lucien: Is that so?
His voice is soft as he lowers his eyelashes and gazes into my eyes.
I feel like my entire being is almost seen through by him. He doesn't say a word, just keeps looking at me.
MC: Why are you staring at me?
Lucien: I'm solidifying this memory.
MC: Um?
Lucien: Because I'm not just here by myself.
Lucien: Today, I'm revisiting this place with my girlfriend. I want to look closely, carefully, and remember your appearance clearly.
I can't help but laugh, my fingertips brushing against his earlobe.
MC: Then how about remembering a bit more~ What else did little Lucien do here?
Lucien: I ate the apples.
MC: ....That doesn't count!
Lucien: Of course it counts. To be precise, it was an apple feast, with apple pie, apple muffins, apple salad, apple stew…
MC: Stop...! You're making me dizzy just looking at these apple trees now.
MC: I feel like they're saying to me, "I'm apple pie, I'm apple muffin…”
I dramatically shake my head and point to the huge fruits hanging above us.
Lucien seems amused by my actions. Seizing the moment, he smoothly takes my hand and plucks the apple hanging closest to us.
Lucien: Then let's eat them all, one by one.
He finishes speaking and even "conjures" a thin blanket from his bag, spreading it on the ground. He pulls me, who is still processing the moment, to sit under the tree.
His seamless actions leave me completely unable to keep up with him, and my questions come out in a jumble.
MC: C- Can we just pick the apples here? And sit down like this? And this blanket…
Lucien: I told you waiting for you to wake up feels endless, and I wasn't lying.
He looks as if he knows I can't do anything about him, and his tone, though seemingly aggrieved, is full of triumph.
We sit side-by-side under the tree, falling into a brief silence. The wind gently blows, as if not wanting to disturb this tranquility.
Lucien & MC: What are you thinking about?
Suddenly, we speak at the same time, and the unexpected coincidence makes us look at each other and laugh.
MC: You go first~
Lucien: I was wondering if an apple might fall on my head.
He says it so seriously that I find it rather cute. On a whim, I get up, pluck an apple, and then gently tap him on the head.
MC: Knock knock…
Lucien seems surprised by my action, the light in his pupils flickers.
Lucien: What about you?
MC: Me…
I smile sheepishly.
MC: I thought of a fairy tale, Prince... Snow White.
Lucien: But that's not how I remember the story?
MC: Because… this is a story I imagined!
Lucien nods thoughtfully, not minding my nonsense at all, but instead curving his eyes in a good mood.
Lucien: Then in your story, who are you?
This question stumps me for a moment, and I pause to think seriously before answering.
MC: I'm the magic mirror.
Lucien: Because the magic mirror knows everything?
MC: Not really, it's because the magic mirror only looks at...the prince.
MC: And if I were the magic mirror, I wouldn't need you to ask, I'd tell you that—
MC: Lucien is the most handsome, the most intelligent, the most amazing, and the person I love the most in this entire world.
My voice is not loud, yet it feels like the entire orchard of apples has heard it. Their already gorgeous red blushing even deeper, making their vibrancy impossible to conceal.
My clamorous heart seems to be thoroughly exposed by the sun, allowing me to distinctly feel its beating and clearly see the smile filling Lucien's eyes.
He lowers his head, takes a bite of the apple in his hand, and lies down without hesitation.
Our hands, which have been holding each other all along, pull me slightly forward because of his sudden movement.
MC: …!
Lucien lies lazily on the plush blanket, each strand of hair scattering softly, as if quietly outlining his innermost feeling at this moment.
His already loose shirt falls open completely, revealing a patch of skin.
He gently blinks and the corners of his lips slightly curl up.
Under the scorching heat, the apples hanging from the branches exude an even more enticing fragrance.
The wind gathers from afar, wave after wave, sweeping through the villa, the woods, and each apple tree, carrying an increasingly rich scent toward us.
His fingertip traces mine, gently caressing the sensitive skin between my thumb and index finger.
It's like some kind of seduction.
Lucien: Miss Magic Mirror, I've been poisoned.
His voice is soft as if melting into the sunlight, yet it possesses a bewitching power that makes one willingly lean closer to him.
Lucien: You can kiss me now.
[T/N:  "Prince Snow White and Miss Magic Mirror" references his second Halloween date from last year, "Prison Date!" It also ties into the theme of "lover as a mirror" from last year's kiss SP, "Blooming Amidst Turbulent Desires MQ."-
- perhaps by seeing your lover's eyes you can see the real and complete you :”. And unique to Lucien, it could be that only through seeing his reflection in her eyes can he perceive the colorful version of himself
]
After buying some apple cookies at the farm store and making a reservation for apple cider making tomorrow, we drive to Dr. Lawson's lab.
The asphalt road under the shade of the trees glistens in the summer light. In the distance, sailboats glide on the river and people cycle along the riverbank.
Perhaps it's due to the fluttering anticipation in my heart, but the half-hour drive feels like it's over in the blink of an eye.
Lucien: Dr. Lawson is giving a lecture in London this week, and the current head of the lab is my senior, Colt. After graduation, he stayed on to continue the research.
Lucien: But he happens to be leading a group of students in an academic exchange with another lab today…
Lucien pauses for a moment, moves the gift bag he just placed on the desk to the side, and takes a sticky note off the computer screen.
Lucien: [quietly reading the sticky note] …..
He waves the sticky note at me, and I can clearly see the lively handwriting on it: "Enjoy: )".
Lucien: It seems like no one will be back today. In that case, let's graciously accept this invitation to enjoy ourselves.
The white walls make the spacious corridor even brighter. Along the way, the walls of classrooms and laboratories are adorned with various awards and patent certificates.
It seems that just by passing through, one can feel countless figures with unceasing footsteps, moving forward persistently and rationally, knocking on one unknown door after another.
Lucien: The desk by the window was the place I most often sat in the lab. Because I always sat there, it eventually became my ‘workstation’.
Lucien: Even if I arrived late, everyone would save this seat for me;
Lucien: But I don't really have a fixed seat in the library. I've never known if those people who are already looking up information early in the morning are actually early risers or if they just never went to bed;
Lucien: Occasionally, when the weather was nice, professors would take us out to the lawn for class;
Lucien: This vending machine used to swallow coins. I wonder if it's been fixed…
Lucien leads me through the corridor, past the small garden, into classrooms, laboratories, and the library…
Perhaps even he himself hasn't realized it, but returning here has made him happy.
It's in the little things he doesn't even realize he's doing: the way his steps quicken without him noticing, the instinctive caress of his fingertips against my palm, the soft murmurs he makes when he notices something different from his memories.
And even the hint of joy as he reveals those past memories with me.
He leads me by the hand through every nook and cranny of this place, making me feel as if I'm walking through his youth.
Finally, we arrive at the dormitory building.
Lucien: Generally, everyone lives here. They're mostly single rooms, so you have a lot of privacy.
MC: I remember you mentioned it before, so is this the common lounge area?
In this not-so-large space in front of us, several sofas and coffee tables are neatly arranged, and the bar counter displays simple everyday items.
Lucien: Mm, usually everyone relaxes here while waiting for experiment results. Occasionally, we also play a round of NOU.
MC: Pfft, I didn't expect this kind of leisure activity.
Lucien: To be precise, it's a traditional activity.
Sensing an interesting topic, I quickly shake his hand and press for more details.
MC: What else? What other things do you do?
Lucien thinks for a moment, then suddenly smiles.
Lucien: There's actually one interesting thing.
Lucien: In the past, before important experimental results were concluded, everyone would tacitly let a certain colleague touch the experiment machine a few more times, and then pray to it.
Lucien: And often, the results wouldn't be too bad, and there was a high probability of exceeding expectations.
MC: Hahaha, so he's the ‘lab koi’ you were talking about!
Lucien nods, the warm white light tracing the contours of his face, making his features appear even softer.
I can hear the nostalgia in his voice that he unintentionally revealed, and I know that he might be thinking about a lot of things at this moment.
I'm reluctant to break this precious silence, my gaze subconsciously drifting towards this lounge, as if I could catch a glimpse of the genius boy who had once been here.
Suddenly, my attention is drawn to the wall next to the bar counter.
It's a small display wall. Besides showcasing some achievement certificates of past researchers, there's also a handwritten message board and some photos.
It turns out there will always be someone who earnestly preserves and longs for the past, with all its time and traces.
I quickly find a familiar figure among them.
It's a slightly blurry photo, almost as if it were a frame grabbed from a video.
The boy surrounded by the crowds slightly widened his eyes, a bouquet of flowers was thrust into his arms as he let the others boisterously tease and laugh around him.
Lucien: ...So, I really was quite surprised back then.
Lucien quietly walks up behind me at some point, his gaze intently fixed on this photo.
The world is truly a wondrous place. It appears to operate according to established principles, yet it often defies logic.
Those emotions that he never understood in the past are now brought before him in some fateful way, regaining their meaning and significance.
Lucien gazes at the girl beside him, observing her happiness and surprise, witnessing all the beautiful emotions that have blossomed because of him.
But she has no idea that her existence has allowed him to see how beautiful the world is.
Lucien's gaze slowly returned to the photo.
Countless colorful ribbons flutter in the air, shimmering and sparkling. The colors, engraved with blessings and well-wishes, seem to transcend time, flowing into his eyes in this very moment.
He speaks softly.
Lucien: It turns out that day was actually so lively.
[T/N: The last scene refers to his birthday story from the CN server last year. He graduated with his PhD on his birthday. This graduation was celebrated by his seniors and professor. At that time, everything was monochrome in his eyes-
-However, visiting the place with MC and seeing his graduation photo with her brings color to a memory that once only in black and white. He now realizes how lively and vibrant that day truly was.]
MC: Are you saying that Senior Brother Colt and Senior Sister Caroline being together was something specifically emailed to you?
Lucien gives a helpless smile.
Lucien: Their reasoning was that I'd receive the information faster by email, and it turns out they were absolutely right.
MC: Hahaha!
We walk back, laughing and chatting. Along the way, I listen to Lucien share stories from his past that he seldom opens up about, about the later developments of his companions, and their current situations.
Some things he tells me without much recollection, while others he needs to think about for a moment. But it seems that the process of remembering makes him a bit happier.
One intersection away from the farm, we pass by a market and stop to buy some food.
Lucien: I'll take the things to the car first, wait for me here.
MC: Okay~ I'll be right here at the market.
While waiting for Lucien to get the car, I notice a stall at the market.
A silver-haired grandma is engrossed in weaving bracelets, her stall filled with dazzling beaded ornaments that shimmer under the soft glow of the glass lamps.
Suddenly, an idea strikes me, and I walk towards the stall.
MC: Ah, it's so hot.
As soon as I enter the house, I hurriedly turn on the air conditioner and fan.
Although the temperature here is still quite pleasant compared to the summer in Loveland City, I’m probably still jet-lagged that I feel a little dizzy.
Struggling to fight the rising drowsiness, I sort and organize the purchased items with Lucien.
Lucien: How about having dinner at the farm's eco-restaurant tonight? That way you can sleep earlier and won't be too tired.
Lucien: Or should we go somewhere farther to try some local specialties?
MC: Either is fine with me~ But before we eat, I need to do something important first.
I arrange the washed apples in a fruit bowl and pull Lucien to sit down with me.
I fish the woven bracelet I bought earlier from the stall out of my pocket. I pull his arm towards me and carefully, with a sense of cherishing, fasten the bracelet around his wrist.
Lucien clasps my wrist in return, his gaze shifting from the bracelet to me, as if waiting for an explanation.
MC: It's just... I suddenly wanted to give you something.
MC: Maybe it's because I saw your photos in the lounge earlier, or maybe it's because I heard so much about your past today.
MC: Even though I knew what those days truly meant to you, it wasn't until I actually went there that I realized…
MC: Everything about Lucien has been well treasured.
He's looking at me, hanging on to my every word.
MC: I'm so lucky to have picked them up again and to have pieced them together with you.
MC: To let them become you, the complete person standing before me.
Gazing into his eyes and seeing the one and only figure reflected there, I feel surprisingly calm and settled inside.
I gently caress his wrist twice.
MC: You see, I tied this knot myself! And I picked out this little agate bead super carefully. Don't you think it's pretty?
MC: It can be like the apple that falls on your head and sparks inspiration or the one that tempts you to be curious about everything.
MC: But now, it is also the "apple" I am giving to you.
MC: Lucien, I hope the present me can also become a special fragment, forever remaining in your memories.
Pinkish-purple hues gently paint the horizon, and a beam of light happens to fall in, illuminating the agate bead.
The smooth texture is brightly highlighted, making the color seem to dance, leaping into those beautiful dark eyes.
Lucien: Indeed… very vibrant.
Lucien: Like an apple.
As he says this, he looks at me, his brows and eyes curving into a beautiful arc, leaving me momentarily unsure of what exactly he's referring to.
MC: Then let’s go eat…!
My cheeks start to feel warm as I belatedly realize what he means, and as I try to rise from his embrace, an irresistible force pulls me back onto his lap.
The arm wrapped around my waist tightens slightly, deepening the embrace.
Lucien: Before that, I also have something important to do.
He lowers his head, kissing the little agate bead cherishingly, then gently moves his kisses to my fingertips resting on his wrist, his lips slowly trailing upward, inch by inch.
Each kiss is feather light and slow, as if he’s carefully tracing every detail, until every part of my skin is stained with his warmth.
Lucien: MC.
He gives my earlobe another gentle peck before pulling back slightly, creating a small distance between us.
Lucien: Today, I've felt the significance of those seemingly meaningless moments from the past.
Lucien: It turns out there are many other people in my dreams.
His abrupt change of topic leaves me momentarily confused as if he’s speaking in riddles. It takes me a moment to catch up and understand what he’s talking about.
Memories of the beach from a month ago flood back. I look into those eyes that are still fixed on me, and I seem to see emotions in them that weren't there before.
Lucien: You're right. People are complex, and they're also greedy.
Lucien: Because of you, I've accepted many things, and as a result, I desire even more.
Lucien: I'm curious about what other changes I'll experience because of you, and what surprises you'll bring me.
Lucien: And besides curiosity, there's also expectation.
I tilt my head up and kiss the corner of his lips.
MC: Then keep being curious about me.
MC: I like that you're curious about me.
I reach out to touch Lucien's face, wanting to look more clearly into his eyes.
Lucien: Miss Magic Mirror, can you tell me…
Lucien: In your eyes, what am I like at this very moment?
I can't help but laugh.
MC: Right now, your eyes are the color of the entire sky. They're so beautiful.
MC: Your hair is bestowed with the warm glow of the setting sun, looking soft and fluffy. Your lips…
As I talk, I give him another kiss.
MC: It makes me want to do this.
Lucien also starts laughing.
MC: Lucien, right now, everything about you is complete in my eyes, and I can see you clearly.
He leans down again, his warm and moist breath brushing against my neck as he kisses me, causing subtle tingling sensations on my skin.
I instinctively try to pull away, but as I reach out to hold onto the back of his neck, he firmly holds me in place.
My legs dangle, unable to find a foothold, forcing me to use all my strength to hook onto his lap, while my other hand blindly grabs onto the curtain.
The crimson sunset spills over us unrestrainedly. As if dazzled by the spots of light, Lucien lifts me towards him, shifting a little as he holds me.
Amid the rocking motion, his leg accidentally touches the nearby coffee table, making a noise.
The sudden weightlessness makes me instinctively tighten my arms, causing him to gently bite my collarbone.
His scorching breath brushes against my neck like a feather, his scent overwhelming and filling every corner. It mingles with the fruity fragrance in the air, creating an even more alluring aroma.
Out of the corner of my eye, the goldfish in the fish bowl* seem startled as well, swaying and swinging, leaving behind two tangled and intertwined trails.
The skin grazed by my fingertips starts to burn, and I'm getting hot too.
Lucien: MC, you make me feel a gentle gaze.
Right now, we probably can't see each other's expressions, but it's as if we can see everything.
His low, hoarse voice resonates against my neck, and his moving lips make my throat vibrate, as though his words and voice have become my own.
Lucien: Make me feel truly seen by you, deeply loved by you**.
Lucien: Make me… feel happy and satisfied.
He traces a trail of delicate nibbles along my neck, kissing the path where life itself flows.
I feel those affectionate yet slightly demanding marks being etched again and again. For some reason, I find myself speaking without thinking.
MC: Bite me, Lucien.
The rustling of clothes suddenly stops, and his breathing also ceases, as if he is holding his breath.
I know my face is burning bright red, but I only shyly embrace him, moving myself even closer to him.
MC: I've also been seen by you and possessed by you.
In the sweaty air, I hear his long, drawn-out breath.
But in the next moment, they are all swept into my lips and tongue, obtaining all my oxygen in a different way.
Lucien: It is because you possess me that I am complete.
Lucien: Please keep possessing me forever… MC.
Lucien: In this world, only you will possess this kind of me.
*: The fish in the bowl description might seem out of place, but it's not! It alludes to '鱼水之欢' (lit. 'the joy of fish and water'), which is a Chinese idiom that describes the joy and intimacy of sexual intercourse or the metaphor for the act itself.
**: This is my favorite line in this because of the way it emphasizes Lucien's feeling of being understood and cherished 🤧 “看见" (kàn jiàn, to see) has the connotation of being acknowledged and truly understood.
Then the use of directly spoken “爱” (ài) which is a very, very sentimental word to say compared to how the west uses ‘love’ regularly…it also encompasses a sense of enduring love, a sense of care, cherishing, and protectiveness
Those last lines! Under her gaze, he feels utterly seen, completely known, and thus, entirely himself. She alone possesses all of him, while others only hold fragments.
Like the fox in The Little Prince says, “If you tame me, we shall need each other. To me, you will be unique in all the world." Through her 'taming,' this complete him becomes hers alone.
And as Lucien mentioned in the Radio Broadcast Date, his form of possessiveness goes beyond one-sided control or dominance. Rather than just possessing her, he longs even more for her to possess him.
Their possessiveness is a two-way thing: just as he is insatiable and wants all of her, he also craves to belong completely to the one he loves and to surrender himself entirely.