video credit: 一包洛氏薯片 in bilibili, thank you for letting me use the video to be subtitled!
[T/N: This date has a theme that is a kind of continuation to his car UR MQ, [On Fire MQ]; So please give it a read if you haven’t! you can click on the video link at right upper corner~]
[Just like the car UR MQ, the central theme of this story revolves around fully experiencing the world through your senses and his emotional growth-
I personally love this date because it's a kind of role reversal for them. In both the main story and the 'dateverse,' it was Lucien who had lost his senses to fully experience the world, and MC’s presence helped him regain them and learn how to immerse himself in it. In this date, the opposite happens—MC is the one who loses her senses, and Lucien helps her reawaken them.
Lucien sincerely wants to help her, he truly understands her struggle here because he used to go through the same thing (losing his ability to sense the world around him to some degree (something that’s confirmed on S2 ch 33) before meeting her,
-hence hindering his ability to fully experience the world around him. And as I mentioned in his car UR MQ analysis, emotions and senses are linked, so his limited sensory engagement with the world naturally made his emotional perception and expression rather dull (for a lack of better word)-
With MC he slowly regains his sensory and emotional connection with the world and learns to immerse himself in it. This date is the very proof of this ‘growth’!
Anyway- before I yap any further please enjoy the date~
Waiter: We used horseradish cheese sauce and basil pesto in this dish, resulting in sour and spicy flavors. Please enjoy the meal.
The waiter eloquently introduced us to the newly served exquisite dish. Lucien nods and takes a bite.
Lucien: Mm, the sour and spicy flavors make the ingredients themselves taste more refreshing. It's delicious.
Watching Lucien savor the dish so attentively, I also take a bite, my heart full of anticipation.
MC: Uhh…
MC: …ah…
Seeing my slight frown, the waiter immediately becomes a bit nervous.
Waiter: Madam, is there something you're not satisfied with about our dish? Please feel free to share your feedback…
MC: No, no, the flavor is quite good!
I wave my hand, signaling to the waiter that he doesn't need to continue attending to us. After he leaves, I turn to Lucien and let out a long sigh.
Lucien: How did your face turn so sour* while eating?
MC: Ugh, it's all because of my tongue…
Last week, the flu virus spread explosively through the company, and I unfortunately became one of its victims.
By the time I finally managed to break the fever and stop coughing, I discovered I had developed a bit of an "aftereffect."
My sense of taste... has undergone a subtle change.
MC: I can clearly tell that this dish is sour, and that dish is salty, but no matter what I eat, there's no lingering flavor…
MC: Lucien, I finally understand what 'taste like cardboard’ means!
I listlessly poke at the food in front of me with my fork as I speak. Seeing me like this, Lucien can’t resist chuckling.
Lucien: It’s indeed painful for our gourmet Miss MC not to be able to experience the deliciousness of the food.
MC: The pain doesn't stop there.
I can't help but start counting on my fingers, listing them one by one.
MC: You have no idea how expensive and hard to book this private kitchen is!
MC: I booked a month in advance, battling countless scalpers on their app, and finally managed to snag a VIP table for two.
MC: I specifically chose today to celebrate the end of your research project…
MC: Argh, and I was even planning to take you to try out this newly opened specialty cocktail bar after this meal!
Before I can finish my grumbling, Lucien suddenly takes hold of my fingertips.
Under the warm light, his smile is gentle and clear.
Lucien: So, are you regretting the money you spent, the loss of your taste, or the fact that our date isn't going as planned?
MC: You tell me.
I hook my finger around his, pouting justifiably*.
MC: Can the clever Professor Lucien help me think of a way to turn this "tasteless" date into something more "flavorful"?
Lucien tilts his head slightly, pondering seriously for a moment.
Lucien: Then let's change our date plans. After dinner, let's do something that doesn't require a sense of taste.
*: Lucien uses the word "苦瓜脸" (bitter melon face - kǔguā liǎn) to teasingly describe her facial expression LOL-
It is a Chinese idiom used to describe someone who looks unhappy or has a sour expression,
implying that her expression resembles the bitter, wrinkled appearance of a bitter melon!
**: The phrase used here is 理直气壮 (lǐ zhí qì zhuàng) which is a Chinese idiom that describes someone confident and assertive-
-often due to having a strong justification for their actions or words. MC feels wronged because the date doesn’t go as planned,
so she assertively challenges Lucien to ‘turn the tasteless date into something flavorful’ and feels justified to do so~
After leaving the private kitchen, I hand full control of the date over to Lucien with complete peace of mind.
We stroll along the riverside path, petting kittens at pet stores, gathering flowers still damp with evening dew, and finally arriving at a used bookstore.
MC: Lucien, is this the book you've been looking for?
Lucien: Where?
Lucien takes the old book from my hand and flips through a few pages, his eyes light up noticeably, and a surprised smile appears on the corner of his mouth.
Lucien: It really is this one... good thing you have a keen eye; If it were up to me, I'd have definitely missed it.
MC: Heh, I have a keen sense for anything related to you.
I proudly nuzzle against his arm and then lean my head against him.
The bouquet in my arms, the faint scent of ink mingling with the fragrance of Lucien's clothes, all lingered around my nose, drawing a contented sigh from me.
Lucien: What's wrong?
MC: It's nothing. I just suddenly realized that although my sense of taste wasn't indulged today, all my other senses have been thoroughly delighted thanks to your arrangements.
MC: I'm really happy, so I want to cuddle up to you for a bit.
Lucien lowers his head at my words, a hint of smile playing at the corner of his lips.
Lucien: I'm also very content and happy today, and I don't want to just ‘cuddle’ with you.
I understand the meaning behind his words and deliberately elongate the end of my tone.
MC: Ah, it's not really appropriate in a bookstore, is it~?
MC: I'm also feeling a bit tired now. Shall we head home?
Lucien: That's just what I was thinking.
I carry the flowers, and Lucien carries the old book as we head home together.
As soon as I push open the door, I notice a pile of delivery boxes stacked next to the shoe cabinet. Lucien also notices my gaze and starts to explain.
Lucien: They're all your packages.
Lucien: I happened to run into the delivery person on my way out, so I signed for them.
MC: Ah, I don't recall buying anything recently?
Lucien: Hmm… it seems MC was indeed a bit out of it from the fever a few days ago.
Lucien picks up the scissors to open packages, struggling to suppress the laughter in his voice.
Lucien: That night, weren't you a bit out of it from the fever, refusing to go to bed, and ended up watching a bunch of food livestreams?
Lucien: During that time, I heard a lot of ‘ding ding ding, payment successful’.
MC: —I remember now!
Heat rushes to my face in an instant, and I bury my face in my hands, feeling a little embarrassed.
MC: …As expected, it was a combination of cravings, impulsive shopping, and a viral invasion that left me with no rationality at all.
Lucien: I actually think it was a good thing that the food livestream distracted you that night, so you didn’t feel so uncomfortable.
Lucien helps me take the snack bags out of the box, then soothingly takes my hand and leads me to the sofa to sit down.
Lucien: Besides, I'm also curious to know if these snacks are as delicious as the live streamers described them to be.
Remembering the live streamers' over-the-top expressions, I also get curious and take the initiative to tear open a bag of sandwich cookies first.
I chew and swallow with the utmost seriousness, but I can still only taste bland saltiness and sweetness.
Seeing my increasingly dejected expression, Lucien is about to offer words of comfort, but I quickly stuff the other sandwich cookie from the bag into his mouth.
Lucien: Um…?
I prop myself up on a pillow, lean closer to Lucien, and wink at him.
MC: Hehe, I want to watch you eat it.
MC: If you think it's delicious, then that means I think it's delicious too.
Mirroring my gesture, Lucien winks back, his Adam's apple bobbing as he swallows the cookie.
Lucien: So, you want me to be your ’tongue’ then?
MC: Exactly, you describe it, and I'll imagine it; that's not a bad idea either.
MC: Maybe if I keep imagining and imagining, my sense of taste will return as well.
Lucien can't help but smile, his eyes curving with amusement. He leans down and places a kiss on the corner of my lips.
Lucien: I’ve noticed that a certain little foodie’s resentment towards not being able to enjoy delicious food has become as deep as a black hole.
MC: Haha, it's not that exaggerated…
Lucien: I completely understand how you feel, MC.
Lucien's sigh-like whisper overlaps with my words, swallowing my dry laughter entirely.
He doesn't say anything more, but I know he understands my current frustration and dejection.
I let out a long sigh, then bury my head in his chest affectionately, murmuring softly.
MC: I really want to get my sense of taste back soon…
Lucien: Then, how about we try making a plan to reawaken your taste buds?
MC: What?
Lucien: Taste buds are essentially signal receivers. When they malfunction, your brain also experiences cognitive errors, leading to a decreased sensitivity to taste.
Lucien: The tongue is most sensitive to sweetness first, then saltiness, followed by sourness, and finally bitterness.
MC: What about spiciness?
Lucien: Spiciness is actually a sensation of touch, not taste.
Lucien: How about we try this: starting tomorrow, you taste, and I describe. We can use synesthesia to try and awaken one flavor at a time?
MC: That might actually work. So, which flavor should we start with?
Lucien smiles, then unwraps a toffee candy, holds it between his teeth, and leans towards me.
Lucien: ....Sweetness.
Perhaps because I'm looking forward to Lucien's ‘taste buds awakening plan’, I wake up really early without needing an alarm.
I yawn as I drag myself into the bathroom and find that Lucien is also washing up.
Lucien: Good morning. Have you decided where we'll carry out our plan later?
MC: There seems to be a highly-rated dessert shop on Floral Road. My colleagues have recommended it before. Let's go check it out.
I squeeze out some toothpaste and start brushing my teeth, continuing to chat with Lucien with my words slightly muffled.
MC: By the way, I happn to fearch for popular science articles 'bout tafe recobery before going to bed, it said… Lucien! Lucien! (By the way, I happened to look up some science on taste recovery before going to sleep, it said… Lucien! Lucien!)
Startled by my voice, Lucien immediately lifts his head from the towel.
Lucien: Hmm? What's wrong?
MC: I think I can taste a bit of toothpaste!
At this moment, I realize with a mix of delayed comprehension and crystal-clear certainty—my sense of taste seems to be gradually returning!
Lucien is momentarily stunned, then he also breaks into a chuckle.
Lucien: That's great, it seems like this afternoon we should be able to… Mmm.
The rest of his words are cut off as I pounce on him, kissing him. He widens his eyes slightly in surprise, but almost instantly, he happily accepts my lead.
I grasp his arm, and with a sense of satisfaction, I lick my lips.
MC: Did you taste it?
Lucien: Mm, it's the taste of white tea and pomelo.
MC: Right, right! Although it's faint, I can finally distinguish some of them now!
MC: I almost don't want to rinse my mouth.
Lucien's smile deepens as he hands the glass of water to me.
Lucien: Well, this classmate still needs to rinse their mouth. Otherwise, how will you be able to taste the deliciousness that's yet to come?
Lucien: You look as nervous as if you're about to go to a job interview.
MC: Regaining my sense of taste is a big deal, of course I'm going to take it seriously!
I'm sitting up straight in the dessert shop, looking at Lucien with a serious expression on my face.
MC: On the other hand, does Professor Lucien have the confidence to be a good ‘tongue’ for me?
Lucien raises an eyebrow at me noncommittally, then picks up the menu.
Lucien: Hello, I'd like one macaron, one red velvet cake, one Basque cheesecake, one Napoleon pastry…
I watch Lucien expertly order a mountain of desserts, and I can't help but feel a little guilty.
MC: Wait a minute, can we really eat this much?
Lucien: No need to worry, if you can't finish them, just hand them over to me.
Lucien: Besides, you're still in the recovery phase of your sense of taste. Of course, you need to try as many different flavors of sweetness as possible in order to remember them well.
I nod in partial understanding. Soon, plate after plate of desserts are brought to our table.
Vibrantly colored jams, intricately patterned cream, and delicate little candies…
They are arranged across the table and dessert tower, resembling bright and vibrant gems under the afternoon sun.
Lucien picks up a cupcake and holds it near my lips.
Lucien: You first.
I take a bite of the cake, and the moist, soft texture instantly fills my mouth.
Lucien: How does it taste?
MC: Hmm... It seems like it's light cream with a tart fruit jam?
Lucien: You got most of it right.
MC: Then what's the remaining small part?
Lucien doesn't answer right away. He lightly trails his finger across the frosting on the cupcake.
The fluffy frosting rests on his finger like a tiny cloud. He lowers his eyes and sticks out his tongue, slowly and carefully licking it.
A small amount of the thick and sticky jam escapes the lingering sweep of his tongue, slowly slides down the skin of his knuckles.
Lucien's voice is neither hurried nor slow, each word enunciated with a hint of honeyed sweetness.
Lucien: The cream melts quickly, leaving a slightly fatty, sticky coating on the tip of the tongue, but this sensation is soon overtaken by the sweet and tart flavor of the jam.
Lucien: In the end, they blend together, creating a gentle and delicate flavor.
Even though I haven't taken a second bite of the cake, Lucien's description makes me involuntarily swallow.
That's the most fundamental desire—known as appetite.
I don't know why, but I'm suddenly thinking about that deep kiss from this morning.
Looking back, I definitely should have kissed him a few more times.
[T/N: Can confirm that MC kiss isn't just a peck on lips because the summary of the date phrase it like this: “顺便也尝了尝许墨嘴里牙膏的味道” (while at it I was also tasting the toothpaste in his mouth),
the text text uses "嘴里" (zui li), which literally means "inside the mouth”, and add the fact that she was not just ‘visiting’, but tasting…. the kiss was rather an… intimate exploration]
Lucien: Basque cake is very thick and sticky, not quite like the filling of an egg tart. You can slowly and gently stir it with the tip of your tongue to melt it…
Lucien: The Napoleon pastry from this particular shop is generously filled with almond slices. As they blend with the flaky pastry, you can slowly distinguish their textures and flavors…
MC: The puff pastry is crumbly and buttery, while the almond slices are smooth with a slight chewiness?
Lucien: Well said. Would you like to try the apple pie?
MC: I'd love to!
I take a bite of the apple pie he cut for me, chew carefully, and my eyes widen in surprise.
MC: I can taste it... this apple pie is a bit tastier than the one we had last time!
Lucien: It seems that classmate MC is starting to develop a standard for distinguishing similar flavors?
As Lucien speaks, he takes a bite of the apple pie and nods.
Lucien: Hmm... it does seem like it. I think the difference might be that they added a bit of liquor to the filling, which gives the apples a more fermented flavor. Can you smell it?
I lean closer, my nose twitching slightly. Sure enough, amidst the rich aroma of apples and cream, I catch a faint whiff of alcohol.
MC: There really is a hint of alcohol! How did I not taste it earlier?
Lucien: That means it's time for you to try the next dessert and awaken your taste buds further. Here, have a macaron.
We taste various desserts, and Lucien continuously describes the different textures and aftertastes to me, guiding me to gradually recover my sense of taste.
This ‘awakening plan’ seems to be doing more than just reawakening my sense of taste. It feels like all my other senses are being fully engaged and heightened by him as well.
As Lucien and I taste the same flavors, my eyes are filled with Lucien, my ears hear only his voice, my nose is enveloped by Lucien's lingering fragrance…
In my heart, there's only Lucien.
Lucien: What are you writing?
After returning home from the dessert shop, I excitedly open my computer and create a new document.
MC: Now that my sense of taste is back, I definitely need to rearrange the gourmet plans that I put on hold over the past couple of days.
MC: It's the first time I've truly felt how much having a sense of taste can enhance happiness!
MC: How about we go for a hot pot this weekend?
MC: It's also time to stimulate my tongue with some salty and spicy flavors!
MC: I know you said spiciness is a pain sensation, but hey, they are all handled by the tongue anyway…
Lucien leans back on the sofa, listening to my chatter, nodding with a warm smile beaming on his face.
Lucien: Only planning for next weekend? I was actually thinking about what we could eat together tomorrow.
MC: Of course, we should also plan for tomorrow! Let me see if there are any good places to eat nearby…
MC: Oh! There's this too!
I lean over and grab those bags of snacks from yesterday, the ones I couldn't taste when I ate them.
Rich cheese, tangy plums, savory dried meat... I savor each snack, one by one, and a feeling of immense happiness wells up in my heart.
MC: Sniffle sniffle… Lucien, those streamers weren't lying! It really is delicious, you should try some too!
I hold out the snacks to Lucien's lips like I did yesterday, but he doesn't open his mouth. Instead, he just looks at me and smiles.
MC: Why the smile? Do you think I'm being too greedy?
Lucien: Of course not. I just realized there was an idiom I didn't like before, but now I don't feel the same way about it anymore.
MC: Which idiom?
Lucien: "饮食男女" [yǐn shí nán nǚ - literally mean drink, eat, man, woman, it is derived from what Confucius once said, "饮食男女，人之大欲存焉 (Food and sex are the greatest/basic desires of humans) -T/N]
Lucien: Food and sex are the greatest desires of humans. These are the most basic and instinctual impulses of human beings, and there's nothing vulgar about them.
He reaches out and gently wipes the snack crumbs from the corner of my mouth.
Lucien: On the contrary, they're very endearing.
MC: Of course, being able to experience and engage the world through one's nature is a very endearing thing.
MC: And haven't you noticed that your perception of the world is becoming increasingly nuanced, vibrant, and lively?
Lucien: Are you referring to our 'taste bud awakening plan' today?
MC: Far more than that. It's also the text messages you sent me, the photos you took and gave to me, and all our trivial little chats;
MC: We're experiencing the beauty in all the small, ordinary things together. Even if it’s merely a tiny change like adding a bit of alcohol to the apple pie…
I gently nuzzle my cheek against his fingers, which he hasn't yet withdrawn, smiling with contentment and pride.
MC: It's because I'm endearing that you're becoming endearing too.
MC: We're endearing people who enjoy the basic desires of humankind.
Lucien: ….
Lucien is momentarily stunned, then his narrow eyes suddenly lit up at my words.
His lips open and close, but in the end, no words come out. He just leans toward me slowly.
The atmosphere becomes somewhat suggestive. I realize what he's about to do and quickly cover my mouth, leaning back.
MC: Wait... Not now!
Lucien: Why?
MC: I just ate jerky, dried fruits, and cookies, now my mouth tastes like a mess.... So, not now!
I twist my waist, trying to dodge him. Lucien, resigned yet amused, can only straighten back up.
Lucien: I'll brew you some plain tea then.
Lucien finishes brewing the tea and hands it to me. I accept it a bit awkwardly and sip slowly, regret starting to creep into my heart.
Why am I even bringing up rinsing my mouth? When I was brushing my teeth this morning, wasn't it natural to just pounce and kiss him directly?
Besides, Lucien wouldn't mind if it's me…
Now it's like this, my mouth doesn't taste bad anymore, but kissing has become this serious and stiff affair, like some kind of formal ceremony.
MC: I really…
Lucien: What?
MC: It's nothing, it's nothing. I meant... I finished my drink.
I pull Lucien's arm, then, feeling a bit uncertain, lower my head to huff a breath.
MC: It should be fresh now, right...?
MC: Lucien, why do I feel like I'm starting to doubt my sense of smell again?
Lucien: No need to doubt.
Lucien cups my face in his hands, and his scent, like that of green tea, envelops me completely.
In the moment of our intertwined breaths, Lucien personally confirms the answer.
Lucien: Very sweet.
Fun fact: Lucien ends up having a lingering pain between his teeth after this date HAHA. Oh the length he would go for his love......