Pitter-patter…
Outside, the drizzling sound of rain weaves the most perfect white noise, turning the rustling of book pages and the clicking of a mouse indoors into something no longer dull and monotonous.
Such a lazy moment is just right for leisurely passing time at home, soaking in the aroma of coffee together with Lucien.
MC: Pfft…
Lucien: Did you see something funny? What’s got you laughing so much?
Hearing my voice, Lucien lifts his head curiously from the other side of the sofa.
I beckon with a smile, tugging his sleeve as I bring him over to my computer.
MC: Take a look at my new desktop pet companion~
On the computer desktop, a little bunny hops around in response to my mouse clicks.
MC: Look, her name is Nobi. Once the system's set up, she chats with me whenever I poke her.
As I speak, I poke her twice. The little bunny blinks, and with a pop, a dialogue box jumps out above her head.
Nobi: "Want to ask the world’s cutest Nobi Rabbit something?"
Nobi: "Feeling wronged? Listen to me, it’s better to trouble others than to wrong yourself!"
MC: Haha, isn’t it funny?
Lucien: Mm, she’s certainly a little bunny even livelier than MC.
Lucien’s gaze falls on the Nobi pin on my collar.
Lucien: Speaking of which, you really have bought a lot of Nobi Rabbit merchandise lately… Do you like her a lot?
MC: Of course I do! But this is only one of the reasons; the more important reason is this!
With a cheerful lilt in my voice, I click open a video.
MC: Behold—"The Bunny Arrives!"
In the video, an excited couple waves at the camera, and perched on their shoulders is none other than... Nobi Rabbit!
With his index finger hooked under his chin, Lucien watches the interaction between Nobi and the couple in the video thoughtfully and slightly raises an eyebrow.
Lucien: [chuckles] ...Is it real?
MC: Hum hum, of course it's real.
MC: Lately, for some unknown reason, the real Nobi Rabbit has been appearing in Loveland City!
MC: Now there’s already a wave of 'Nobi craze'. Everyone’s trying all kinds of ways to get her to appear by their side and play with her.
Lucien: So, all the new merchandise added at home over the past few days, including that 'magical' cuddle claw machine, is meant to make Nobi show up faster?
MC: Sort of. Gotta make an effort to raise the chance of being the lucky one, right...
Before I can finish my sentence, Lucien gently pinches my cheek.
Lucien: I think my little one is already very lucky.
Lucien: And you always share your luck with me so generously.
Lucien: Whether it’s the RV trip, the island holiday… even a strand of blessing bracelets, or a fortune cookie.
Lucien: You haven’t forgotten all of that, have you? Because then I would be heartbroken.
Lucien’s voice is low and soft, as if coquettishly coaxing me, yet the tail end of his tone carries a firmness that leaves no room for doubt.
Accompanied by his words, memories of those sweet and happy moments from the past surface in my mind.
All those big and small moments of luck that had Lucien in them.
A smile rises on my face without me realizing it, and I lean against his shoulder.
MC: Gee~ When you put it like that, I feel embarrassed.
MC: It makes me seem like someone who’s already so lucky, yet still greedily wants more.
Lucien: But your expression doesn't look 'embarrassed' at all.
MC: Hm? Then what kind of expression do I have?
Just as I lift my face, a soft kiss lands at the corner of my lips.
Lucien: It’s a righteously bold, greedy expression, one that says you want to become the luckiest person in the world.
I burst out laughing and reach out to hook my arm around Lucien’s neck.
MC: Then, is it okay if I want to be a little greedier?
Lucien: Sure. What do you want?
MC: Of course, it is…
I gently press down on his neck with my wrist, letting his breath blend once again with mine.
MC: Lucien also has to become the luckiest person in the world together with me.
Lucien: All right... how soon can you get here?
Lucien: Please hurry as fast as possible, over here....
Through the slightly ajar door, Lucien’s voice sounds fuzzy and distant, as if mingled with the drip-drop of water.
Is it still raining? I frown, opening my eyes from the lingering daze of sleep, only to see a bright, cloudless sky outside the window.
MC: Then the water sound just now was....
Just as I’m puzzling over it, Lucien happens to push open the door. His eyes pause for a beat.
Lucien: Did I wake you?
MC: No… were you on the phone just now?
Lucien: Yes, there’s a bit of an issue with the drainage pipe on the balcony at home. I just contacted property management.
MC: Huh?!
Drip, drip...
Gazing at the dripping mess strewn across the balcony, I feel as if my mood has also been soaked through by the muddy water.
MC: How could this happen...
MC: Just yesterday I said we have to become the luckiest people, and we already ran into something this unlucky today, sigh.
Hearing my sigh, Lucien gently rubs my head.
Lucien: Look on the bright side, at least it was discovered early. Otherwise, our living room floor would've been ruined too.
MC: That's true. Luckily, it’s not like what happened to me last time…
I trail off mid-sentence and turn to look at Lucien. A knowing smile lifts the corners of his mouth.
Lucien: Yeah. Now we've both experienced ‘The flooded Jinshan’.
[T/N: They were talking about what happened during the 2020 Valentine’s Day date (the one with cherry cg), when MC’s apartment got flooded and she ended up spending the night at Lucien’s place."The Flooded Jinshan" (水漫金山) alludes to a legendary scene from The Legend of the White Snake in which the White Snake floods Jinshan Temple to rescue her husband, Xu Xian. This phrase is often used to refer unfortunate occurrence of flooding]
His gentle, joking tone melts away my gloom. I let out a sigh of relief and simply take his hand.
MC: Then, in the spirit of 'courtesy demands reciprocity', how about coming over to my place as a guest while we wait for the property maintenance, Professor Xu?
A bright gleam flashes in Lucien’s eyes. He gently squeezes my palm, his eyes curving into a smile.
Lucien: Alright, I’ll trouble Miss Producer to take me in.
As I begin excitedly planning how to properly host Lucien, I open my door—
Suddenly, I feel something bump against my calf, and a crisp, chirpy voice chimes out from near my feet.
??: Wow, your place is pretty big!
I glance down. To my surprise, a Nobi rabbit has already bounced ahead of me into my home!
MC: ?!
My eyes widen as I stare in disbelief. Hearing my gasp, Nobi comes to a stop and lifts her chin at me.
Nobi: Don’t you chat with me on your computer every day? How come you don't recognize me?
MC: Of course I recognize you! Y-you're really Nobi?
Nobi: Hmph! Who else in the whole world could possibly be this adorable besides me?
Nobi: You two shouldn't just stand at the doorway. Come on in.
After finishing her sentence, Nobi plops down onto my couch without a care in the world.
Lucien watches the little bunny rolling around before him, letting a rare flicker of subtle expression surface on his face
Yet before I can confirm it, he has already returned to his usual composed demeanor, giving me a helpless smile.
Lucien: Looks like there’s a new guest besides me today.
With that, he takes my hand and leads me over to Nobi.
Lucien: Hello, Nobi Rabbit.
Lucien: Can you tell me where you came from?
Nobi: Um? I came from the cutest planet in the entire universe.
Lucien: Then, by what means did you arrive here? Was it through spatial teleportation or energy conversion?
Lucien’s gaze is filled with genuine curiosity and thirst for knowledge. Nobi puffs up her cheeks, seemingly a bit overwhelmed.
Nobi: W-why do you humans like to ask strange questions?
She firmly plants her hands on her hips and shakes her ears.
Nobi: Anyway, the reason I appeared here is 'love'!
Nobi: As long as there’s love, anything can be explained. That’s just how this world is!
Because of Nobi’s righteously confident statement, the air goes quiet for a moment, then Lucien and I can’t help but chuckle at her answer.
Lucien: Alright, that question just now really was a bit much for a little bunny.
Lucien: After all, the world truly does become simpler because of love.
Our eyes meet, and in silent unison, tender, indulgent smiles bloom on our faces. I scoot closer to Nobi’s side and give her a light poke.
MC: Oh~ so does that mean it was the power of love between Lucien and me that drew you to appear here?
Nobi: Yes, yes, exactly!
Nobi: Professor Xu, you should learn from your girlfriend. She's much smarter and cuter than you!
Lucien: ….
Nobi and I tease in tandem, making him lift his brow slightly. He then bows down just a bit, as if earnestly seeking guidance.
Lucien: Then, may I ask my two teachers what I can do to become as smart and as cute as my girlfriend?
As if reclaiming her dignity, Nobi adjusts her glasses and nods with satisfaction.
Nobi: That’s the very reason I came to you two~
As she speaks, Nobi suddenly hops onto Lucien’s shoulder, leans in close to his ear, and whispers something softly.
Lucien: [gasps softly] ...Really?
Nobi: Just try it and you'll see.
Lucien nods thoughtfully, then leans down toward me.
Watching his face draw closer and closer, my heartbeat begins to race beyond my control.
Yet Lucien merely extends his hand, guiding mine to his face, then slowly moving it upward.
My fingertips glide from the warmth of his cheek, tangle through the fine strands of his hair, and finally come to rest on the fluffy crown of his head.
The tactile sensations are magnified infinitely under his guidance, just like his innocent eyes that now occupy my whole vision.
Lucien: …Am I cute?
I blurt out almost reflexively:
MC: —So cute!!
Just as I’m still basking in the lingering thrill of his adorable assault, Lucien’s phone begins to ring.
Seeing that it's a call from property management, I pout my lips, can't help but nuzzle once more against Lucien’s fluffy hair, and only then do I longingly send him out the door.
Taking advantage of the moment while Lucien deals with property management, I quietly move closer to Nobi and ask in a whisper.
MC: Nobi, do you have mind-reading powers? How do you know that I... am so susceptible to Lucien's tricks?
Nobi: Hm? Didn’t you tell me all that yourself?
Nobi hops onto my lap, her big eyes behind the lenses blinking at me.
Nobi: You said the person you like most is Professor Xu, and that you have endless things to say to him every single day.
Nobi: Although others see him as a serious and proper genius professor, you think the more a man is like that, the more suitable he is for...
MC: Aaaah! STOP! Stop! I get it! Don’t go on!
I didn’t expect that the real-life Nobi would actually remember everything from her time as a desktop pet!
The moment I remember whispering all those unfiltered secrets to the little desktop pet, my face burns hot in an instant.
I quickly change the subject to stop her from rambling on.
MC: Th-then how did you make Lucien willing to do this?
Nobi: Hahaha, it’s a secret spell I whispered to him.
Nobi smugly shakes her ears and shoots me a triumphant glance.
Nobi: Anyway, today he’s definitely going to fulfill all your demands.
All of my demands.
Those four words brush across the bottom of my heart like tiny feathers, leaving a faint, ticklish sensation.
Just as I'm about to ask something else, the door suddenly opens, and Lucien shuffles in, holding a delivery box in his arms.
A little surprised, I hurry over to lend him a hand.
MC: So fast? Is the pipe already fixed?
He shakes his head and lets out a troubled sigh.
Lucien: The repairs can't be done today. The maintenance worker said it's a bit complicated and will probably need to inspect it together with the unit upstairs tomorrow.
Lucien: Oh, and this is the package that was at your door.
I freeze for a moment before I can fully process the meaning behind those two sentences.
MC: So... you're staying at my place today?
Lucien: Can't I?
I'm just about to nod along with what he says when Nobi's words just now sweep through my mind again, and my gaze involuntarily drifts to the delivery box in his hands.
Of course, I know what's inside the delivery box. If all these things could appear on Lucien...
I blink, and then a huge smile spreads across my face.
MC: Of course you can! But you need to be good and do as I say, abide by the principle 'guest adapts to host’s arrangements'.
I take the delivery box from his hands and tear it open, then pull out a set of soft, plush pajamas with adorable bunny ears... Nobi Rabbit-themed sleepwear!
Wiggling the pajamas at Lucien, I smile at him with eyes curved like crescent moons.
MC: If you’re staying at my home, then you’ve got to wear the pajamas from my place~
Lucien casts a glance at that fluffy set and smiles faintly.
Lucien: Whatever your arrangements, I am at your command.
It’s not often that the weather is this sunny and clear, so I pull Lucien along, bring out the lounge chair and tea table, and get ready to comfortably enjoy a ‘stay-at-home sunbath’.
I enthusiastically lay out the cushions and arrange the drinks and snacks, but then discover there’s still a pillow missing from the rattan chair.
MC: Ah, I almost forgot!
I rise to my feet, clap my hands, then turn with a smile to tell Lucien and Nobi, "Wait here for a bit!"—before briskly darting back to the bedroom to fetch the pillow.
MC: Anyway, there's still one day off tomorrow. How about taking Nobi out for some fun with Lucien?
MC: Where to go though... that newly opened ball pit park sounds like a good idea...
As I mull it over, I pick up the pillow and walk out of the bedroom.
A richly scented summer breeze flutters through the balcony curtains, and the first thing that meets my eyes is a pair of fluffy, gently swaying—
—bunny ears.
Lucien wears the bunny pajamas, surrounded by a circle of Nobi merchandise and greenery, even the air is infused with a noisy warmth.
Yet amid all the blooming abundance, the rowdiest of all is still Nobi Rabbit, spinning noisily around Lucien.
Everything under the sunshine softens my heart. I lighten my footsteps, quietly pulling out my phone to capture this scene.
Nobi: So then, why do you think this is the cutest thing about MC?
...Are they talking about me? I instantly perk up my ears as I try to eavesdrop on Lucien’s answer.
With his back to me in the camera frame, Lucien lets out a deliberately profound "Hmm."
Lucien: For that, I should likely begin with the activity levels of dopamine neurons in the medial prefrontal cortex.
Lucien: When I make eye contact or talk with her, there are significant fluctuations in the secretion of oxytocin and serotonin.
Lucien: This kind of neurochemical reaction forms memories through the hippocampus, gradually establishing a conditioned reflex in my subconscious where "MC = cute"....
Nobi: Ack!
Nobi lets out a cry and clutches her head as if she's dizzy, plopping down onto the pillow with a wobbly flop.
Nobi: You're truly way too un-cute!
MC: Pffft-HAHAHA!
Unable to hold back, I finally burst out laughing. Lucien turns his head at the sound.
The bunny ears tremble in the breeze, and the soft, plush material makes him look several times softer and gentler than usual.
Beneath the purple bow, his long, narrow eyes brim with helplessness, yet the smile at the corner of his lips is full of sly mischief.
Hmph, he doesn’t look like a bunny at all. He’s clearly a little fox in bunny’s clothing.
I can’t help but reach out and pinch his 'bunny ears'.
Lucien doesn’t dodge my 'troublemaking'. Instead, he squints his eyes, leans in, and nuzzles against my palm.
Lucien: What should I do, Teacher MC? I’ve been called un-cute again.
MC: Well then, Little Student Lulu needs to study hard and follow Nobi’s and my guidance
Lucien: Little Student Lulu? [chuckles] Is that nickname also part of becoming cute?
MC: That's right, and also...
I excitedly take out one little accessory after another from the delivery box and clip them onto Lucien’s hair.
While I’m at it, I open my phone's camera and select the most over-the-top, cutesy filter.
Seeing Lucien turn into a 'big-eyed moe boy' on screen, a wave of mischievous pride wells up in my heart.
MC: Mmhmm, this Little Student Lulu is definitely cute!
Lucien: …..
Lucien reaches up to touch the newly added pink hair accessory on his head, then raises an eyebrow in understanding.
Lucien: I see. I’ve learned it now.
Lucien: As a good student, I'll naturally follow the teacher's guidance. But as a good teacher, shouldn't MC also lead by example?
MC: Lead by example how?
Lucien: For example...
Lucien leans in and sweeps me into his arms in one smooth, irresistible motion.
The delicate fragrance of gardenias still lingers in his sleeves. A scent that belongs to Lucien alone.
Then he takes my phone with one hand, and with the other, he plucks the spare hair accessories from my grasp, mimicking me as he clips them into my hair.
Looking at the two of us on screen, wearing the same hair clips and surrounded by pink bubbles and flowers, it feels as if bubbles and blossoms are rising and blooming in my heart too.
Lucien’s satisfied chuckle sounds softly by my ear.
Lucien: So next, how should I face the camera in a 'cute' way? Little Teacher MC, can you teach me?
With Nobi’s guidance, we not only play lots of fun little games but also boldly try filming all sorts of childish little videos.
Just as Nobi promised at the beginning, Lucien always indulges and goes along with my antics.
As night gradually descends, Nobi suddenly jumps onto the center of the coffee table and solemnly adjusts her round glasses.
Nobi: Alright, my dear students, I’m leaving now.
MC: So sudden? I was hoping to go to the ball pit park with you tomorrow!
Hearing my plea to stay, Nobi’s figure wavers slightly, her expression clearly falters, but she quickly pretends to be serious and shakes her ears.
Nobi: It’s no surprise you can’t bear to see me go. After all, I’m everyone's favorite little bunny!
Nobi: But as the universe’s cutest Nobi Rabbit, I must keep helping more people become even more adorable!
After saying that, Nobi immediately pounces into my arms, affectionately rubbing against my cheek. She then hops onto Lucien's shoulder, cups his cheek, and rubs against it too.
Lucien and I look at each other and smile, then tacitly reach out to gently rub her fluffy cheeks.
MC: Thank youuu, Teacher Nobi~
Lucien: I will also remember your teachings. I promise I’ll continue becoming cuter from now on.
After a round of ‘cuddly’ goodbyes, Nobi finally darts over to the windowsill and waves her tiny paw at us.
Nobi: Bye-bye the cutest couple in Loveland City second only to me!
Only after watching Nobi disappear into the night do I reluctantly withdraw my gaze and turn to look at the room filled with Nobi merchandise.
MC: It’s getting late. Shall we tidy up the balcony together?
Lucien says "Mm" in response. He picks up the pillow from the lounge chair and suddenly speaks.
Lucien: Have you told Nobi a lot about me?
MC: Huh? How did you know?
Lucien: From what I observed today, there was a certain tacit understanding between you and her in your 'guidance' toward me.
MC: ….!
My face turns red all at once, and I stammer as I wave my hand.
MC: Uh, I just chatted with her about some girl talk, that’s all.
Lucien props his chin on a pillow, a faintly mischievous tone lacing his voice.
Lucien: So you have told her a lot of secrets about me. Sigh... Looks like I’m no longer your first choice for sharing secrets.
MC: That's not true at all!
I hastily deny it, yet have no idea how to explain.
MC: It’s just… uh…
MC: Sometimes people fantasize about things that are unlikely to happen. But normally, who would have the nerve to actually ask the other person to do such things?
MC: I’m just casually chatting with Nobi…
Lucien takes a step forward, drawing out his ending tone as the smile at the corners of his mouth deepens.
Lucien: So today, you had me wear a bunny onesie, act cute to you, play childish games, and film adorable videos...
Lucien: Were all these lessons your 'fantasies coming true', MC?
As he lists off today's antics one by one, my face grows even hotter, nearly overwhelmed with guilt for my unrestrained indulgence.
Lucien gently pinches my flushed cheek.
Lucien: Silly, there's no need to feel embarrassed. I genuinely like this feeling of ‘psychological regression’ today.
MC: Psychological regression?
Lucien: When someone is in a highly trusting and secure relationship, the brain subconsciously chooses to return to a relatively simpler and more relaxed state.
Lucien: It’s similar to the carefree feeling during childhood.
Lucien: Sometimes, being in a state of regression actually helps us express our needs and authentic inner thoughts more clearly.
I blink and take the pillow Lucien hands to me.
MC: So… do you also have moments when you really want to see that side of the other person, but feel too embarrassed to say it because it seems childish?
Lucien pauses at my words, as if he earnestly thinks it over for a moment before smiling and nodding.
Lucien: You mean willful thoughts like yours? Yeah, I do have those.
MC: Eh? Like what?
Lucien smiles without answering and simply reaches out to gently take hold of my wrist.
In the next second, the world spins before my eyes, and the ground beneath me suddenly softens—
Swirling colorful lights fill my vision as my whole body unexpectedly sinks into an ocean of pillowy soft balls!
I look up in surprise at Lucien, who’s fallen into the ball pit alongside me, and he gives me an innocent smile.
Lucien: When I heard those childish requests of yours, I was indeed a bit surprised.
MC: Are you surprised at my childishness?
Lucien: No. Surprised that I hadn’t done enough, that I should’ve enabled my little lady to 'regress' by my side without holding anything back… much, much earlier.
He shifts his posture slightly, letting himself sink even deeper into the soft sea of plastic orbs.
Colorful spheres tumble around us with a soft rumble as his gaze settles tenderly on my face.
Lucien: Letting myself be childish with you to our hearts' content like this... I really like it.
His voice whispers softly in my ear. It becomes the warmest comfort, filling my heart with a feather-light happiness.
MC: So, what exactly did Nobi teach you that made you so willing to grant my every wish today?
Lucien: Actually, it's only two words.
I blink, looking at him in confusion, while Lucien nods seriously and pulls my hand onto his soft, fluffy hair.
Lucien: Tactile feel.
MC: Tactile feel?
His voice is soft, like a light feather falling into my heart.
Lucien: Nobi says that as long as you let your hand touch something soft, your heart will grow just as soft, too.
His hair is delicate, soft, and fluffy. The warm sensation travels through my palm, and just like he said, my heart softly melts all at once.
MC: I do admit, Professor Xu feels especially good to the touch today.
Lucien: Is it just the way I feel that’s good?
Lucien: I still want to hear you affirm my cuteness a little more.
My heartbeat is stirred by his words and tender gaze. Without a second thought, I lean in and kiss him.
MC: Everything about Lucien is incredibly cute
In his embrace, my eyes crinkle into a smile. My fingers twirl strands of his hair round and round, and my heart, too, grows soft like a floating bubble.
MC: By the way, what about me?
MC: What do you think is the cutest thing about me? You’re not allowed to fool me with scientific reasoning like you did with Nobi earlier!
MC: You have to say it one by one. Be specific.
Lucien is slightly taken aback upon hearing this, then gives a helpless smile. His hands tenderly cradle my cheeks, his warm fingertips slowly tracing along my features.
His fingers glide over the space between my brows, then gently rub my earlobe.
Lucien: If… I had to choose the cutest part of you, then it would probably be your brows and eyes, your cheeks, the tip of your nose...
His voice flows as softly as the night. With every word he speaks, a gentle yet solemn kiss falls upon my face.
Moved by his earnest, tenderly lingering gesture, I can’t help but wrap my arms around his neck.
MC: Oh~ Then which one is the cutest of all?
Lucien: It's here.
He pulls back slightly, gazing at me with a tender and wholly focused gaze.
Lucien: The cutest of all… is your eyes that are forever overflowing with love.
I'm just going to drop the translation of the moments here. This guy is too cute lol~ Also, there's one phone call [Couple Desktop Pets] from this card that I want to share after this.
Lucien: It’s rare for you to call me right while you're at work. Is there something up?
MC: Ahem, Lucien, are you free to help me record a few lines right now?
Lucien: Hm? I guess I'm free... Is this for your new show production?
MC: No, it's not that. Nobi has just released a limited-edition Children's Day desktop pet.
MC: Not only can you customize desktop pets with couple avatars, but you can also record voice lines!
Lucien: I see. So, what kind of lines would you like me to record?
MC: Just some simple ones like "Hello~", "Goodbye", or "Do your best today too" and such.
MC: That way, I’ll have a mini Lucien watching over me while I work~
Lucien: So that’s what Miss Producer was planning all along.
MC: Hehe, so… would you be willing to play along?
Lucien: Of course I’m willing. But since it’s a couple-edition desktop pet… shouldn’t I have a "Mini Producer" on my desktop as well?
MC: Eh? You want to keep a mini version of me too?
Lucien: Can't I?
MC: I mean, you can...... but how are you planning to design my desktop pet avatar?
Lucien: For example, endlessly curious, enjoys experiencing all kinds of life’s little joys, and always brings me small, delightful surprises...
Lucien: And when she eats something delicious, she gives a silly little smile, and when she’s asleep, she instinctively burrows into my chest...
MC: W-wait a second. Lucien, isn’t your impression of me a little too specific?
Lucien: Is it? I haven’t even mentioned the more specific and cuter details yet.
MC: Ahem... Okay, let’s not talk about that for now. So, do you have any lines you'd like me to record for your desktop pet?
Lucien: I only need you to record one sentence.
MC: Which sentence?
Lucien: Just the simplest words—meant just for me—
Lucien:"Love you."