MC: I've arrived at Basement Level 2.
In the darkness, the scent of decay spreads around. I struggle to carry the lantern down the stairs and cautiously press the black box in my hand.
It's as if there's an invisible flame in the air, making it hard for me to breathe. My skin also feels a faint burning pain.
??(Lucien): [talking through the transmitter] It took 36 minutes longer than expected. How is your physical condition now?
MC: A bit hot and stuffy... my whole body still feels a bit sore.
??(Lucien): Is the pain severe?
MC: It's okay. I can still bear it.
I enunciate each word slowly. After a moment of silence, I hear the other person speak again.
??(Lucien): Then let's continue.
??(Lucien): In front of you is a corridor. The path should be relatively smooth.
??(Lucien): Follow the stairs to the left and try to see if you can open the third room. There should be a cabinet inside.
Per his instructions, I successfully feel my way to the room he mentioned and even luckily push the door open directly.
As I enter the room, I am greeted by a wave of dust that has been undisturbed for a long time. Torn and tattered papers lie scattered across the floor, their contents illegible.
I brush away the moldy air in front of me; the room is even larger than I imagined, and after feeling around for a long time, I finally see a huge cabinet.
The rusty cabinet door is already a bit twisted. When I finally pry it open, I find neatly stacked thick notebooks.
I curiously pull out a book. The pages are already yellowed, but the text remains clear.
MC: In 1973... the 19th experimental report on the 'Simulation of Radiation from the 1917 Comet'...
MC: In 1995... the 42nd experimental report on the 'Evol Energy Core'...
Various complex numbers and figures are recorded sequentially according to time. I browse through them blankly, completely unable to understand what they mean.
??(Lucien): Is this lady encountering some trouble?
MC: Not really. However, this cabinet is more extensive than I imagined, and there is a lot of information inside.
MC: It feels like I can't take everything out at once.
??(Lucien): It's okay. Each booklet should have a numerical label. Let's start with the important ones first.
As he speaks, he reports a few numbers.
MC: ...1974, 1981, 1995... Alright, I've got them all.
MC: By the way, I just found many tables in the room I passed by.
MC: There are lots and lots of pressable and rotatable... buttons? There are also some mysterious shapes on the wall that I can't quite understand.
MC: Do you know what they are?
The person opposite the black box also seems stunned and falls silent.
??(Lucien): Is that table slightly curved, and are the structures on the wall mainly dot-shaped and block-shaped?
MC: That's right!
??(Lucien): [chuckles then sighs] I didn't expect... such things would still be left behind.
He seems to smile as he lets out a long sigh, with a particular indescribable itch to try.
??(Lucien): Today's gains have completely exceeded expectations. Thank you for your hard work. Let's get ready to return.
I walk alone through the ruins corroded by decay.
I thought I had long been accustomed to facing the scent of death, but when I see a familiar yet blurry figure in the desolation, my steps involuntarily quicken.
As the sharp alarm sounds, his figure becomes increasingly clear.
I stand still from a distance, looking back at that smile-filled gaze.
MC: [happily] Lucien, why are you here again! Didn't I tell you to wait for me in the safe house?
Lucien: I wanted to go for a walk, but as I walked farther, I felt a bit scared being alone. It would be more reassuring to have someone accompany me.
Lucien: I'm very happy to have waited for you.
I know this is just his excuse, but I am equally happy not to expose him.
I skillfully put on the isolation*** suit Lucien specially made for me not far away and walked up to him.
MC: A certain someone really pushes their luck, making one person do multiple tasks. Not only do I have to help with research, but I also have to run errands.
Lucien: They are indeed pushing their luck, so I suggest you ask for more compensation from him.
MC: [smiles softly] Then I will make him help me deal with all kinds of troubles.
Lucien: I think... he would be more than willing to do such things.
As we chat casually and leisurely, the safe house appears before us.
I habitually walk into the house, descend the stairs, pass through layers of iron doors, and remove my isolation suit in front of the last iron door.
As the door closes, a dazzling light suddenly pierces through the darkness.
I fall into a momentary daze, vaguely hearing distant and cold voices.
??(Not Lucien, distant voice from the past): "Increase the dosage... the data is showing significant fluctuations…"
A sense of phantom pain surges through my entire body as if a black tide is rolling in.
Lucien: MC.
Lucien's voice comes through the speaker.
Lucien: Our experiment No. 0625 is about to start. Are you ready?
I take a deep breath and lift my head with a determined gaze.
MC: I'm ready.
Today's experiment doesn't seem to yield any results.
I secretly observed his calm face and silently drew a conclusion in my mind.
Upon careful reflection, I realize that in the past six months, I have hardly ever seen any signs of frustration on Lucien's face, nor has he ever caused me as much pain as those madmen from the past.
Therefore, although I cannot fully trust researchers like him, I can still achieve long-term cooperation with him.
Lucien quickly organizes today's data and then opens another set of records and a map.
Lucien: Yesterday's radiation tide has intensified the radiation in Zone X. The personnel in these areas need to be relocated soon.
MC: [worriedly] ...The heavily contaminated radiation zone is getting larger and larger. Will the entire Zone X eventually be…
Lucien: There is such a trend, but the changes in the world always exceed our imagination.
Lucien: Many areas in Zone X are still only mildly contaminated, so there's no need to be too pessimistic yet.
Facing my worries, he gives a reassuring smile.
Lucien: However, time is indeed running a bit tight.
MC: [worriedly] Do you want to move to a safer place first?
Lucien: My research on the books and materials in this building is not yet finished, and the equipment and samples are also here.
MC: ...Are these things more important than human beings?
Lucien doesn't answer me. He just smiles, puts on the protective gear, and picks up the organized boxes.
Lucien: Let's go. Let's take a look at the city.
The city's ruins have been eroded by rain, snow, and frost, leaving only moss and weeds freely spreading throughout.
The world wears down this desolate land in different ways, but it has never listened to everyone's prayers and pleas.
Lucien and I skillfully turn into an alley, pass through an almost completely unshielded door, and see a weak middle-aged man inside the dilapidated house.
Lucien: How are you doing today?
Middle-aged man: ...Doctor, you're here... my whole body still hurts... but I feel much better…
Lucien: Don't worry, that's the normal effect of the medication. You'll feel more comfortable tomorrow.
As Lucien speaks, he injects medication into the middle-aged man's arm and hands him a packet of medicine.
Lucien: Just like I told you before, once a day.
Middle-aged Man: Alright... Thank you very much…
Lucien develops all those medications himself. I don't know how he manages to create these in such a ruined world, but he somehow does.
It's as enigmatic as 'radiation'.
No one knew what it was before; everyone only knew that approaching certain places would cause inexplicable pain and death.
Some called it a 'curse', some called it a 'colorless beast', and others said such places were 'God's slaughterhouse'.
Even though I had been with it for many years, no one ever told me what it really was.
I will always remember when I saw Lucien again after we had agreed to work together; he took out a notebook and started drawing for me.
Lucien: It is called 'radiation.' It is the form of energy that moves as waves or subatomic particles, radiating outward in straight lines from the radiation source in all directions.
Lucien: Based on its energy level and ability to ionize substances, we generally classify it as 'ionizing radiation' and 'non-ionizing radiation.'
MC: ...I don't understand. Why does it make people die?
Lucien: You can temporarily imagine it as countless bullets, too small for you to see, being shot at you.
Lucien: They break everything inside your body, preventing your blood from regenerating and your heart from continuing to beat.
Lucien told me that this is 'knowledge'.
MC: If I still want to ask 'why', is that also an effect of 'radiation'?
His smile deepened, and in those deep, mysterious eyes, I seemed to see countless emotions that I couldn't understand.
Lucien: This is 'curiosity'.
Lucien: It has nothing to do with 'radiation'. It belongs only to you and is the first step towards the world and yourself.
After noting down some things, Lucien takes me to meet many people.
They are either weak or healthy; some undergo drastic changes overnight, while others are lucky enough to regain their vitality.
I never understood why there were still people in the contaminated areas. Despite fearing death, they still chose to set foot on this gloomy land.
Later, following Lucien, I gradually understood that there are always many people in this world.
There will always be those with nowhere to go, those who yearn for death, those at their wit's end, those longing to return to their hometown, and those who refuse to believe.
And Lucien… he records and treats each of them according to their situations. Seeing their admiring gazes, I silently avert my eyes.
Man: City Lord... I beg you... please kill... me…!
In the last visited hut, blood and pus soak through the tattered sheets. Their entire body is rotting, leaving only a grotesque face that still faintly resembles a human being.
People call such individuals 'living corpses'. They seem to be alive but are also dying.
Lucien: You have already done very well.
Lucien: We still have opportunities, and you will undoubtedly have many possibilities.
Lucien's calm voice is particularly eerie amidst the wailing as he gently comforts the person and changes the bandages covering him.
The clear liquid flows through the needle into the vein, while the glowing instrument continuously shines. Lucien observes and records simultaneously.
The man's pleas and wails seem to be separated from him by some barrier. He just smiles and injects another dose of medication.
Lucien: Only by living can you reach the future. Your life is still very important.
As we step out of the building amid the wailing, the gentle and brilliant light shines down as always, but I feel incredibly cold.
A little child runs over with a tattered book and stands beside Lucien.
Little Boy: Teacher, how should this character be pronounced?
Lucien: Let me take a look.
He squats down, looks at the spot the little boy is pointing to, and teaches him word by word.
Suddenly, the wailing behind us stops.
I instinctively turn my head, but the glaring sunlight blurs my vision.
Lucien: Is the dosage still not right…
Faintly, Lucien's voice seems to come through.
When I turn to the side again, I see him with his hand on his chin, lost in thought, then he continues talking to the child.
I gaze at him deeply, feeling that sometimes this man has a kind of calmness that is terrifying.
On the way back, I remain silent. When death arrives, it always easily strips me of all words and emotions.
Lucien: MC, are you feeling sad?
Lucien's question shatters the silence. I ponder it for a long moment, then nod slowly.
Lucien: [sighs then speaks] Do you think death is the end?
I don't know why he would ask this. Looking at the blood-red dusk outside the window, many faces that I have only seen once and never again flash through my mind.
MC: When a person dies, they are just dead, and there is nothing left.
More and more people are becoming seriously ill, and the radiation alarm in the safe house is sounding more intensely every day. However, Lucien still has no plans to move.
Seeing him inject medication into himself more frequently, I finally break the silence.
MC: Are you okay?
Lucien: Don't worry. This body has been confirmed to be able to last for some time in this environment.
MC: ...Don't you feel any pain?
Lucien: I'm not very sensitive to pain, so it won't be a factor in my judgment.
His tone is relaxed, and he even curls up on the sofa to read the pile of documents I retrieved for him earlier.
Despite trusting Lucien's judgment, I still faintly feel a certain sense of urgency.
MC: Lucien, will our experiment really yield results?
MC: In such a harsh world, shouldn't we lower our high expectations? Wouldn't it be better to just be ordinary people?
Instead of chasing for answers that we may never get in our lifetime, wouldn't it be enough to just simply live?
For a long time after that, Lucien doesn't say anything.
He just gazes at me quietly, his bottomless eyes like an abyss, making it hard to see clearly.
Lucien: I don't know.
Lucien: But experiments inevitably come with failures and contingencies, so I can't give you a definite answer.
Lucien: But I believe there will be results.
Even knowing that he might fail, he will definitely keep trying—until he reaches a point where he can no longer move forward, and then calmly starts over from the beginning.
Lucien: For this, I am willing to pay any price.
At night, I have a dream.
In the dream, those severely ill people stand up, the desolate land starts to have flowers, and there are more smiling faces.
However, everything shatters like broken glass the next moment, revealing a dreadful and bewildering void.
Lucien: MC, we have failed. This world will not get better.
Lucien, standing in front of me, starts to rot and blur, eventually turning into an exploded mess of blood.
I can feel the cold liquid seeping through my body, flowing over my cheeks and arms.
Lucien: MC, how do you feel now?
I can't see Lucien's face, but I can hear his voice filling my mind.
I feel him gently embrace me, patiently waiting for my answer as usual.
The incredibly realistic sensation makes it hard for me to tell whether this is a dream or reality.
Lucien: Listen to the voice in your heart and tell me your answer.
I feel my entire body start to tremble violently, and countless unfamiliar images flash through my mind.
I see Lucien's calm yet mad eyes;
I hear the sharp whirring sound of a machine;
I see blood pouring like a waterfall, drenching my entire body like rain.
I scream and open my eyes—only to see Lucien's face the next second.
The face in front of me overlaps with the one in my dream, but he only has a worried expression on his face; some kind of familiar scent clings to his body.
Lucien: Are you okay?
I'm tongue-tied and can only stare at him blankly.
I don't know if it's the effect of the moonlight, but his entire figure seems to be covered with a faint halo, which then dissipates in the blink of an eye.
MC: I… seem to have had a nightmare and seen many scenes.
He gently strokes my back, but his eyes imperceptibly darken a little.
Lucien: I observed that your Evol fluctuations are quite significant. The recent radiation tide may have also affected you.
Perhaps it's the lingering effect of my dream, but as I look at Lucien standing before me, I feel an inexplicable timidity and uneasiness. I subconsciously reach out my hand to him.
Suddenly, I realize my body is without an isolation suit, and Lucien has almost no protective equipment. I quickly wrap myself in the blanket.
MC: Lucien, get away from me quickly! I'm not wearing an isolation suit! Get out quickly!
Lucien: ….
Lucien: A certain lady's decision is too hasty, making me a bit worried that you might actually dislike me.
The next second, a warm palm covers my head through the blanket.
I can't see Lucien's expression at this moment.
It seems to be a time that belongs solely to him. As long as he doesn't allow it, I can't enter.
Even long after, I still don't know what expression he had during that nearly minute-long silence.
In the end, Lucien walks out of the room without a word.
As I lie on the bed, my heart is still pounding with lingering fear, and I have lost the desire to fall asleep again.
The inexplicably familiar scent floods the entire room, making me sit up in frustration and can't help but sigh.
In the faint moonlight, I suddenly see some small, scattered black spots 'growing' on the floor.
Curious, I squat down and find that it is very fresh, with a faint hint of a metallic smell—
It's blood!
Cold sweat instantly seeps out of my back. Only Lucien had been here just now... Could he be injured? Or affected by the radiation?!
I hastily don the isolation suit and run in the direction of the bloodstains.
The intermittent and scattered bloodstains seem to *guide* me, leading me step by step toward an unfamiliar corridor.
??: “Rrrrr…”
A strange and piercing sound echoes from the depths, like... the sound I heard amidst the chaotic scenes.
Faint specks of light flicker faintly in the darkness, and I suddenly feel a surge of fear and foreboding —
That glimmer of light might destroy many things, but I can't stop my footsteps.
I traverse through numerous unfamiliar corridors and finally step into the glimmer of light—
A vast yet desolate building appears before me, with an enormous pit at its center.
Gazing down, I see the pit divided into numerous sections by plastic sheeting. The walls and sheeting are splattered with varying shades of crimson.
I descend into the pit, pushing aside the hanging curtains as if unveiling the true face of another world.
A thick stench of blood fills my nostrils, and the grating whirring of machinery churns my entire brain.
A familiar figure flickers past in a corner cubicle.
The curtain blurs his face, and the shadow gracefully raises a machine, lowering his arm like a conductor.
The transparent shower curtain is covered with dense 'raindrops'. Something is sliced open and falls heavily.
It rolls on the ground, spinning endlessly, before finally stopping in the gap between the curtains.
I see a person's face, the same face that was wailing and begging for death.
Now, he lies silently on the ground, his rotting eyes staring rigidly at me.
And in the next second, the shadow picks him up, revealing that familiar face through the gap.
Standing against the light, he turns his head, his calm yet crazed eyes gleaming brightly.
He doesn't seem surprised by my arrival.
An arm shrouded in the shadows casually slashes, slicing the entire curtain open in an instant-
-revealing the full, blood-soaked figure of Lucien before my eyes.
My rapid breathing fogs up the transparent visor on my isolation suit, obscuring most of my vision, yet I've never seen him more clearly.
I burst into a sprint.
A torrent of images and distant memories flooded my mind, slicing through me like a scalpel.
??: ...That’s a highly-contaminated area, and you say that child came out alive?!
??: She is crucial to our experiment. We need to study her powers—we have no choice!
Under the glaring lights, someone binds me to an iron table.
Countless days and nights blur together as flames sear my skin and sharp blades inflict ceaseless pain.
??: ...Under high radiation, her body remains stable... she's carrying high-intensity energy... 5 people died from…
??: Evol core… like a quasi-magnetic field…
Strangers speak in tongues I cannot comprehend, their eyes perpetually fixed on the distant future, but all I sense is madness.
They are all lunatics, lunatics of the apocalypse, and I only want to escape.
As I blast open the laboratory door, a gentle-faced young boy appears before me in the thick smoke.
Boy: Once you pass through this door, you can run free.
He pressed a button, and accompanied by a piercing siren, an iron door not far away slowly opened.
Boy: Remember to take the forest path. Nothing will harm you there.
For a moment, I thought this would be another experimental trap set by those lunatics.
The hurried footsteps gradually came closer, but the boy made no move to jump away. He simply watched me patiently.
Boy: You have three minutes to decide whether you want to be caught by them again or trust me.
Boy: Of course, you can also trust your instincts.
Those deep, dark eyes seemed to possess a strange power. In an instant, I turned and ran towards the door.
Suddenly, another thought struck me, and I turned back at the iron door.
MC: Why are you helping me?
Boy: If you want to know who you are one day, you can come find me.
MC: ….How can I find you?
Boy: I will let you find me. Remember to learn how to protect yourself.
Years later, I remembered his words when I finally realized the 'Grim Reaper' I carried within me.
I want to know who I am and what I want to change.
And he seemed to know that I would eventually return to this 'land of death,' leaving messages and marks in each area ravaged by radiation-
I thought Lucien was different.
Maybe he was hiding it too well, or perhaps he finally lost his patience.
The grating sounds of machinery and footsteps seemed to follow me like a shadow, yanking my taut consciousness back to reality.
As if anticipating my arrival, many places were already locked up.
The ground and walls around me tremble slightly, permeated with a strange yet familiar power that makes me feel dizzy.
The unbearable heat and dizziness slow my steps, but the chilling footsteps keep my nerves on edge.
To speed up, I simply take off the isolation suit.
I don't want to die, I must live on.
My heart feels like it's burning, urging me not to stop moving.
After escaping aimlessly, I found myself back in that deep pit again.
As I gaze upon the blood-stained black bags concealed behind the curtain, a sudden idea strikes me.
Shrouded in the humid darkness, I dare not make a single move.
The already cramped space seems to be devouring the last vestiges of air, causing me to slow my breathing instinctively.
Muffled rustling sounds intermittently pierce the silence, sounding eerily ominous in the heightened state of my hearing.
I force myself to focus, but the image of those eyes keeps intruding into my mind uncontrollably.
….The truth is, I don't know Lucien at all.
Is it because he has never fully revealed himself to me, or have I never truly gotten close to him?
Amidst a tinge of sadness, I realize that none of this matters now—I must focus on how to survive.
I exhale softly, and a familiar surge of power gathers in my chest. Through the haze, I catch glimpses of fragmented images —
The hum of machinery fills my ears, while the pulsing red light and constantly fluctuating curves leave afterimages on my retina.
I walk through the crowd of people, and flowers bloom by the roadside.
In that hazy world, there exists a pair of eyes that always gaze upon me with unwavering clarity.
Sharp, resolute, and scrutinizing. He seems to be peering through me to a distant place.
MC: …Lucien.
I part my dry lips but make no sound.
The air seems to thin even further, and in a daze, I feel as if I've been transported back to countless moments of frigid breathlessness in the past.
The unknown and fear tug at my remaining consciousness as if I'm about to be swallowed by the boundless darkness.
I don't know how much time has passed; the rustling sounds around me have also disappeared.
Perhaps Lucien has gone somewhere else to find me. Thinking this, I carefully unzip the zipper.
Before I even adjust to the harsh white light, I crash straight into Lucien's gaze.
The world roars, and my heart seems to stop for a moment.
Lucien: [chuckles] Not hiding anymore?
He squinted his eyes and chuckled softly.
He crouches in front of me, his hair scattered across his forehead, damp with water droplets, his exposed chest rising and falling slightly.
He casually grips the chainsaw and pulls the starter cord with one hand, producing a piercing and terrifying sound.
I can't fathom how long he's been waiting like this.
Five minutes? Ten minutes? Or has he been silently observing my every move from the beginning, watching me run continuously and then return here, lying down in the bag?
Fear makes me clench my fingers tightly, but I do not avoid his gaze, trying to find the answers I seek in his eyes.
MC: ...Why did you help me escape back then?
I don't answer him; instead, I ask a question I have never figured out. As if slightly surprised, Lucien's eyes flicker.
Lucien: Because I worry that they will damage my test subject.
He answers directly and calmly as if it's the most natural answer.
Somehow, I suddenly don't feel afraid at all. I even feel like laughing, so I simply pull at the corners of my mouth and lie in the bag.
I don't want to think about whether his close proximity will be affected by the radiation from my body, nor do I want to consider how to escape from this rapidly moving saw.
Maybe I've always wanted to find some way to talk to Lucien.
MC: Then why do you want to study me?
MC: Why do so many people want to study me? Do you want to change the world?
Lucien: [chuckles] Change the world?
Lucien laughs as if what I just said is a joke.
But soon he restrains his laugh, his gaze turns slightly bright as he looks at me again, and his voice carries an undisguised seriousness and stubbornness.
Lucien: Why change the world? I think this world is fine.
Lucien: What I want to seek is 'evolution'.
Lucien: Radiation, disasters, and the like are merely puzzles posed by objective reality, and we are the problem solvers.
Lucien: Only in this way do we qualify to step onto a new level.
His voice is exceptionally gentle, accompanied by the buzzing sound of an electric current that sends shivers down my spine.
MC: ...Are you going to kill me?
Lucien: [chuckles] Do you want me to?
He lowers the machine in his hand, bringing the rapidly spinning chainsaw blade dangerously close to my neck.
Lucien: I can dismember your limbs, but that won’t be particularly useful to me right now.
Lucien: I can extract your brain intact and keep it active for a certain period of time. Maybe you would still be considered 'alive' in some biological sense.
Lucien: Of course, the most important thing is your heart and... your Evol 'core'.
Lucien: I've been curious for a long time about how it works, allowing you to withstand any severe radiation threat and survive until now.
Lucien: Maybe when I cut you open, there will be an answer to all this. What do you think?
I can feel the intense wind pressure from the chainsaw pressing down on all my nerves, but at the same time, it seems that an even more majestic and surging force is roaring in my chest.
My mind is almost blank, leaving only some kind of instinct.
MC: ....No, you are wrong.
MC: If I die, you won't get any answers.
At this moment, I seem to see something more clearly.
MC: And... it's not you who is studying me to carry out so-called 'evolution', but rather me using you to complete ‘change’.
The corners of his mouth curve into a more pronounced arc.
Lucien: Is that so? But it seems I have the opportunity to lock you up again at any time.
Lucien: I have many ways to keep you from going anywhere, even... to take away your right to choose death.
MC: Then go ahead and try. Just hope you don't die too soon from my radiation.
MC: Just like right now, you've been around me without any protection for too long.
In this gamble, that ever-surging power now settles in my heart. It feels unfamiliar to me, yet at this moment, it seems to belong to me completely.
His deep eyes fill with more laughter. He elegantly sets the machine aside, squats down, and places his hands on both sides of the bag.
His warm breath hits my face, and he seems like another cage, closing in on me even more.
Lucien: Do you know? Ten years ago, your data readings fluctuated wildly. They thought it was due to your unstable condition, but I suspected back then that it was because of ‘fear’.
Lucien: Humans can feel the existence of life through extreme fear. They will instinctively want to protect themselves, and that drive will generate immense energy.
Lucien: Back then, my knowledge and skills were far from sufficient to fully uncover everything about you, so I concluded... that we both needed some time.
Lucien: [whispers] But later, I regretted it. Actually, I shouldn't have let you go back then.
His gentle voice brushes past my ear like a feather, making me instinctively hold my breath.
Something heavy and complex seems to be shedding its outer shell, revealing a more genuine and indescribable side to me.
Lucien: A lot of time was wasted, so when you appeared before me, I was very happy.
Lucien: And you're slowly starting to trust me, which is good.
MC: So everything over the past six months... was it all your facade?
MC: To make me truly feel fear?
Lucien: No, I want you to always remember the feeling you just had.
His noticeably cold fingertips brush my cheek, meticulously tracing a certain outline.
Lucien: You should have been constantly thinking, striving to survive, and seeing many scenes.
Lucien: Remember how you used that power and then tame it.
Lucien: Only then will you be complete.
A pair of calm abysses engulf me, tempting me to gaze upon what lies hidden deep beneath the surface-
A soul that is pure yet obsessive, mad yet patient.
Lucien: Besides, I have never pretended in front of you. Just because you don’t see it doesn't mean it doesn't exist.
Lucien: Our time is running out. I think it's a good idea to use myself as a stepping stone for change.
Lucien: After all, solving the problem is the key to everything, and I don't want to cause you too much pain.
I freeze momentarily, suddenly realizing something, and repeatedly examine his entire body.
The person in front of me has no skin ulcers, looks mentally stable, and everything seems normal…
MC: Could it be that you…
Lucien: I am my own test subject, and the facts prove that I have succeeded.
He lifts his palm, revealing faint flickering motes of light. I can sense a power radiating from within.
Lucien: As I've mentioned before, your body seems to possess a sort of 'core' or 'field'.
Lucien: Your core affects the radiation energy, either absorbing or repelling it; hence, you remain unaffected.
Lucien: And I used the power you unleashed earlier to replicate a similar 'field'.
Flecks of excitement dance in his eyes as he arrogantly retracts his fingertips.
Lucien: [chuckles] If my hypothesis is correct, in a few days, I will be able to create a 'core' with a near-identical operating mechanism in a few days.
Lucien: I might soon be able to research the data from the heavily contaminated areas myself, including... the machines there.
With that, he rises to his feet, carefully placing various organs and components into separate jars before turning his head back.
Lucien: I previously asked you, 'Is death the end?' Do you remember your answer?
MC: ...I remember.
Lucien: I don't think death is the end.
He lets out a soft chuckle tinged with an air of undeniable arrogance.
Lucien: No one here cares about death, because it's too commonplace, and also because they don't understand the value of death.
Watching his retreating figure without turning his head, I instinctively crawl out of the black bag.
I feel as if I've just experienced death and have been reborn with new flesh and blood in this moment.
I want to know what he means and see how far he can go.
Following his figure, I enter a room on the side of the deep pit. Jars of all shapes and sizes are placed in the dimly lit environment.
The wall is covered with a dense jumble of numbers and changing curves, new numbers and symbols overlapping the old marks, layer upon layer.
I look around in surprise, momentarily at a loss for words.
MC: These... are all your doing?
Lucien: Not entirely, I just took over them.
He places the jars on different shelves and writes new numbers in one spot.
Lucien: Someone else conducted experiments here before, leaving behind many things and data. There are always predecessors doing similar things, just like the information you brought back.
Lucien: I just found them, researched and revised their conclusions, and came up with my own answers.
MC: How do you know that someone else will do the same thing…?
Lucien: There will always be.
Lucien: There will always be those who are curious, questioning all the current definitions and conjectures, wanting to know how this world actually works.
Lucien: There are always things that spread wider and longer than diseases and death, leaving their mark on the world in various ways.
I stand there in a daze, Lucien is clearly standing in front of me, yet I feel like he is so far away.
In a world ravaged by wounds, his words sounded like a miracle, but he spoke them as if it were a matter of course.
At this moment, I suddenly have a premonition.
Even if Lucien disappears from the world one day, there will surely be someone who will sweep away the dust of time, pick up the whole box, and continue to climb upwards on this silent boulder.
Lucien: Aside from that, these corpses are also quite nutritious.
Having seemingly finished his preparations, Lucien spoke abruptly, causing my expression to change instantly.
Following his footsteps, I arrive at another dark, large building. I had never thought that the buildings next to the laboratory each had their own purpose.
Amidst the continuous rumbling, Lucien opens each black bag one by one and empties their contents into a deep pit, its contents and depth obscured from view.
Lucien: Corpses can be fermented by bacteria to produce biogas, which is a tremendous source of chemical energy.
Lucien: Moreover, improper handling of these corpses could lead to an outbreak of plague, resulting in even more deaths.
Unable to understand what he's saying, I stare into the depths of the pit for a long moment before turning my gaze towards Lucien.
MC: Have you been experimenting on the people in the city all this time?
Lucien: I don't deny it.
Faced with his somewhat ambiguous answer, I fall silent for a moment.
Lucien is both saving and experimenting. It seems as if the divine and the devil coexist paradoxically within him, making it impossible for me to define him in any way.
Lucien: The more people who survive, the more it proves that my path is the correct one.
Lucien: I deeply regret the loss of those who died, but I will only use their deaths to go further.
As we leave the building, the sky is so dark that no single star can be seen.
Lucien doesn't stop but walks towards the city.
Seeing this, I instinctively halt—I am not wearing my isolation suit, and my presence could harm the city's residents.
Lucien: It's okay, MC. Trust me.
He stands in the darkness yet extends an invitation to me like a burning flame.
Lucien: Let me show you what this world can be.
In the empty square, not a sliver of light is visible. Lucien takes out a small device, instantly illuminating his face. A small, dome-shaped black hole is also aimed at me.
MC: …!
Instinctively assuming it to be a weapon, I cover my neck and recoil half a step.
Unexpectedly, Lucien laughs and gestures with the device at me for quite a while. I instinctively try to escape his ‘target lock’, but it only makes his laughter more pronounced.
Finally, I can't resist moving closer. After he presses the button, I find myself appearing on the lit-up screen!
The me in the picture frame steps back in fear, nervously runs around, and finally moves closer out of curiosity.
MC: …What is this! So amazing!
Lucien: I don't know either. But since we've found it, it means someone invented it in this world.
Lucien: It has no significance for survival, yet it still exists.
With a gentle shake of the device, specks of light dance exuberantly in his eyes.
Lucien: How boring it would be if the only meaning of this world was survival.
My heart is racing, and the moment I take the device, it feels heavy.
I don't know what I pressed, but Lucien's face appears on the screen.
Lucien looks straight at me through the device.
Lucien: [softly] MC, do you know? From the moment you appeared before me, I realized that this world is actually full of color.
Lucien: So, I really want you to see what the world looks like through my eyes.
An unknown button press triggers a blinding flash of light that erupts in an instant, searing an imprint onto my retinas-
The whole world seems to be glowing.
Multicolored luminescence suffuses every corner of the city. The splendid and brilliant lights are like eternal fireworks, blooming with unparalleled beauty.
Zone X is lit up.
Shadowy figures emerge from the corners, their heads raised and eyes wide open.
??: ...Is this also a radiation tide?
??: It must be... it must be! Run! Otherwise, none of us will survive!
??: It hurts! I feel so much pain!!
??: Wait… City lord is over there!
??: City lord! Save us!!
Countless cries of clamor and anguish rise and fall, eyes full of pleading and struggle are cast in my direction.
Lucien: These are all my doing, they are just some lights that I turned on.
As those words settle, the entire square instantly falls silent.
??: There's no way so many lights would turn on in this world... you must be lying!
??: ...Really? Could it be that City Lord is just that powerful?
??: Run!!
In that fleeting moment, I seem to perceive a myriad of faces. Doubt, curiosity, anger, despair...
In the unfamiliar yet radiant scene of rebirth, something sprouts and grows amidst the ruins.
As someone charges forward with a roar, Lucien remains nonchalant, a smile still gracing his lips.
His eyes hold no trace of them.
Lucien: MC, the future awaiting everyone will never be peaceful; death and struggle will inevitably permeate the entirety of human history.
Lucien: But if, after enduring pain and struggle, one can gain the courage to face the truth, it will surely lead humanity to a further future.
MC: ...What kind of future?
Lucien: For example…
As blood splatters everywhere, I see Lucien proudly raise the corners of his mouth.
Lucien: You can stand in front of everyone just as ordinarily as this.
Lucien: Without restrictions, in a state of freedom.
Lucien: I think this future is just beginning.
Lucien extends his hand to me as he speaks.
I have never seen someone like this, standing before me in such a real and equal way, in the face of me who always brings death to others because of my radiation.
He has calculated everything and cut open everything, inviting me to embark on an unknown and long journey together.
Almost without hesitation, I step forward and grasp that hand, letting the blood stains on it also stain my hand.
Since he has used himself and the future as bait, then I have absolutely no reason to give up.
MC: Lucien, is all of this tonight part of your bigger trap?
Lucien: [chuckles] What if it is?
I stare back at him deeply, the corners of my mouth curling into a smile.
MC: Then I will gladly accept it.
With a dazzling halo around his arched eyebrows and eyes, he pulls my hand up and we start running together.
Lucien: The isolation membrane I placed on you only lasts for 15 minutes. "Miss Death" is about to come again.
As he speaks, he spreads his palm open with a serious demeanor. Despite being covered in blood, he appears as graceful as the wisest grand wizard from a book.
I can't help but laugh, placing my hand in his as if placing both my life and death in his hand.
MC: Pfft, don't you need to escape from me then?
Lucien: I don't need to.
He laughs casually, and there’s even a hint of anticipation.
Lucien: Death is one of my best nutrients.
The static dark screens served as a backdrop behind him. The neon light outlines his silhouette as if it could illuminate everything.
I subconsciously raise the device in my hand and aim it behind us-
Countless images of Lucien appear on the machines behind me. I excitedly sway it back and forth, and the pictures of the machine sway in real time along with my movements.
MC: You need to tell me what's happening when you return!
Lucien: I'd be happy to explain it to you.
MC: Then I also want to know the principle behind it and more!
Lucien: In that case, a certain student might need to put in a bit more effort outside of the experiments.
The sky starts to rain at some point, as if a joyful symphony is playing.
MC: Lucien, do you find this world interesting?
Lucien: Incredibly interesting.
MC: I'm starting to find it interesting too!
I've never felt so free and happy. All the unknowns seem to have transformed into challenges at this moment, and I want to overcome them.
MC: With Zone X being so bright, more people are bound to notice it, right?
Lucien: Probably, similar people will understand its significance. Some will come closer, and some will question it—
Lucien: But perhaps more and more areas will light up like this.
Lucien: The data you brought back contains a very special piece of information.
Lucien: It is said that there is a person in this world who can change everything. The recorder referred to her as — 'Queen'.
I was stunned for a moment and slowly stopped walking.
Lucien stands in front of me, still gazing at me with a gentle smile.
I look at our intertwined palms, and after a long while, I raise my head resolutely and hold his hand even tighter.
MC: If there really is someone who can change everything, I will be that person.
MC: I will be the 'Queen'.
Lucien smiles gently.
Lucien: Then I will witness your coronation.
He holds my hand, steps over the line between light and darkness, and merges into the darkness.
Lucien: Welcome to the new world.
Thank you for reading! I put my thoughts about the date in the comment if you are interested in that :)