cw: (mutual) confinement, arguably justified drug use, intimacy as a coping mechanism for PTSD. Please proceed with caution and avoid reading if these topics may be distressing, triggering, or uncomfortable for you.
This date contains STRONG REFERENCES to Season 1, Chapter 25 and [Not Planned On] R&S. If you haven’t read them yet, I highly recommend doing so first for a more immersive emotional experience™.
Another date that I recommend to read before reading are: Embrace Date (Shower Karma SSR), Tidying Date (Childhood Solo SSR) because these two dates also delves on his ptsd and ‘possessiveness’. You can either find it on my tumblr or search on youtube as the date is already localized in EN server!
I feel like I'm going to die.
The world is spinning, and the sudden sense of weightlessness crushes my heart as if it could burst at any moment.
I cross my hands and press my head tightly against the back of the seat. The oxygen mask on my face inflates and deflates with my rapid breathing, and white mist engulfs the breathing bag in the blink of an eye.
Captain: Our plane has encountered an unexpected situation during the flight...
Captain: Please fasten your seatbelts... Do not panic...
The hoarse announcements, deafening roars, and helpless cries collide chaotically, pulling me into a state of bewildered despair.
…Am I going to die here?
A figure appears before my eyes, and amidst the violent turbulence, his face seems to grow increasingly blurred.
Several pieces of luggage crash from above, hitting my shoulders and completely shattering all my thoughts.
The scenery outside the porthole speeds past in reverse, with raging flames and thick black smoke seemingly burning wildly in my eyes, leaving only silent pleas and prayers.
??: Buddha, please protect us...
??: No...
As an invisible huge wall slams into me, the air in my lungs feels as if it’s being forcibly squeezed out. Amid the piercing roar, my consciousness is gradually torn and pulled away.
MC: Lucien…
Deep beneath the surface, bright light illuminates the rough concrete walls and rows of metal instruments. Several blonde researchers move back and forth through the somewhat modest laboratory.
Lucien stands in front of the second-floor platform, calmly looking down without revealing any emotion.
A foreign gentleman stands beside him, his profound green eyes gleaming sharply as he raises his palm.
??: Doctor X, I didn’t expect our formal meeting to occur at such a chaotic moment.
Lucien: Indeed, it is a bit unexpected.
Lucien: However, to smoothly avoid the turmoil in such a short time and maintain such a well-equipped research environment...
Lucien pauses, his narrow eyes showing a faint smile devoid of warmth.
Lucien: It seems that aside from research, Professor Holden also holds considerable authority in other areas.
Holden: Professor Lucien, if you want to stay in such a volatile place, you must be well-prepared.
Holden: Risks and rewards always go hand in hand.
Lucien: In that case, I think we can further accelerate the pace of the experiment to minimize the risk.
Lucien: I don’t intend to let meaningless disruptions become the key turning points of the past several months I’ve worked on.
A silent tension faintly brews. Feeling a slight sense of pressure, Holden raises an eyebrow and places one hand on the railing in front of him.
Holden: I’m just as eager as you are, Professor.
Holden: But in these chaotic times, there are always accidents.*
As if in response to his words, a barely perceptible hum comes from above. The ceiling trembles slightly, shedding a shower of fine gravel.
But everyone present seems accustomed to it, continuing their work unfazed.
Lucien also looks up without surprise, gazing into the distance.
Lucien: Accidents are meant to be controlled and enjoyed.
Lucien: Chaos will ultimately become the catalyst for new discoveries, and that’s why I chose to work with you in the first place.
As he speaks, he turns and walks away. Just as he steps into the open elevator, a voice calls out with a laugh from behind.
Holden: With Professor Lucien joining us, I suppose we should indeed be more confident.
Lucien doesn’t respond. With a loud rumble, the old elevator doors slowly closed behind him.
The sound of metal grinding outside the elevator continues to roar persistently, like the distant echoes of endless artillery fire.
The fading afternoon sunlight streams in from outside as the elevator doors open.
Three days have passed since the meeting with Professor Holden.
The lab operates around the clock, almost pushing time to its limit, but the results are still not ideal.
Just as Lucien expected.
He extends his fingertip, verifying one fingerprint scan after another, before stepping out of the unassuming old factory.
The scent of gunpowder constantly assaults his nostrils. Scattered armed personnel stand guard in front of barbed wire fences among the crumbling ruins on both sides.
Lucien walks steadfastly through this land where turmoil is the norm. Only when he passes a corner does he finally stop and take out his phone.
The signal bars silently returned to full. While waiting, he looks up at the sky not far away.
A vast expanse of dark clouds churns and burns fiercely. Soon, the phone in his palm vibrates.
Lucien opens the message box and sees a text from the girl six hours ago, informing him of her boarding.
She is on a private plane back with several film industry executives. He instinctively calculates her estimated arrival time in Loveland City—
She will land in about four hours. His expression softens unconsciously, and a hint of a smile appears at the corner of his lips.
Lucien's Message: Miss Producer, you must be tired from your business trip. Thinking about how you'll be home soon… I feel a little lonely too.
Lucien's Message: Looks like I want to wrap up my work early so I can get home sooner to see you.
Pressing the send button, he hears an increasingly loud whirring sound that continues to fill the air.
Lucien looks up again. In the distance, a small passenger plane makes a sharp turn and plummets, veering at an unusual trajectory. Thick black smoke billows from its right wing.
A fighter jet closes in from behind as the passenger plane plunges into the distance, skimming beneath the low-hanging clouds.
In an instant, it merges with the smoke.
He watches calmly, then looks down to confirm that his message has been sent successfully before turning to leave.
The dust floats in the wind and settles on his shoulder.
In a world where people depart at any moment, he simply reaches out to brush off the dust before walking away in the direction he came from.
*: 意外 (yìwài) is the keyword of this date. It refers to something unforeseen, whether a surprising event or an unfortunate incident. This word generally means "unexpected" or "accident.
But to keep the repetition intact and considering how, more often than not, it carries a slightly negative connotation of things going wrong, I choose to only use "accident"  to translate the word throughout the whole date.
Plop—
Hearing the abrupt noise, I immediately press myself against the wall, shaking as I tighten my grip on the scalpel in my hand.
In my narrow field of vision, a hunched old woman passes by the intersection.
Her figure is shrouded in gray, and with each unsteady step, a patch of nearly black bloodstain on her back comes into view, sending a violent shudder through me.
I finally realize that I haven’t truly escaped death—
I’ve merely fallen from one desperate situation into another.
Three hours ago.
Co-Pilot: We are currently unable to determine the captain’s physical and mental condition...
Co-Pilot: Amid the chaos, the aircraft veered off its autopilot route and entered the airspace of a conflict zone, where it encountered a warning attack...
Co-Pilot: Although we managed to make an emergency landing, the current situation remains unclear...
Co-Pilot: We will continue to do everything possible to contact the airline and relevant authorities.
In a crude medical shelter, with his right arm wrapped in a rough bandage, the co-pilot speaks heavily.
Several fellow passengers frown, wanting to say something, but in the end, it turns into a few muttered curses.
Faced with the absent-minded captain, he almost single-handedly managed to execute an emergency landing in the woods.
He then proceeded to provide emergency bandages to the more seriously injured passengers in an orderly manner.
With the communication equipment failing, he relies on his memory of the flight path before the crash, leading the group toward a possible inhabited area.
It wasn’t until dark that we finally found a rundown bungalow on the city's outskirts, flying a Red Cross flag, where we fortunately received temporary assistance.
Everything feels like some kind of miracle in the midst of immense misfortune.
Co-Pilot: I suggest we stay here for now. This place is relatively safe and on the other hand...
Co-Pilot: We have several seriously injured passengers who can’t be easily moved.
Passenger: Can’t we ask them to go somewhere with a signal and contact the embassy for us?
As the words are spoken, the rushing wind carries a pungent scent of blood. They speak anxiously in a language we don't understand, pushing a surgical trolley as they rush into the building.
They already have their hands full with the constant influx of injured people.
No one speaks again, and I lower my head as well.
By great fortune, I’ve survived the disaster.
Gratitude and trance consume me at the same time. At this moment, I don’t even know how much time has passed—it feels like time has frozen into a blurry black mass.
Will Lucien know that something has happened to me?
Will my flight make the news as a ghost flight? Will he see the reports saying my fate is unknown?
I bite my lips tightly, trying to force my muddled mind to think, but my eyes slowly grow wet.
I can’t even imagine what Lucien would look like at that moment, but I know very well that staying here is the safest and most responsible choice for both him and me.
...I must survive.
Boom—The distant sound of what seems to be a collapse suddenly pulls me back to reality.
We’ve underestimated the level of chaos here; accidents can happen at any moment.
The conflict has reached the camp, and in the urgent evacuation, there’s only a loud noise left in the world.
When I come to my senses, I find myself alone, with nothing but a rust-covered scalpel that I don’t even remember holding.
The streets are even more desolate after dark, and I force myself to stay alert almost instinctively.
What should I do? How can I survive?
Only deathly silence answers me.
I clench my hand repeatedly, trying to force myself to stop trembling, but it’s no use.
Suddenly, a click sounds from behind me, and a cold sweat instantly soaks my skin.
Someone has appeared behind me, stepping on shards of glass.
I tremble so much that I can barely breathe, forcing myself to silently hide the scalpel in my sleeve. Turning around, I raise both hands to show that I mean no harm.
What comes into view is a pair of black leather shoes covered in ashes, yet there’s not a single crease or scuff on them.
They are not combat boots, nor do they bear any traces of blood, which makes me breathe a sudden and grateful sigh of relief.
Perhaps someone from the medical team has found me. With that thought in mind, I lift my head, only to find myself staring into a pair of familiar eyes.
Those dark, indifferent eyes seem to contract intensely the moment they see me.
The world suddenly loses all sound, and on the eerily empty street, Lucien stands across from me.
MC: ….
I don’t dare to move, not even to blink.
It feels like a grand hallucination on the verge of collapse, one that’s ready to burst like a bubble the moment I move.
My blurred vision makes his face even more indistinct, and that figure also seems to walk toward me in a daze.
He, too, seems to hold his breath. His steps gradually quicken, stirring the hem of his coat and the dust in the air until he stops right in front of me.
His chest seems to tremble uncontrollably, and his slightly shaking fingertips fall upon my face. Cold. Undeniably real.
Lucien: …MC?
His low, hoarse voice feels both near and distant, leaving me dazed as I gaze at him, feeling his uneasy yet fearful touch brush against my cheek.
MC: …Lucien, is it really… you?
MC: Am I… going insane?
Lucien: …Fool, how could I… be just your hallucination?
He lifts my hand and brushes it against his cheek as if confirming*.
The cold, dry sensation spreads through my fingertips, and just like that, the tension that had been stretched to its limit finally snaps.
MC: Lucien…..
MC: Lucien… I’m… so scared…
I don’t know how I appear in his eyes at this moment. All I want is to hold him tightly. To be held tightly by him.
His unbearably tight embrace brings pain, but it’s the reality I desperately need right now.
This man who has always been effortlessly composed now seems to have lost all sense of restraint.
Lucien: …It’s okay.
Lucien: It’s okay now… MC.
He murmurs the words over and over, I don’t even know if he’s saying them for me or for himself.
Lucien: I’m here…
Lucien: I'm right here by your side... Don't be afraid...
The head resting against my shoulder feels so, so heavy as if something even weightier has sunk into the depth of our souls along with it.
I don’t know how long I’ve been crying.
Only when I have finally let out all my emotions and lean into his embrace do I realize that I’ve arrived in a warm place—
Surrounded by irregular rock walls, the air is filled with a damp, mineral scent.
The rising steam soothes my nerves, and I tug at his collar with more ease.
MC: It's okay now, Lucien...
MC: I'm not afraid anymore...
Lucien: I’m afraid.
His voice is so faint it feels like a figment of my imagination. I want to turn my head to look at him but find myself gently and firmly held in his embrace.
Lucien: It’s safe here. I’m staying here for now.
Peering over his shoulder, I see an open door leading to a clean bed, a few sofas, and a table.
In the corner of my vision, a gray toothbrush rests inside a glass cup, and the razor I gave him is neatly placed.
I freeze for a moment, feeling like something is off.
MC: Didn’t you say you were on a business trip…?
Lucien: I am, and I’ve indeed been staying here for a few days.
Lucien: I know you must have a lot of questions. To be honest, so do I.
Lucien: But right now… there’s something even more important to me.
Following his lowered gaze, I see the dirt covering me and my tattered clothes, torn in places I don’t know.
My drooping strands of hair are covered in dust, resting against Lucien’s clean shirt.
MC: I got your shirt dirty.
Lucien: ...Stop saying such silly things.
He gently pecks the space between my brows, his fingertips naturally undoing the loosened buttons on my clothes.
MC: Lu—!
Lucien: Shh….
His lips move downward, pressing insistently against the corner of mine.
Though very light, it is filled with an undeniable firmness.
Lucien: Don’t push me away.
Lucien: I also need to confirm that you're really here with me.
Lucien: Let me help you… okay?
It isn’t really a question. His voice lingers at the edge of my lips, flowing with his breath, making my head feel light and dazed. Instinctively, I nod at him.
His fingers move slowly yet deftly. Bit by bit, patches of deep bruises become more visible.
His warmth spreads through me faster than the cold.
I’m too embarrassed to look at him, so I bury my face deep into his chest instead. I feel him scoop me up in his arms and carefully lower me into the bathtub’s warm water.
The sudden heat stings me, jolting me awake as I grab Lucien’s wrist.
MC: Wait, the other passengers I was with, because of the conflict, they’re now…
Lucien: Don’t worry, someone will take care of it.
Lucien: Right now, only you matter the most to me.
There seems to be something growing wildly beneath his calm gaze. He subtly and seamlessly intertwines his fingers with mine, gently submerging my body into the water.
The deep and shallow bruises appear even more striking in the clear water. A dull ache seeps into the water, causing a small, instinctive sigh to spill from my lips.
Lucien: Relax.
He applies slight pressure, gently prying apart my fingers that are curled around my knees. Carefully avoiding the bruises on my thighs, his hand presses downward.
MC: [moans] L-lucien…
Lucien: I just want to help you relax a little more.
Lucien: At least for this moment, be a good girl... okay?
Another question that isn’t really a question.
I can’t get a single word out**, so I can only bite my lower lip, watching as he kneels by the bathtub, a soft towel in his hand, lightly stroking over my arm.
Lucien: Does it hurt?
His low, hoarse voice is caught in his throat as if suppressing something before finally smoothing into a calm steadiness.
MC: …A little.
Lucien: Then I’ll be gentler.
His gentle, unhurried touch warms one arm before moving to the other. Then, it follows the top of my foot, slowly moving upward.
As he leans down, his large shadow envelops my whole body, and I instinctively tremble with each faint mark he leaves behind.
Something seems to be stirring madly in his calm gaze, suppressed within his silence, driving him to confirm me even more deeply and intimately.
I feel as if I’m sinking into the warm water, yet also weightlessly floating with it, my hands instinctively clutching the fabric at his chest tightly.
Lucien: …bear with it a little longer… wait for me...
As if to soothe, his even more scorching lips descend, teasingly hooking and coaxing my lips and tongue, relentlessly drawing me in.
At some point, his entire body has also become drenched, his drooping bangs soaked with water, revealing those unfathomably profound eyes.
Lucien: I'll help you get rid of all the pain.
*: the wording in Chinese is ambiguous; it could mean either that he is making sure she’s not his hallucination or that he’s reassuring her that he’s real :") and this ambiguousness HURTS because-
you know that he also has the same fear as her (this will be expanded more later on memory silhouette). This guy really said, "…Fool, how could I… be just your hallucination?" yet he’s in disbelief himself that she’s real and I’m just SOB-
**: 说不出任何话 literally means "can't say any words at all." However, the nuance is deeper than just the inability to speak. It can imply being so overwhelmed by emotions (orcoughpleasurecough) that speaking becomes impossible.
Besides being overwhelmed, it’s also often used when somebody wants to say something but physically/emotionally just cannot.
Even when carried to the bed, my whole body still feels light and weightless.
An oversized shirt is put over me, its scent different from the dense smell of gunpowder as it carries the light freshness of grass that I’m familiar with.
Lucien casually changes into fresh clothes, grabs a few towels, then pulls me into his arms and smooths back my damp hair.
MC: …How about I do it myself?
MC: It’s inconvenient for you like this, and it’ll just get your clothes wet again.
Lucien: But it seems my hands can’t let go of you… they need your warmth even more.
His gentle yet firm fingertips stroke the back of my neck, resting the side of my forehead against his shoulder. His legs settle on either side of me, enclosing me within his territory.
The world is enveloped in tranquility, with only the rustling sound of a towel rubbing against damp hair remaining.
MC: It must be pretty inconvenient for you here too, there’s not even a hairdryer.
Lucien: Don’t worry, the equipment here is a bit more complete than you think.
His low voice brushes past my ear, making me look up in confusion.
MC: Then why do you…
Lucien: Sound of the hairdryer would make you uncomfortable, so this will do.
I freeze for a moment. That trace of distant rumble and roar still seems to be howling, yet at this moment, they appear to settle into a quiet stillness within his deep eyes.
Only now do I notice more clearly that he seems to be slowing down his breathing as if he's cradling something fragile.
MC: …Do I look like a total mess?
Lucien: How could that be? To me, I never would have imagined that in a place as desolate and ruined as this…
Lucien: I could still be lucky enough to encounter such a beautiful and resilient color.
Lucien: Even though I never wanted you to be here.
Lucien: I can’t help but wonder… if I hadn’t stepped out the door today if I hadn’t turned left...
His words come to an abrupt halt, followed quickly by a faint chuckle that carries a touch of self-mockery.
Like a staunch materialist*, yet hesitating over irrational ‘what ifs’.
The rhythmic beating of his heart echoes in my ears, but that subtle, unintentional quickening of its pace seems to take on another name—
It’s called ‘lingering fear’**.
The arm holding me seems to tighten in the next moment, and I can’t help but clutch the front of his shirt, burrowing myself even deeper into his embrace.
Lucien: Right now, I’m already by your side.
Lucien: I’ll take responsibility for driving away all those unpleasant things lingering in your brain.
MC: Really?
Lucien smiles lightly, and the tension in his brows and eyes finally eases slightly.
Lucien: As a brain scientist, it would be difficult for me to lie to you about this.
Seeing him feign seriousness while explaining, I can’t hide my laughter at his dry joke.
MC: Lucien, let me tell you about my brush with death.
MC: Maybe facing it head-on will make it less frightening.
Lucien doesn’t speak for a moment, only silently changing to a new towel.
I rarely see him like this, so I can’t resist reaching out and gently smooth the furrow between his brows.
MC: Do you want to hear it?
Lucien: …Perhaps, the one who is more afraid is me.
He closes his eyes, presses a light kiss to my fingertips, and finally looks at me with an even deeper calm.
Lucien: I’ll do my best to hold back the ache in my heart and listen carefully.
MC: Lucien, you’re just as much a fool as I am.
Lucien: You're probably the only person in the world who would praise me like that.
In his tender, lingering kisses, I finally steady my mind.
MC: Actually, I still don’t have a clear understanding of what exactly happened during that time.
MC: I only heard the co-pilot say that the captain suddenly had some kind of mental issue…?
MC: Later, our plane accidentally entered a no-fly zone, was threatened, and ultimately had to make an emergency landing.
Lucien's breathing seems to have stagnated for a moment, and his eyes droop slightly.
Lucien: Your plane… Did the right wing get hit?
MC: Hmm? It seems... to be true?
MC: I was sitting on the plane's right side at the time, and all I could see was black smoke. But I was so scared then that I couldn't really tell...
Recalling that scene, I still instinctively curl up in lingering fear, not noticing the way his eyes suddenly contract sharply.
MC: But luckily, everyone was safe. We just kept walking and were rescued by a local civilian medical organization.
MC: But the scene was too chaotic. Later, the gathering site was also affected, and I got separated from the main group during the evacuation.
I pause, looking into his eyes with mixed emotions.
MC: And then I met you.
MC: …All of this is just too unbelievable.
MC: The accidents in this world really catch people completely off guard. I feel like I’ve had the worst luck… but at the same time, I also seem exceptionally fortunate.
Lucien: ….
He falls silent again, it's unclear what he is thinking.
I don’t know how much time has passed. After ensuring my hair has been completely dried, he casually throws the damp towels aside.
The world suddenly quiets down, and Lucien wordlessly raises his hand, his fingertips gently brushing over the bruises on my body.
As our skin touches, a slight itch ripples through my skin, accompanied by an extremely faint pain sensation.
Thinking of his ‘confirmation’ in the bathtub not long ago, I can’t help but feel my face grow slightly warm again.
I lift my head and kiss the corner of his lips, lingering until our breaths intertwine, then smile and wink at him.
MC: Don’t worry. With you here, I already feel much better.
MC: When I get up tomorrow, I’ll definitely return to full strength. Then, we can…
As I speak, I suddenly stop, realizing something.
MC: Are we... still near this area?
Seeing him respond softly, my heart tightens.
MC: You said you’ve been here for a few days, so that closed-off lab you mentioned... is it here?
Lucien: Yes.
Lucien: Even though this place is far from tranquil, I have a reason that makes it necessary for me to be here.
His voice possesses a certain indifference and resolve. I gaze at him for a moment before slowly speaking.
MC: Are you doing something dangerous?
Lucien: ….
Under my gaze, Lucien remains silent for a long time, long enough that I almost think he will find some way to sidestep the topic until his low voice finally breaks the silence.
Lucien: The research institution I’m working with now is one I had contact with years ago when I first joined BS.
Lucien: They have a considerable amount of multinational projects, as well as some that can hardly be called ethical or compliant. In one way or another, some covert dealings are involved.
Lucien: All I can say is, yes. The things I’m doing are not safe.
Lucien: So I hope you don’t go anywhere and just stay by my side.
Seeing him be especially frank about his thoughts, I can’t hold back my smile.
MC: Lucien, I'm not asking about myself, I'm asking if you will be in danger.
He freezes for a moment, then smiles without the slightest hesitation.
Lucien: No, I won’t.
Lucien: I should be able to get what I want soon, so don’t worry.
He presses a light kiss to my forehead, pulls back the blanket, and wraps me in its softness.
Lucien: But… I think that’s enough of a bedtime story for now.
Lucien: Just like you said, I want to see you full of energy as soon as possible, smiling without any worries or strain.
Looking at his incredibly close face, I smile and lean in closer to his scent.
MC: What should I do? I’m still a little reluctant to sleep.
MC: It might be a bit late to say this now, but after so many days apart, I’ve really missed you all along.
Lucien: Me too.
Lucien: So all you need to do is close your eyes, I will always let you feel my presence and longing.
Like finally returning to the most secure and reassuring home***, I relax and close my eyes.
One after another, incomparably intimate and affectionate kisses fall upon my face and between my lips, as if scattering in tiny, delicate fragments that sink into the depths of my heart—
—until I fall into an exceedingly gentle dream.
When I open my eyes again, daylight is already shining brightly.
Lucien isn’t by the bed. As I get up and step out of bed, I notice that my wounds seem to have been tended once more.
MC: Lucien…?
The room is quiet. Breakfast is laid out on the table, along with a laptop and a slightly old-fashioned phone.
He hasn’t left a note, but I still smile with an unspoken understanding.
I’m just about to wash up when the phone screen suddenly lights up. A message pops up, showing Lucien’s number.
Lucien's message: Good morning MC. I’m already at the lab.
Lucien's message: I’ve arranged for someone to contact and assist the passengers who were with you, so there’s no need to worry.
Lucien's message: I’ve also informed your company that you’re safe. Work matters can be left to them for now.
Lucien's message: Get some rest, I’ll return as soon as I can.
Sunlight spills in from the balcony, and a gentle breeze brushes against my face, carrying a touch of winter’s coldness.
Yet, I don’t feel the biting cold. Instead, there’s a sense of warmth and security.
Though the scene before me remains desolate and ruined, the world feels tranquil right now, free of the terrifying tumultuous noise.
I step onto the balcony and see golden light magnanimously illuminating the earth. A small bird perches under the eaves, occasionally lowering its head to preen its feathers.
A faint wave of emotion wells up in my heart. Perhaps this place would have been entirely different if not for all the turmoil.
But what I’ve never noticed is—
—the little bird on the eaves has only one wing.
*: In this date, it’s Materialism in philosophical context rather than everyday use.  Materialism is a philosophical belief that only physical matter exists and that everything can be explained through the physical world and natural laws.
Lucien mocks himself for speculating about "what ifs", because it involves considering possibilities that may have no empirical grounding, which contradicts materialist core belief that only the physical matters.
**: “后怕" refers to lingering/delayed fear, realizing the terror of something only after it has passed. He has just come to the realization of how close he was to losing her forever, and it filled him with 后怕. In some contexts, it can even be directly translated into PTSD.
***: "归处" (guīchù) means both "home" and "place of belonging." So for MC, Lucien is not just a home to return to but a refuge where her heart finds peace, like a final destination of solace and stability.
As expected, everything has been thoroughly taken care of by Lucien.
Upon seeing on the laptop that the embassy had already contacted the local government to carry out the rescue operation, the last bit of unease in my heart vanished into thin air.
Thinking of how Lucien told me not to wander around, I simply grab one of his books to read and wait for him in the room.
Before I realize it, the light of setting sun slants, casting its glow onto the coffee table. Amid my drowsiness, my phone suddenly rings.
MC: Are you done with work?
Lucien: Mm. Are you doing okay?
MC: I’m fine. I was just reading the book you left on the sofa, but it’s so abstruse I almost fell asleep.
Lucien: To be honest, I’ve dozed off on that book more than a few times myself too.
As we chat and laugh, I stroll to the balcony under the slowly fading glow of the sunset.
Lucien: I should be back very soon.
MC: Then I’ll check what’s left in the fridge and see what I can cook. Maybe I can cook a big hodgepodge~
I smile as I hang up the phone and look up, only to see the same little bird from this morning still perched on the eaves.
—No different from the scene I saw before.
It still preening its feathers, never stopping for even a second, nor ever lifting its head.
It's as if it were a lifeless shadow, mechanically repeating the same motions repeatedly.
A chill spreads through my heart, and I unconsciously feel a bit of panic. Suddenly, I notice that the scene before me carries an absurd sense of repetition—
At times, a passerby would cross to the end of the street only to abruptly reappear on the other side.
The distant edges of the city also seem indescribably blurred, as if detached from reality, carved apart by dividing borders.
I try to calm down and cautiously push open the door.
The dark-colored walls on either side are clean yet monotonous, showing no signs of anything unusual.
After thinking about it, I step through the doorway. But the farther I walk, the more cold sweat seeps down my back.
There is no elevator here nor any emergency exit.
The dim corridor seems endless, with the same unchanging scenery stretching ahead and behind.
As my nerves gradually tighten, I suddenly catch sight of a warm yellow light at the end of the corridor.
I immediately run toward it—
Until that glow envelops me, and I freeze in place.
I find myself back in the room again.
The space that once felt reassuring now makes me feel like I can’t breathe.
Even though I’ve experienced similar situations before, I still can’t help but wonder… could all of this be nothing more than a fleeting hallucination* inside my mind?
But the voice I just heard was gentle and real, and the spot where he lay still retains a faint warmth.
??(Lucien): …MC…
I keep comforting myself not to fall into post-traumatic stress. Lucien said he is here conducting research, maybe this strange phenomenon is also related to his work.
?? (Lucien): MC, are you okay?
In a daze, a warm palm seems to lift me from the depths of the sea, bringing me back to the surface.
I blink and suddenly see Lucien standing before me, his face filled with worry as he cups my cheeks. I have no idea when he got there.
MC: Lucien…
Lucien: Are you feeling unwell anywhere?
I open my mouth, momentarily at a loss. Lucien immediately pulls me into a tighter embrace.
Lucien: It's my fault.
Lucien: You're not in a good state right now. I should have spent more time with you.
Lucien: It’ll be over soon, just hold on a little longer. Soon… we’ll be able to go home together.
His warmth presses against me, enveloping my whole body. I take a deep breath and gently pat him.
MC: Don’t worry, Lucien. I’m fine.
Looking at his raised face, I feel a pang of heartache as I brush over his slightly bloodshot eyes. Tentatively, I ask him.
MC: Are you working on some kind of Evol-related research?
Lucien: Why do you ask?
MC: Maybe I'm overthinking it… but I can't shake the feeling that everything outside this room seems unreal.
He seems startled for a moment, his entire figure hidden in the shadows.
Heavy emotions surge within his dark eyes as he presses his forehead to mine, swallowing my whole reflection into them.
Lucien: Then do you think I’m unreal?
MC: Of course not!
MC: I just... suddenly discover that the corridor outside the door seems endless, so...
Lucien: I see.
He gently takes my hand and leads me outside. We move smoothly through the corridor, take the elevator, and leave the apartment without any trouble.
The night is quiet, and there are hardly any people along the way.
Seeing my stunned expression, Lucien smiles and tightens his hold on my hand.
Lucien: I think the best way to comfort you right now is to take a walk, just like we always do.
Lucien: Although this place isn’t exactly peaceful, at least this neighborhood is not dangerous.
He pauses for a moment, then continues explaining in a gentle voice.
Lucien: The result I await has nothing to do with Evol. It is an experiment in the field of neuroscience.
Lucien: However, the test samples are extremely fragile and require strict control over variables such as temperature and humidity.
Lucien: Therefore, special devices have been installed near the laboratory to restrict Evol, eliminating interference factors and preserving the samples’ activity.
I listen thoughtfully, unable to resist asking another question.
MC: ...So what I saw was really an effect of the experiment?
Lucien gives a noncommittal smile, adjusting my scarf snugly before we continue walking through the quiet neighborhood.
In the following days, Lucien maintains a highly regular work schedule and calls me every now and then.
I have a vague feeling that my accident, combined with my previous state, may have truly frightened him badly. He seems even more attentive to me than before.
I put down the book in my hands and look toward the door again.
Actually, I’ve tried going out on my own since then, but for some reason, whenever I’m alone, I end up circling back to where I started—
As if I’m trapped inside the room.
The vague sense of confinement only makes me even more curious about what Lucien is really doing, so I start searching around.
Before long, I found a report on the Holden Research Institute, which seems to contain a list of personnel and medication records.
As my eyes scan the unfamiliar faces, they all appear ordinary and unremarkable.
Until a familiar face enters my sight, making my eyes widen in shock—
The captain of my flight is among them!
Reading through the information, I find that the captain turns out to be a retired soldier. He has been taking this medication long-term to treat post-war trauma.
The records also show that the drug has a small probability of causing neurasthenia, emotional intensification, and even brief episodes of shock…
I involuntarily break out in a cold sweat as I see these people’s data being continuously recorded and updated, even as recently as two weeks ago.
Lucien: Are you saying that the pilot responsible for the accident is on this medication record list?
MC: …Yes.
When Lucien returns that day, I hesitate but eventually tell him about my discovery.
He sits on the sofa, not saying a word for a long time, his entire being sinking into some kind of heavy and terrifying silence.
Lucien: …It seems there really is no need to continue with them.
Lucien: I will put an end to all of this as soon as possible.
He flicks his fingertips, tossing the stack of data reports into the fireplace.
As the flames burn, the charred traces seem to reach all the way into his eyes.
Somehow, I seem to see even darker emotions burning within them, and I can't resist reaching out to stroke his cheek.
MC: Lucien, are you okay?
Lucien: ...MC, are you really here in front of me?
His gaze is deep and distant, yet it firmly holds my gaze in place.
I look at him for a moment, and in that empty gaze, I seem to see a reflection of something similar to myself.
So I move even closer and straddle his lap.
MC: Of course I am. I'm right here with you.
Within his raised gaze, my hand slowly glides toward his sharp jawline.
The artery on the side of his neck subtly swells with each swallow, and with every heartbeat, they pulse steadily yet distinctly beneath my fingertips.
I slightly tilt my face downward, leaning in closer to him. My lips gently graze his, coaxing them to part ever so slightly.
He stares without blinking, watching as in our mingling breaths, my tongue tentatively flicks out to softly lick his upper lip.
It is a test, a touch, and also a reassurance.
I swirl my tongue around his, while Lucien simply follows along, letting himself be led by me.
I can clearly see the corners of his eyes gradually tinged with red, while the pulse at the side of his neck throbs with escalating intensity.
MC: Lucien, tell me, am I in front of you?
Lucien: Yes. You are in front of me.
His voice also seems to catch fire, burning over, searing into his neck as it arches even further, tracing a suggestive arc.
His indulgence unleashes me boundlessly. I can’t help but venture even closer to his breath, brushing past the scorching heat of his chest, trailing all the way downward.
MC: Then... are you in front of me?
Amid the overflowing sultry heat, I can’t stop myself from lifting my body and pushing things further by settling on top of him.
A muffled, unbearable groan slips past his lips. His hand instinctively tightens on my waist, pulling me even closer to him.
Lucien: …Yes… I am in front of you.
His heartbeat seems to throb inside my body, and mine does too.
Countless trembles surge and collide through the bloodstream, even the instinctive sighs spilling from our lips becoming tangled together.
At some point, the fire in the hearth dims, and the dim light of the night blurs into a chaotic and ambiguous interplay of light and shadow.
I can feel his whole body relaxing, and I can’t help but hold him even tighter.
MC: How wonderful, Lucien. You're here by my side.
In the darkness, Lucien stays silent for a moment. Only after what feels like an eternity does his reply drift slowly through the air.
Lucien: Why are you the one offering comfort now... shouldn’t it be me?
MC: Because... even though I’m the one who’s scared, you seem to be afraid of something too.
Lucien: But you should have more important questions to ask me.
Lucien: You should ask me why that drug list is here, or even…
Lucien: Ask whether any of this could possibly be connected to me.
His calm question carries an indescribable scrutiny and simmering anger, leaving me momentarily stunned.
Only now do I belatedly realize the implication of his words. I had almost instinctively not linked Lucien to this matter.
MC: But this drug is essentially used to treat stress-related trauma?
MC: There must be flaws in the screening process that allowed someone taking this medication to become a captain...?
MC: And even if we take a huge step back, if this drug really is connected to you, it’s not like you caused the crash to happen.
MC: As Professor Lucien would usually say, this is just a low-probability event. A mere accident.
Lucien: I don’t like this kind of accident.
He speaks with a stubborn edge, his tone even somewhat stiff and cold.
Like a butterfly with fluttering wings, the massive waves it stirred up should never have crashed upon me.
I only find him endearing and can't resist wanting to peck the corner of his lips.
But in the next second, I’m suddenly picked up. The world spins, and amidst the dizzying whirl, my body is pinned against the sofa in a position difficult to break free from.
My cheek pressed against the cushion, making me unable to see Lucien’s expression at this moment.
With each breath I can sense the fine texture of the fabric, carrying a hint of warmth yet also a subtle, constraining sense of oppression.
Lucien: I don’t like accidents taking you to places I don’t know about.
Lucien: I also don’t like accidents making you go through things I’m unaware of.
Lucien: I dislike it even more when accidents leave bruises that don't belong to me on your body.
As his words trail off, one of his hands seems to trace along my wrist, gliding up my arm to my shoulder, neck, and back.
His burning fingertips travel all the way down my spine, and I can only feel his touch, my body instinctively letting out a trembling shudder.
Lucien: It almost made you disappear.
I feel a firm and increasingly invasive dominant pressure pressing against me from behind, making me bite down my lower lip.
But before I can even utter a word, Lucien overwhelms me almost instantly.
It's as if we're two sheets of dampened paper, growing so wet that we seep into each other.
Without realizing it, we become more and more soaked, until we seem to meld into a single sheet.
I feel as if I've sunk into a deep daze, only aware of him holding me even tighter, pulling me back into his embrace again and again, each time closer than before.
Lucien: MC, you should be angry.
Waves of tingling pleasure continuously spread down my spine, and his voice, filled with frustration, reaches me in a hazy blur.
A dizzy haze endlessly clouds my mind, and I instinctively bite down on a gasp, unable to stop myself from turning my head to look at him.
His face is shrouded in shadows, making his expression even more obscure and harder to discern.
MC: Do you want me to be angry?
Lucien: I don’t know.
He quietly half-kneels there, his voice particularly low and subdued.
MC: Are you trying to punish yourself this way?
MC: You’re angry at yourself, aren’t you?
He still doesn't say anything. He only leans down, pressing his body even deeper into mine. At the same time, his fingers slip between mine, locking our hands together with even more force.
A long time passes before I finally hear his voice from behind me.
Lucien: I almost... lost you again.
The word ‘again’ sinks into my heart, sending a painful ache through me.
MC: Lucien, I want to see you.
MC: Let me see how you are, okay?
Though he doesn’t retreat even half a step, he still yields to my request.
Slowly, he turns me around, finally letting me see his eyes.
Dark. Frenzied. Profoundly raw.***
Too many indescribable emotions surge in those eyes, rising like sky-high waves, sweeping me along with them.
MC: You haven’t lost me, Lucien.
What answers me is an even more scorching kiss. My heartbeat remains restless and shaky.
Lucien: Yes… I won’t give myself another chance to lose you.
*: "走马灯" (zǒu mǎ dēng) refers to a spinning lantern with paper horses. Metaphorically, it describes fleeting, dreamlike scenes, often used for life flashing before one’s eyes.
**: "神经衰弱" (shén jīng shuāi ruò) translates to "neurasthenia" or "weak nerves." While rare in the West, it's still recognized in some Asian countries as a persistent mental disorder with symptoms like weakness, emotional instability, tension-induced pain, and sleep disturbances caused by ‘weak nerves’.
*** His eyes are described with three words: 晦暗 (huì àn), 疯狂 (fēng kuáng), 深切 (shēn qiè).
-晦暗: Shadowed and obscure, as if hiding intense emotions.
-疯狂: A chaotic, unrestrained madness, unlike his usual controlled obsession (偏执 piān zhí).
深切 (shēn qiè) combines "深" (deep) and "切" (cut/slice), usually used to convey the most sincere emotions. The way I interpret it is that his profound, raw emotions and vulnerabilities are fully exposed, like his heart being laid bare after getting cut open.
3:00 AM.
Monochrome liquid flows through a blood-collecting device into the vacuum tube as Lucien slightly loosens his tightly clenched fingers.
High-speed metal instruments hum without pause while the surrounding screens flash with streams of data—shifting graphs and numbers reflected in pairs of focused and urgent eyes.
Lucien shifts his gaze to the clock on the wall and speaks in a cold voice.
Lucien: We still need to make up eight hours.
After speaking, he tosses the cotton swab used to press against his vein into the trash. He removes his clothes and, assisted by the researchers, puts on monitoring equipment and a respirator before lying down in the experimental chamber.
According to his calculations, the data samples were originally expected to reach No. 58 today, leaving at most 39 hours until the No. 63 that he needed.
But an accident still happened. In his anxiety, he used space folding to bring the girl back to his room from the ruins.
Rationality told him he shouldn’t have done it. But he was desperate to confirm her real existence, to wash away the dirt and wounds that had tainted her.
Or rather, he had truly felt a certain fear, one that made it impossible for him to calmly leave her in any situation where another accident could occur.
However, the price was that the Evol fluctuations affected the experimental environment, briefly stalling the data progress.
Even the slightest deviation is something Lucien refuses to accept.
If the purpose of accelerating his pace before was to safely obtain the special sample and return to her as soon as possible…
…then now, he has an even stronger reason to race against time.
Lucien: If any abnormal fluctuations occur during the process, as long as the values don’t reach their peak, there’s no need to pause.
Lucien: Begin the experiment.
Lucien closes his eyes, letting the liquid engulf him.
In a trance, the complicated emotions from moments ago rise even faster than the water, suddenly making it hard for him to breathe.
The moment he realized he hadn’t received a message from her reporting her safety, the moment he saw that her flight had lost communication on trending—
—only then did he discover that a heart could contract this severely in an instant.
The stabbing pain in his chest spread along his nerves, making him instinctively furrow his brows and inexplicably take a step forward.
He didn’t know where he was going, nor did he even know why he was moving forward.
Perhaps he just didn't want to stay in place, or perhaps it was just a subconscious reflex of self-deception.
Broken pavement carried the lingering charred scent, and severed electrical wires hung down, scraping eerie marks onto the ground.
The world remained as monotonous and colorless as ever, as if this had always been its true color.
After walking aimlessly past several street corners, a streak of bright color crashed into his vision without warning.
She appeared so abruptly, like a grand hallucination, catching him completely off guard.
Lucien instinctively stopped in his tracks.
Suddenly, he recalled a moment from long ago. Beneath the camphor tree in early spring, he had seen that streak of a phantom that seemed almost real.
Lucien: [gasps] ….
Lucien: It shouldn’t be like this.
Even though reason told him that there were countless possibilities that she wouldn't be here, an unreasonable certainty drove Lucien towards his only color.
Somewhat distant sounds from the equipment scratch at his eardrums, and Lucien knows that the experiment is going smoothly.
It seems he can return to her side soon.
Not much time has passed. She probably won’t notice anything.
But she has always been sharper than he thought. If she picks up on something, what then?
In truth, he dislikes this kind of wavering irresolution and, even more so, the feeling of losing control to accidents.
Accidents are supposed to be challenges and abundant possibilities, not something that leaves him helpless and in a flustered mess like this.
But to ensure the experiment goes smoothly, he has no choice but to accelerate the process. This means he cannot be by her side all the time.
So, he chose the safest method at this stage.
Before leaving his room, he locked her inside a dream.
*: SOBBING at the every Out of Plan R&S/S1 Chapter 25 reference—I did not need to be reminded of his hallucination of her after her death every five seconds!! 😭 Also, oh my god, the constant mentions of his colorblindness and how she's the only color in his world… PG really loves twisting the knife for us XM stans huh😭💔
Sure enough, by the next night, Lucien pushes open the door of his room and walks in, calmly picking up the duffel bag he had packed at noon.
Lucien: MC, we should go.
MC: ...Go home? So soon?
Lucien: Yes, but... there might be some complications along the way.
As he speaks, the air outside hums loudly, as if the aftershocks of distant artillery fire continuously ripple through the atmosphere.
Meanwhile, this trembling persisted for almost the entire afternoon, making me slightly uneasy.
Lucien: MC, although I know this is putting you in a bit of a tough spot...
Lucien: But the only way we can evacuate now is by helicopter.
MC: …!
My body nearly trembles on instinct.
But Lucien reacts even faster. He wraps an arm around my waist, his long, narrow eyes gazing deeply at me.
Lucien: I don’t want to make you afraid.
Lucien: If there were any better solution, I would never allow something like this to happen.
As he speaks, he holds out his palm toward me. On it lies a single white pill.
Lucien: MC, do you trust me?
Lucien: This is a sedative, and it has a safe composition. When you wake up, the first thing you see will be a safer place.
Boom—!
An even more intense blast slams through layers of air. This time, even the floor beneath my feet begins to shake faintly.
Looking into those unwavering eyes, I take a deep breath then pick up the pill and the water bottle.
MC: Have you got what you wanted?
Seemingly not expecting that I still have the mind to care about this matter, he freezes briefly, then his eyes crinkle into a smile.
Lucien: Of course, I never break my word.
MC: So, the state I’ll be in after taking it is also within your calculations, right?
Lucien: Yes. Don’t worry, I’ll handle everything.
I feel relieved and swallow the white pill in one gulp.
In my dazed state, I suddenly feel a violent tremor—
At the same time, bursts of explosions ring out one after another, near and far. It’s as if the entire world is roaring, clamoring to rush toward me.
MC: …Ah!
I abruptly open my eyes, but my consciousness stays foggy, feeling nothing but the world spinning around me.
Until my vision slowly comes into focus, and I suddenly meet a pair of startled, slightly panicked eyes. My mind blanks out in an instant.
Lucien sits across from me, his face pale. Fresh blood seeps through his tattered shirt, snaking down his body in rivulets.
Each blast of distant artillery fire is carried by the raging wind, thrashing wildly inside the aircraft cabin. In the almost suffocating air pressure, my entire body trembles uncontrollably.
MC: Lucien!
I shout at him, my voice choked as all the unease and pain in my heart burst out at once.
His dark pupils shrink for a split second, but he immediately smiles reassuringly at me. He reaches out his hand toward me as if wanting to caress my cheek.
Brownish blood seeps from the bandaged wound on that well-defined hand, mingled with tiny grains of sand and grit.
Everything happens too suddenly. I stare blankly at the IV tube secured to his arm. As it sways and tugs, I catch a glimpse of faint bloodstains around the needle site on his hand.
Lucien: MC, I'm fine.
Lucien: Close your eyes...
The howling wind and rain instantly swallow up his voice. I bite my lip hard, fighting to push words through
However, the helicopter suddenly tilts sharply to one side. I instinctively grip my seatbelt tightly, but the intense pulling force nearly overwhelms my shoulders and back.
Every bone in my body feels as if being torn apart, and my brain seems vacuumed of air.
My entire body is deathly stiff in my seat, only my heart pounding violently in my chest.
I can't help but shout at Lucien in front of me.
MC: Lucien! You Big Liar!!!
The person across from me freezes for a moment, as if struck by a sudden thought, then immediately shows a faint, particularly conceding smile.
Lucien: Yes, I'm a big liar. It's all my fault.
MC: You even said it was all within your calculations. Was your injury part of that too?!
Lucien: I don’t mean to upset you on purpose, but none of these are serious wounds, so yes, they fall within my calculations.
MC: ...Y-you, stop talking! Don’t make me mad!
Lucien: Then just be angry. As long as you’re only mad at me, that’s fine.
MC: You bad guy!!
As he unintentionally or intentionally fans the flames, those crushing fears are unknowingly pushed out by anger.
By the time I regain my senses, I realize we’ve come to a stop on the deck of a cargo ship—
A foreign man stands not far away, greeting us with a friendly smile.
The cabin's guest room isn’t large, but it has all the essentials. Devoted medical personnel even come in to treat Lucien’s wounds.
Until they leave with the medical kit, I continue to stand not far away, watching him with a pained heart and furrowing my brows.
MC: Does it hurt?
Lucien: Are you still afraid?
The words we speak come out simultaneously, causing us to freeze in the same instant and then share a tacit smile.
Lucien: Hurts a lot, so come hug me, okay?
He knows I can never do anything about him.
I walk up to him, and he wraps his arms around my waist. His fluffy head leans against my chest, and for a moment, it feels like the tension melts away.
MC: …So now you realize you still have me.
Lucien: I can’t do it alone, after all. But I can’t always rely on you either.
Lucien: Even though I really want to.
Hearing the slightly aggrieved tone in his voice, I feel both exasperated and amused.
MC: If I had stayed asleep, were you planning to hide your injuries?
Lucien: Maybe. I'm sorry, MC.
MC: You big fool, it’s not like I’m blaming you for getting hurt.
Lucien: I know. I’m just really sorry for making you wake up early.
Lucien: The dosage of the sedative was precisely calculated by me. You were supposed to wake up only after we landed.
Lucien: But… we encountered an unexpected attack during the retreat, which delayed us for a bit.
He explains with excessive seriousness and caution, making my heart ache faintly.
While I've suffered trauma, he seems to have been wounded as well.
Those wounds are hidden in corners I can’t see, leaving me with nothing to do but press silent kisses onto his calm face, one after another.
Remembering the foreign man on the deck earlier, I can’t help but gently stroke his brows with some concern.
MC: Lucien, can we really trust these people and make it back to Loveland City without any problems?
Lucien: When the helicopter landed, I noticed the Holden Institute’s insignia on the ship’s stern.
Lucien: On the path from the deck to the guest rooms, a section of the wooden floorboards makes a subtly different sound when stepped on compared to the rest.
Lucien: It is highly possible that he used such a design to transport things he didn't want others to discover easily.
Lucien: Moreover, a considerable amount of this institute's funding comes from underground deals that can’t see the light of day.
Lucien: So I deduce that Holden uses this ship to transport collectibles for trade. Of course, the possibility of smuggling weapons can’t be ruled out either.
Lucien seems to notice my nervousness and gently places his palm on the back of my hand.
Lucien: More importantly, after the helicopter landed, I discovered an Evol-suppressing device that’s difficult to detect.
Lucien: Based on my past observations in the lab, I think there’s a high probability that this ship also carries research samples.
MC: ...Could it be that they also made an emergency transfer while evacuating?
Lucien: We can’t be certain yet, but I think they must’ve set quite a few backup plans in place.
MC: …Will what they're doing affect your objectives?
Lucien: It will have some impact, but it doesn’t matter.
Lucien: I won’t give them the chance. I’ll either find the item or no one will.*
Hearing him say that, I can’t help but feel a little worried and instinctively hold his hand.
MC: Let me help you too, okay?
Lucien: Of course I need your help.
Lucien: I need you to keep staying well by my side and embracing me just like this.
His gentle whispers brush past my fingertips, but I feel a silent rejection and purse my lips a bit unhappily.
MC: Are you still afraid?
MC: Because of what happened before, you just want to put me in the safest place.
He doesn’t speak, as if this is yet another form of silent acknowledgment.
Relief and dread are intertwined. I’ve known for a long time that he buries his emotions even deeper than I do, which is why I need to embrace him tighter and for longer.
MC: I admit that the airplane incident scared me out of my mind, and even now, I’m still shaking.
MC: But I'm also worried that you'll be in danger, though I trust you, believe you can accomplish anything...
MC: Lucien, I want you safely by my side too.
His profound eyes are filled with my reflection. He simply gazes at me for a long time, as if this way he could lock me within them forever.
In the end, Lucien only tilts his head up and kisses me even deeper.
*: The literal tl is “I will either find the item or take care of/dispose of (it/him/them).” I decided to take some artistic liberties to capture this vagueness. The phrase "处理掉" (chǔ lǐ diào) is often used when something is taken care of through destruction, removal, or getting rid of something. It could mean he’s simply going to dispose of the item or eliminate the people involved or… both-
Inside the cabin, the banquet hall emanates a touch of warmth that feels out of place.
The flowing lights fall upon Lucien’s black shirt, where the glimpses of bandages beneath inexplicably add some bewitching allure to his elegant demeanor.
Early in the morning, Holden selects several formal dresses and sends them over, saying that since today is New Year’s Eve in Loveland City, everyone should start adapting to local customs.
I can’t shake the feeling that he has ulterior motives. Just as I lean in to whisper to Lucien, I see Holden raising his glass and approaching us.
Holden: Thanks to Professor Lucien’s involvement, our experiment has achieved substantial progress.
Holden: Although the process has been filled with too many unforeseen 'uncertainties', forcing us to start over from the beginning, I believe it has all been worth it.
Holden: Just as you said, accidents are to be enjoyed.
Holden: I trust that after returning to Loveland City, we’ll be able to collaborate more deeply, don’t you agree?
Lucien: I've always enjoyed working with intelligent people.
Beneath the calm of this moment, something continues to surge in the undercurrents.
Aside from Lucien and me, nearly everyone on the ship belongs to Holden’s team.
If Lucien wants to find what he’s looking for without using Evol, these past few days have shown that it won’t be an easy task.
Silently, I lift my gaze toward Lucien. His expression remains composed, as if unconcerned by the present circumstances.
Lucien: Speaking of which, that matter I previously requested you to arrange...
Holden: Of course, no problem.
The other person raises an eyebrow. Soon, this simple banquet comes to a close.
But Lucien does not take me back to the room. Instead, he weaves left and right before finally arriving at the cargo ship’s kitchen.
I blink in confusion, then turn to him with a laugh.
MC: Professor Lucien, didn’t you eat your fill?
Lucien: I really didn’t have much of an appetite in that atmosphere.
Lucien: But more than that, I just want to share a simple meal with you alone today.
As he speaks, he opens the freezer door and unexpectedly takes out several bags of frozen dumplings.
MC: There are actually dumplings here…!
As I recall that the banquet mainly featured Western dishes, I vaguely understand the cryptic exchange Lucien and the other party were trading earlier.
Lucien: Apologies. I originally planned to show you my cooking skills at home this year.
Lucien: But now, it seems we’ll have to wait until we’re back for my Great Producer to properly appraise it.
MC: No need to apologize. After all, we're still spending this Chinese New Year's Eve together.
MC: But Professor Lucien, you better not forget the New Year’s Eve dinner you owe me~
As we chat and laugh, we set the pot to boil, and before long, billowing steam fills our surroundings.
The cold, stiff dumplings tumble into the pot. As I watch the tiny bubbles on the water’s surface, I suddenly feel that this moment is very peaceful.
For a fleeting instant, it feels as if we’ve returned to our warm home.
Lucien: MC, Happy New Year.
Hearing the blessing that falls by my ear, I turn my head and find the answer in those smiling eyes.
Lucien: I think, the more we're in this kind of atmosphere, the more we need some relaxation.
He lifts the lid and serves a bowl of dumplings.
The steaming mist blurs his eyes, making it hard to see them clearly.
He picks up a dumpling, brings it to his lips to blow on it carefully, and then holds it to my mouth.
Although its skin is a bit tough and the filling is rather ordinary, the steaming dumpling still brings me a sense of happiness as it enters my mouth.
Afterward, I can’t help but pick up one for him as well. We share the meal in silence, as though words aren’t needed.
MC: It’s incredible. Though everything’s been coincidental and absurd, spending New Year’s here with you doesn’t feel wrong at all.
Lucien:  Silly girl.
In the dense steam, he leans in close to my lips.
Softer than his lips, his tongue lingers even longer, not just bringing happiness but planting a seed that blooms endlessly in my heart.
Lucien: It will be over soon. After that, we’ll leave immediately.
His words sound like some kind of farewell, making me subconsciously worried.
But before I can ask, a wave of inexplicable dizziness comes over me-
I struggle to keep my eyes open, but Lucien's face gradually dissolves into the darkness.
Gazing at the girl asleep in his arms, Lucien kisses her on the forehead once more.
Holding her quietly, he carries her back to the guest room, lays her on the bed, and carefully tucks her in.
Lucien: Sweet dreams, MC.
When he turns around again, the tenderness on his face has already vanished. His narrow eyes glint with icy coldness.
Just as planned, he smoothly enters the concealed storage room he had noticed earlier. Based on his analysis over the past few days, he also located the reagent he wanted to verify.
As expected, it has lost its activity.
Though this isn’t a good outcome, when weighed against the girl’s safety, it can hardly be considered an excessive loss.
It can be considered that everything has gone as he wished.
He casually finds a spot to sit and speaks calmly.
Lucien: Professor Holden, you still won't come out. Aren’t you afraid I’ll destroy this thing?
In a drowsy haze, I open my eyes.
The room is dark and almost lightless, lit only by faint moonlight filtering through the porthole. There’s no Lucien by my side.
Surrounded by deathly silence, I suddenly have a terrible feeling. I grab Lucien’s coat and drape it over my shoulders without much thought before leaving the room.
The quiet corridor seems endless—it's as if I'm trapped again.
At this moment, my mind is surprisingly calm. Those pair of serene yet inscrutable eyes flash through my thoughts.
Perhaps… I finally grasp why all of this is happening.
...Lucien, you truly are an absolute big fool, a big bad guy!
In an instant, a familiar force surges from my chest, and a lustrous white light burst forth—
I need to have a proper talk with Lucien.
A bone-chilling cold permeates the air, making it feel like even one's breath could freeze into a thin layer of ice.
Crystal-clear ice spreads throughout the corridor of the cabin. Icicles hang from the ceiling here and there, their tips sharp as blades.
Scattered weapons and unknown equipment lie strewn everywhere. I stare blankly at this frost-covered scene as countless terrifying images seem to flash before my eyes.
Without another thought, I pick up a dropped handgun and sprint toward the frozen corridor’s end.
There is no sign of anyone on the ship, deathly silent as if it had been swept clean, with traces of frost all over the place.
I don’t know how long I’ve been running until I stop in front of an unremarkable door—
the only door that hasn’t been frozen shut.
I cautiously look around, then gently push the door so that it opens a crack.
Various artworks are scattered throughout the small space, while cold light falls indifferently, making the entire room feel even more cramped and somber.
Under the cold light in the corner, numerous packaged artworks haphazardly piled on the floor, like a small exhibition yet to be unveiled.
Strips of bright yellow tape cut a glaring boundary across my vision, warning away any visitors who don’t belong there.
A cold, indifferent figure stands at the center. He turns as if sensing something, and his gaze crashes into my furrowed eyes.
The air falls into silence.
Everything before me seems beyond ‘excuse’. His calm gaze dips slightly, eyelashes casting a faint shadow over his tranquil face.
Like a bad kid who knows he's doing something wrong but still insists on doing it, soberly indulges in his own actions.
I walk step by step toward him, check that he has no additional wounds, and only then do I turn my gaze to him.
MC: Is there anything you want to say to me?
Lucien: ….
He blinks and smiles, his expression somewhere between resignation and satisfaction.
Lucien: [that mix of helplessness and pride at her managing to break out the dream using her power:"] Your power has grown stronger.
A rush of heat relentlessly floods upward and I can’t help but tremble all over. I scan the room and then point to a table covered with bubble wrap.
MC: Lie down.
Lucien: ….
Maybe my tone is too harsh, or I seem on the verge of anger, Lucien says nothing and simply lies down quietly.
Then, I forcefully rip off the yellow tape nearby and walk back to his side.
MC: Put your hands behind your back.
As if it were some tacitly understood command, he obeys me without a word.
I resentfully wind the tape around his body, but out of the corner of my eye, I catch the faint bloodstains seeping through, and the strength of my hands falters with reluctance.
Eventually, the tape coils loosely around his neck, shoulders, arms, and down to his exposed abdomen. It’s as if he, too, were a dangerous yet precious collectible.
Lucien continues to let me do as I please. As the tape adheres to his skin, his expression shifts, initially calm and quiet but now touched with enigmatic depth and curiosity.
He watches my every move without blinking. Clearly, he's the one who's bound, yet it feels as if I'm the subject of his interest.
The inexplicable impulse melts into guilt. Suddenly, I catch sight of a golf club nearby and, feigning composure, pick it up.
MC: Lucien, do you know what I’m doing?
Lucien: I know.
Lucien: But just doing this... I’m afraid it’s not quite enough.
As he speaks, he lifts a hand that had somehow slipped free at some point and rests it against the back of my head.
His slender fingers slide into my hair, stroking through the strands. Every so often, his fingertips lightly graze the curve of my ear, sending a faint, tremulous weakness through my body.
Just as I teeter on the edge of surrender, he leans in, closing the distance between us. His lips trail up along my cheek before gently biting down on my earlobe.
Lucien: It needs to be this much, at least.
The bubble wrap around us rustles from friction as I press my bent knee against the inside of his thigh, but afraid of hurting him, I instinctively ease the pressure.
Yet the man beneath me doesn’t seem satisfied with my movement.
He wickedly shifts his leg, making me suddenly lose my fulcrum and involuntarily tip forward, but he swiftly tightens his hold on me with his thighs, leaving me to almost completely surrender my balance to him.
MC: You…
Lucien: There’s no one else here.
Lucien: After doing something so far out of line… if you’re just planning to tie me up and give me a little scare, that won’t do.
MC:  Who said I’m just trying to scare you?
Saying this, I bring the club closer, brushing it against his chin, forcing him to tilt his head back and meet my gaze.
MC: You only care about your own fear, but don’t you realize I can tie you up just like this too?
MC: And lock you up in a place where only I can see you, where I’m the only one you can see.
Lucien: MC, would you also want to... lock me up?
Along with his intimate, bewitching words, some kind of shiver seems to surge wildly through my mind, causing me to look at him on instinct.
MC: Lucien, I am the same as you. I will also possess the same emotions as you… and the same love.
Lucien: Then I suppose… perhaps we could make it a little deeper.
Lucien: That way, I can remember even better.
He keeps tucking my hair back again and again, arousing waves of tingling sensation through me.
Everywhere his scalding fingertips wander heats up quickly, as if the warmth is pressing into my blood, until my entire body is slick with sweat.
Unable to stifle my soft panting, I lift my hand and brush over the dried bloodstain on his cheek.
MC: ...Don’t move.
Lucien: But when I locked you up, I let you move freely.
MC: You’re shamelessly twisting words again. That’s a false equivalence!
Lucien: I admit it.
Lucien: But with you right here, how am I supposed to control myself?
Lucien: I just want you to prove it to me… much harder.
From the room's far end, infrared rays cast a dazzling red light. The light's edges trace the outlines of our pressed-together bodies, staining my hair to the very tips of his fingers.
Everything before my eyes blurs into a haze of sultry crimson.
The distant murmur of waves drifts in dully, while the chill-laden air surges forward, as if breaking through the floodgates of desire and plunging into the most intimate depths.
Lucien: Don’t let me out.
Although the last scene wasn’t as explicit as some others, but they definitely do the devil tango at the end too. The biggest giveaway? That last line before his 'Don't let me out.' -
The combination of '探进' (literally means to enter and explore/slip into) and '幽密的深处' (literally: hidden and secret deep place) is a phrase often used in erotic writing as a metaphor for entering and exploring a woman's intimate depths. Yeah-
Anyway, thanks for reading! I also shared some rambles about this date in the YouTube comments if you’re interested. I immensely enjoyed this date, and I hope my translation and ramblings convey that LOL.